<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="BR2016F01643">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Identification of arthritis in swine through thermographic image</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="pt">
      <dcterms:alternative>Identificação de artrite em suíno utilizando imagem termográfica</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>GRACIANO,  Daniela E.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>NÄÄS, Irenilza A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>GARCIA,  Rodrigo G.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>CALDARA,  Fabiana R.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>SANTANA, Mayara R.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>NASCIMENTO, Guilherme R.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Arthritis</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Lesions</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Infrared spectrophotometry</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Thermography</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8951</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4283</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_28568</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_32609</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">: In intensive pig production systems one of the most prevalent disorders are arthritis, 
causing pain to animals and it may affect their performance and welfare. Thus, the early diagnosis 
becomes important to allow appropriate treatment to animals as soon as possible. The aim of this 
case study was to evaluate the efficiency of use of thermographic images for identifying arthritis or 
inflammatory processes in pigs. Five pigs were selected as they were suspected to present arthritis 
in the rear limbs. The surface temperature (ST) was recorded by average of thermographic images 
using the thermal visor from Testo®. There were calculated the averages of 10 points on the ST of 
each rear limb of the pigs and compared afterwards using t-Student test with reliability of 95% in 
order to verify if there were difference between the ST in sound rear limb and the limb presenting 
edema. The mean ST values were lower (P≤0.05) in the sound limb (33.6°C) than those relating 
to the limb with edema (35.6°C), slowing the use of thermographic images can turn possible the 
identification of inflammatory processes in subclinical stage in swine.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="pt">Nos sistemas intensivos de produção de suíno uma das afecções mais prevalentes 
são as artrites, que causam dor aos animais podendo afetar seu desempenho e bem-estar. Deste 
modo, o diagnóstico precoce torna-se importante para que se dispense aos animais tratamento 
adequado em tempo hábil. Objetivou-se com este estudo de caso, avaliar a eficiência do uso das 
imagens termográficas para identificação de artrite, ou de lesões em suínos. Foram utilizados 
cinco animais com suspeita de artrite nos membros posteriores. A temperatura superficial (TS) dos 
membros posteriores foi registrada por meio de imagens termográficas utilizando o termovisor 
da Testo®. Foram calculadas as médias de 10 pontos da TS de cada membro posterior dos suínos, 
sendo posteriormente comparadas utilizando o teste t-Student, com confiabilidade de 95%. Os 
valores médios de TS foram menores (P≤0,05) no membro sadio (33,6°C), do que naquele com 
artrite (35,6°C) evidenciando que, por meio de imagens termográficas, é possível a identificação de 
processos inflamatórios em suínos.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.iz.sp.gov.br/pdfsbia/1396561314.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">pt</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Boletim de Indústria Animal</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">0067-9615</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.71/n.1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>