<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="IN2016106145">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Baculoviruses as microbial insecticides</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Nidhi N</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">A50</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang=" ">The use of conventional pesticides lead
to a myriad of problems such as environmental
pollution, pest resurgence, secondary pest outbreak and
many more. The present era is the era of new
technologies that are novel, sustainable and
environment friendly. Thus, when one talks about plant
protection, the techniques that fulfil the above criteria
are always welcome. One such technique is the use of
microbial insecticides against the major insect-pests.
The use of pathogenic microorganisms for pest control
is not a new concept, but there have been continuous
research and re-evaluations in the ongoing
technologies, so as to create more potent products. The
necessity of the baculoviruses is indispensable when it
comes to managing the pests. This can be proved by
the fact that a lot of countries including India have
successfully exploited this biopesticide against many
pests. The use of the contemporary technology, such as
gene incorporation and genetic engineering has made
the products much more effective. Baculoviruses are
relatively very safe as they cause diseases in the
arthropods only and no significant damage has been
noted in the non-target population. The prospects of
this emerging biopesticide are immense. The use of
baculoviruses as potential microbial insecticides is the
perfect choice under the current circumstances. Its use
will lead agriculture towards precision and
sustainability.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.indianjournals.com/ijor.aspx?target=ijor%3Ajha&amp;volume=5&amp;issue=2&amp;article=002</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Journal of Hill Agriculture</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">0976-7606</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.5/n.2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>