<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016101011">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">The Effects of Different Levels of Salinity and Indole-3-Acetic Acid (IAA) on Early Growth and Germination of Wheat Seedling</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Abdoli Majid</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Saeidi Mohsen</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Azhand Mandana</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Jalali-Honarmand Saeid</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Esfandiari Ezatollah</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Shekari Fariborz</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2013-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F60</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Seed filling</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Foliar application</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Salinity</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_26785</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3008</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6751</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Salt stress as a major adverse factor can lower germination, ion toxicity, reduction in enzymatic and photosynthetic efficiency and other physiological disorders and ultimately lower crop productivity in salinity zones. As growth regulators are involved in altering growth processes in plants, it is possible that they might even reduce the detrimental effects of salinity by stimulating growth. But their physiological roles are not well known. In example, about the roles of IAA in salinity conditions are not similar viewpoints. For this purpose a factorial experiment based on completely randomized design was conducted with influence of foliar application of Indole-3-Acetic Acid (IAA) in farm on germination percent and seedling growth parameters of wheat (cv. Marvdasht) under different levels (0, 40, 80 and 120 mM) of NaCl salinity with 3 replications, during 2012 in the laboratory research of the Department of plant breading and agronomy, Faculty of Agriculture, Maragheh University in Maragheh state in Iran. The results of this study indicate, that salinity decreased the plumule,  radicle  and  seedling  length  and  plumule,  radicle  and  seedling  dry  weight,  seed germination  and  seedling  vigor  index,  whereas  increase  in  mean  germination  time  and  no signification plumule/radicle ratio observed in the cultivar tested. Also, application of IAA at cell division stage of grain growth caused significant increase in seedling growth parameters under different salinity levels. The interaction between application of IAA and salinity levels significantly affected final germination percentage. Highest final germination percentage was recorded with IAA with  increasing  salinity  level  from  0  up  to  120  mM  NaCl  (98.3,  98.3,  96.7  and  100%  without significant differences between them, respectively).</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.jspb.ru/issues/2013/N4/JSPB_2013_4_329-338.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">en</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Journal of Stress Physiology &amp;amp; Biochemistry</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1997-0838</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.9/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>