<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016102989">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Impact of Cinnamic Acid on Physiological and Anatomical Changes in Maize Plants (Zea mays L.) Grown under Salinity Stress</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Singh Pramod Kumar</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Chaturvedi Varun Kumar</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F60</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Adaptation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Lipid peroxidation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">осмотический стресс</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Zea mays</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_117</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_34043</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_35750</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8504</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The environmental contamination with high salt is the elementary intimidation to the agriculture. Maize plants were deeply affected due to salinity worldwide and a severe problem to scientists. A probable survival strategy of the plants under unpleasant environmental circumstances is to use of endogenous metabolites that could ameliorate the harsh effect of salinity. Current study was under taken to observe the effect of cinnamic acid (CA), a central molecule of phenylpropanoid pathway (Secondary metabolism) on the growth and development of maize plants under NaCl stress conditions. CA is rapidly produced by plants in response to stressful condition. Response to maize seed to the presoaking treatment 0.05mM CA was deliberated under different concentration of NaCl stress such as 50, 100, 150, 200, mM NaCl for 14 days. The injurious effects of salinity on growth and development were manifested by decreased fresh weight, dry weight, and relative water content (RWC) and chlorophyll pigment contents. Degree of lipid peroxidation turned down through the significant decrease in MDA content in maize seedlings. CA induced the anatomical properties under salinity .In present exploration. The cortical cells were induced in root in response to CA than stress. Here, the present study was undertaken with the aim of determining salt induced anatomical and morphological alteration in the presence of exogenous CA. The major reduction in dimension of cortical cells was observed which indicate that salt stress reduced the tolerance of cortical cell more than treatment in maize root. We conclude that CA is a potential phenylpyranoid for protecting crop plant under saline environment.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.jspb.ru/issues/2014/N2/JSPB_2014_2_44-54.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">en</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Journal of Stress Physiology &amp;amp; Biochemistry</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1997-0838</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.10/n.2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>