<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016100870">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Synergetic action of light and temperature on seed germination of some solanaceae members</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Barakat Nasser A.M.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Kabeil H.F.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Hegazy A.K.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Singer Nesrine S.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2013-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">H60</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Germination</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">ecology</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Solanaceae</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Temperature</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Light</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Seeds</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Vigour</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Dormancy</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3247</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2467</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7215</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7657</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4322</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6946</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_37512</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2369</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The  objective  of  the  present  study  was  to  evaluate   the  effects  of  nine  combinations  of temperature  and  light  on  seeds  germination  of  four  solanaceae  species  (Datura  innoxia, Hyoscyamus muticus, Solanum nigrum and Withania somnifera)  in germination chamber. The influence of combined of three alternative temperature regimes from 10 to 40 °C, with 10°C intervals, under three light levels (the continuous white light, alternative and darkness) were tested. The germination parameters as germination percentage, seed vigor index, dormancy, germination  speed  and  germination  index,  and  were  measured  and  calculated.  The  data reveled some similarities in germination percentage and seedling vigor index among  Datura innoxia, Solanum  nigrum in  one  hand  and  between  Hyscyamus  muticus and  Withinia sommenefreae on the other hand, while germination speed and germination index showed some similarities between  Datura innoxia, Withinia sommenefreae and between  Hyscyamus muticus and  Solanum nigrum. The optimum condition for the germination of the seeds was varied  with  species  (species-dependent):  some  species  Hyoscyamus  muticus and  Withinia sommenefreae germinate easier under combined effects of light and temperature, whereas, Solanum nigrum and Datura innoxia decreased their germination in darkness conditions. The maximal germination was reached in Hyoscyamus muticus  follwed by Withania somnifera, Solanum nigrum and Datura innoxia species under wide range of selected combinations. With the  exception  of Datura  innoxia  all  other  species  seemed  a  photoplastic  character.  No relationship  was  found  between  germination  percentage  and  alternating  temperature especially in Hyoscyamus muticus and Withania somnifera. Alternating temperature is not the main  factor  affecting  germination  percentage.  We  concluded  that  the  regime  of  light suppressed  the  effects  alternating  temperatures  on  seed  germination  of  Datura  innoxia species. It  was  concluded  that  synergized  effects  of  light  and  alternating  temperatures, enhanced seed germination of Hyoscyamus mutucs and Solanum nigrum. Thus, the light regime can play a vital role in present and future weed management strategies.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.jspb.ru/issues/2013/N4/JSPB_2013_4_85-100.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">en</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Journal of Stress Physiology &amp;amp; Biochemistry</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1997-0838</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.9/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>