<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016113846">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Initial Morphogenetic Features of Proteome of Suprastructures of Interphase Chromatin for Germination of Mature Germs in Conditions of Adapting to Winter in Wheat</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Ivanova E.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Vafina G.H.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Ivanov R.S.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F62</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Winter</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Proteolysis</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Chromatin</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">spring</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8410</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6261</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1593</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7336</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Investigation morphogenetic processes of how the plant is formed for interact with the environment is necessary to understanding the fundamental problems of stress supramolecular biochemistry of developmental biology. Modern biology has established that the molecular morphogenesis belonging to the number of morphological processes. The molecular morphogenesis is directly based on well-studied forces of intermolecular interactions. From the progress of understanding the morphogenesis, expected not only purely cognitive, but also the practical results of biotechnology.
The purpose of work was the analysis of shielding of morphogenetic suprastructures of interphase chromatin matrix to the localization of sensitivity of the regulatory proteolysis in the conditions of adaptation of vegetative phase of wheat to the stressful environmental factors. It was shown that in the conditions of long-term adaptation to cold shock of wheat at the level of suprastructures, of the packaged in the nuclear matrix of the genome, is carried out the total shielding of arginine-X zones for the regulatory protease-processing. Perhaps these zones represents one of the elements of the LCR (locus control regions), which are related to the histone code and influence the architectural organization of the cell nucleus, which is formed to facilitate life of organism in complex environmental conditions.
These data will be useful for those who involved in the development of mathematical-logic schemes of theory and practice of biological specificity and may be included in the ontology of stages of plant growth and development.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.jspb.ru/issues/2015/N4/JSPB_2015_4_29-42.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">en</dc:language>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Journal of Stress Physiology &amp;amp; Biochemistry</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1997-0838</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.11/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>