<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016H10363">
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">СПОСОБ ОСЛАБЛЕНИЯ СИЛЬНЫХ ЗЕМЛЕТРЯСЕНИЙ</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>METHOD OF WEAKENING THE STRONG EARTHQUAKES</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>РОЗОВСКИЙ Н.С.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">B10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Earthquakes</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2440</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Продолжающиеся много десятилетий усилия сейсмологов разработать эффективный оперативный прогноз безуспешны и, скорее всего, беcперспективны. Цель настоящей работы показать: во_первых, целесообразность переключения усилий сейсмологов и инженеров на ослабление сильных землетрясений</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">во-вторых, реалистичность и своевременность этого направления. В статье это впервые рассматривается как конкретная практическая задача. Для её решения разработаны методы расчёта всех стадий выполнения работы. Выбраны реальные исходные данные. Использована фактическая статистика землетрясений. Выполнены количественные расчёты. Получены следующие оценки: стоимость проекта ~10·10 6 USD, будут обезврежены ~(35-95)% всех опасных землетрясений, при этом выигрыш заметно превзойдёт затраты. В районах страдающих от частых сильных неглубоких (</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">The ongoing efforts of seismic experts to develop an effective operational forecast that continued for many decades were unsuccessful and, most likely, unpromising. The aim of this article is to show: firstly - practicability of switching efforts of seismologists and engineers to prevent major earthquakes</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">secondly - feasibility and timeliness of this direction. This article for the first time sees the above-mentioned issue as a concrete practical problem. Methods of calculation of all stages of work were developed for its solution by using actual raw data. Quantitative calculations were made based on actual statistics of earthquakes. The following estimates were received: total cost of the project will be USD ~10*10 6, and about ~35-95 % of all dangerous earthquakes will be neutralised. Thus, the benefit would surpass the costs significantly. In areas suffering from frequent severe shallow (&lt; 25 km) earthquakes, to start work on their neutralisation is advisable already at the present time.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://research-journal.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/5-4-36.pdf#page=79</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">en</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Международный научно-исследовательский журнал</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2303-9868</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.4/n.5 (36)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>