<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="AL2016104536">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Evaluation of Differences on the Sensory Characteristics of Wine Produced from Non-Dried and Dried Grapes by Using Discriminative Sensory Test, Two out of Five</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>PEÇULI ANISA</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>MANE ERANDA</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Department of Agroalimentary Biotechnology, Faculty of Biotechnology and Food, Agricultural University of Tirana, Kodër-Kamëz, Tiranë, Albania.</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Food Research Center, Faculty of Biotechnology and Food, Agricultural University of Tirana, Kodër-Kamëz, Tiranë, Albania.</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">analysis</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_49928</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang=" ">Eight wines produced from Kallmet and Cabernet Sauvignon, from non-dried and dried grapes and in two years 2011 and 2013 were subjected of discriminative sensory test 2out of 5. The aim of the study was to confirm by human perception, the chemical data that shows differences between wines from non-dried and dried grapes. A group of 15 trained panelist after tasted the wines in a blind test were asked to group the wines in two groups according to their similarity. After a small break a visual evaluation took place. The panelists were asked which of the wines were more intense in color. Data showed that for the first test (2 out of 5) the panelist were able to differ with a high significance level between the wines from non-dried and dried grapes, for both varieties and for both year of production. The visual test also shows that for year 2011 the panelist differ between wines of Kallmet 9 of them evaluate wines from dried grapes as more intense and for wines of 2013, 10 panelist evaluate wines of dried Kallmet as more intense than non-dried. For Cabernet wines of this year 10 panelist evaluate the wines from non-dried grapes as more intense in color.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">https://sites.google.com/a/ubt.edu.al/rssb/ajas_2014/5_Anisa%20Peculi_pp%2026-30.pdf?attredirects=0&amp;d=1</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">en</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Albanian Journal of Agricultural Sciences</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2218-2020</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.13/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>