<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="AL2016111626">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Effect of Partial Root Drying (PRD) and Potassium Fertilizer on Water Use Efficiency and Agronomical Characteristics of Canola (Brassica Napus L.)</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>RAHIMI MOHAMMAD</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Department of Agriculture, Yasooj Branch, Islamic Azad University, Yasooj, Iran</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">In order to evaluate the interaction of the Partial root-zone drying (PRD) and potassium fertilizer on the water
consumption efficiency and agronomical characteristics of canola, an experiment was conducted during 2012-13
in Semirom, Isfahan province, Iran. Factorial testing was carried out in split plot, randomized complete design
(RCD) in four replications. The irrigation had the main plot with three factors, control (irrigation), intermittent
irrigation Partial root-zone drying (PRD), constant irrigation Partial root-zone drying (PRD) at one side of the
roots, and potassium fertilizer in subplots in three levels: 0, 50, 100 kg/ha. The study specifications include:
number of pods per plant, number of seeds in pod, weight of thousand grains, biological yield, yield, harvest
index, and water consumption efficiency after data analysis, the results of the experiment showed that the
irrigation effect on all specifications was significant at 1% probability. Finding showed The highest yield was
observed at 79/3 %, which was equal to 47,330 kg/ha with consumption of water 53% in interaction of
intermittent Partial Root Drying (PRD) and 100 kg/ha potassium fertilizer treatment. Based on the results, in
order to Efficiency in irrigation using of intermittent Partial Root Drying (PRD) and 100 kg/ha potassium
fertilizer treatment is recommended for cultivation in areas that climatic conditions similar to Semirom.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">https://sites.google.com/a/ubt.edu.al/rssb/revista_3_2015_file/2_RAHIMI%20MM_N3_pp%20214-221.pdf?attredirects=0&amp;d=1</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Albanian Journal of Agricultural Sciences</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2218-2020</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.14/n.3</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>