<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="AL2016102304">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Forage, Grass pea, Intercropping, Actual yield loss, LER, Monetary advantag</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>REXHEPI AGIM</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>SHERIFI KURTESH</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>SCHEINERT PETER</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>GRAPCI-KOTORRI LINDA</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Department of veterinary, Faculty of Agricultural and Veterinary, University of Prishtina ‘’Hasan Prishtina”, Prishtina, Kosovo</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Animal Health Service (Tiergesundheitsdienst -TGD), Bayern E. V., Munich, Germany</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Department of Biology, Faculty of Mathematics and Natural Sciences, University of Prishtina ‘’Hasan Prishtina”, Prishtina, Kosovo</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Fish diseases</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Oncorhynchus mykiss</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2920</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33779</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The viral diseases of rainbow trout are of worldwide concern including infectious pancreatic necrosis (IPN). On this study good sanitary practices are applied to prevent outbreaks and minimize losses caused from IPN disease. To highlight importance of improvements on sanitary practices in IPN prevention were compared results from two studies, first conducted in year 2006-2009 with results from one year later study conducted in 2010. In year 2010, samples of organs are collected from 260 fish and pooled in 43 samples, taken in 18 trout farms. Samples are analyzed with RT-PCR method. In the second study the IPN virus was detected in 6 from 43 pools (14%) showing higher infection rate comparing to first study (11.5%) and in 4 from 18 fish farms (22.2%) showing lower infection rate than in first study with 7 from 13 fish farms (53.8%). Results indicated that application of good sanitary practices reduces IPNV presence in fish, but not in fish farms where infection already is established and do not apply preventive measures. The purpose of this paper is to describe occurrence of IPNV and application of good sanitary practices in order to reduce disease outbreaks in rainbow trout fish farming.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Albanian Journal of Agricultural Sciences</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2218-2020</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.13/n.1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>