<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="AL2016106245">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">The Interaction of Season Collection of Cuttings, Indol Butyric Acid (IBA) and Juvenility Factors on Root Induction in Olea europaea L. Cultivar Kokërr Madhi i Beratit</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>LAZAJ ADHURIM</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>RAMA PETRIT</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>VUKSANI GJOK</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Agricultural Technology Transfer Center (ATTC), Vlore- ALBANIA</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Department of Horticulture and Landscape Architecture, Agricultural University of Tirana, Tirana, Albania</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">olive</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_12926</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Differences in the root ability of olive cuttings in the juvenile and mature form are reported. The root ability of cuttings from juvenile and mature olive shoots together with the influence of season stem collection and different concentration of  IBA have been studied. The shoots coming from the olive ovule located at the base of the trunk  are affected by  juvenility factors. Leafy stem cuttings of olive cv. “Kokërr Madhi i Beratit” were obtained from 1-year-old olive shoots sampled on March 25th, April 15th, August 1st and September 1st during the 2013 growing season.
The shoots were collected from the olive ovule located at the base of the tree (juvenile form) and from canopy  of the tree (mature form). To improve the rooting of olive cuttings, different concentrations of  IBA, (0,2000,4000, 6000 and 10000 ppm) are applied. 
The percentage of rooted cuttings sampled on March 25t h and April 15th   was markedly greater than those sampled on the other seasons (August 1st and September 1st). The concentration 4000 ppm of IBA was most effective. In all the seasons and  concentrations of IBA the juvenility modified significantly higher rooting of cuttings.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B_i7_HlsPT6HSjQ2bXVnN2xWTWM/view?usp=sharing</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Albanian Journal of Agricultural Sciences</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2218-2020</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.14/n.1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>