<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="AL2016117439">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Current Situation of the Solid Waste Management in Gjirokastra Region: Problems and Challenges for the Future</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>ÇUÇI ORNELA</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>META ADEM</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>SALLAKU FATBARDH</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>SHKURT REXHEP</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Eqerem Çabej University, Gjirokastra</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2016-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The system of collecting waste and the current situation in their management is the main objective of this paper, to
help the local government for sustainable waste management in the district of Gjirokastra. Through this study it was
possible the provision of a database for the management of actual waste at the regional level, an analysis of actual
system of waste management, the criteria necessary for managing them through an approach of sustainable
development environmental, economic and social. Geographical space, which is the objective of this study is
Gjirokastra district, consisting of three districts and currently, according to the new territorial division of 6
municipalities. To provide data on the current situation of waste used the data of municipalities and communes under
the old territorial division. Processing of this database, the most important qualities and characteristics of the area are
classified into 6 new municipalities functioning. Also they have interviewed over 250 employees and stakeholders the
respective municipalities, and are inventoried evidence on policy practices and technologies used. They were
examined waste prevention policies at national, regional and local enforcement practices, and based on general
descriptions of available activities to prevent / reuse / recycling has prepared a detailed SWOT analyze. With SWOT
analysis and data arising from it the results of this study suggest measures for the sustainable management of waste in
the district of Gjirokastra, because the waste generated is collected without any prior sorting and no recycling process
for hazardous waste appliances (batteries, etc. together with them even hospital waste). Disposal of waste from
communities and municipalities realized using plastic bags or not, but without any preliminary separation according to
their content or without taking into consideration all the resource sharing and protection from further
urbanization.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">https://sites.google.com/a/ubt.edu.al/rssb/ajas_1_2016-1/3_CUCI%20AND%20SALLAKU%20pp%2013-18.pdf?attredirects=0&amp;d=1</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.15/n.1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>