<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="AL2016109828">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Comparison of Two Approaches for Pasture Inventory in Albania</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>MYRTOLLARI ZENI</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>PASHO EDMOND</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>State Inspectorate of Environment and Forestry, Ministry of Environment, Tirana - Albania</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Faculty of Forestry Sciences, Agricultural University of Tirana, Tirana - Albania</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Pastures</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Remote sensing</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Geographical information systems</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5626</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6498</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_35131</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Abstract section. This study presents the evaluation of two approaches (field and remote sensing - GIS) applied for
inventorying pasture condition in Albania. The field inventory was carried out by trained experts in the context of the
latest Albanian National Forest Inventory (ANFI), based on 162 sample plots chosen randomly over the pasture areas.
At each sample plotit was collected detailed data about pasture condition which were made available for this study. The
second approachwe applied, consisted of a combination of Remote Sensing and GIS algorithms to derive several
variable maps(classified into a number of classes): cover components of pastures,slope, aspect, elevation, erosion,
distance from the hydrologic network, road network and the location of villages. The results indicated significant
differences between both methodologies, especially for the cover components of pastures, where a difference of 14%
was found regarding the evaluation of herbaceous species. Environmental and pasture use variables appeared to be
evaluated differently too, especially the erosion level and distances of pastures from thevillages, networks of roads and
water sources.We conclude that the main reason for such discrepancy should bethe low coverage of pasture area in
terms of number of sample plots as well as their distribution.Based on the findings of this study, it is recommended that
in the future, inventory of pasture condition should be done as much as possible using Remote Sensing and GIS
technology because it guarantees full coverage of the study area, reduces the field work which is expensive and time
consuming, and provides more reliable evaluation of pasture conditio</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">https://sites.google.com/a/ubt.edu.al/rssb/revista_2_2015_files/18_ZENI%20MYRTOLLARI%20pp%20198-205.pdf?attredirects=0&amp;d=1</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Albanian Journal of Agricultural Sciences</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2218-2020</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.14/n.2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>