<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="AL2016109732">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Molecular Diversity and Genetic Structure of Durum Wheat Landraces</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>SHIKHSEYIDOVA GULNAR</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>AKHUNDOVA ELLADA</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>QULIYEV RAUF</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>ESHGHI ROHAM</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>SALAYEVA SAMIRA</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>OJAGHI JAVID</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Department of Biotechnology, Genetic Resources Institute of Azerbaijan National Academy of Sciences, Baku, Azerbaijan</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">To determine the genetic diversity of durum wheat, 41 accessions from Morocco, Ethiopia, Turkey, Lebanon,
Kazakhstan, China, and Mongolia were analyzed through Inter-Simple Sequence Repeats (ISSR) molecular
markers. Out of the used twenty primers, 15 primers that included a considerable polymorphism were selected for
the analyses. Among the genotypes under study, 163 fragments (73.7%) were polymorph. Several indexes were
used to determine the most appropriate primers. While UBC812, UBC864, UBC840, and UBC808 primers were
among those markers which produced the highest number of bands and polymorphic bands, they also dedicated the
highest rate of polymorphic index content (PIC). These primers also possessed the highest amounts of effective
multiplex ratio (EMR) and marker index (MI). Therefore, these primers can be recommended for genetic evaluation
of the durum wheat. The results of cluster analysis and principle component analysis indicated that the observed
genetic diversity in wheat materials under study is geographically structured. The results also indicated that the
genetic diversity index based on ISSR markers was higher for Turkey, Lebanon, Morocco, and Ethiopia accessions
than for other countries. The high level of polymorphism in this collections durum wheat would agree with the
suggestion that Fertile Crescent and parts of Africa are first possible diversity center of this crop.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">https://sites.google.com/a/ubt.edu.al/rssb/revista_2_2015_files/6_GULNAR%20pp%20112-120.pdf?attredirects=0&amp;d=1</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Albanian Journal of Agricultural Sciences</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2218-2020</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.14/n.2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>