<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="AL2016111666">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">A GIS Approach for the Managemnt Purposes and the Floristic and Vegetation Features of the “Grand Park” of Tirana</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>MESITI AJOLA</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>DINGA LIRI</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>GALLONI MARTA</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>PEZZI GIOVANNA</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Botanical Garden, Research Centre of Flora and Fauna, Faculty of Natural Science, University of Tirana, Albania</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Faculty of Natural Science, University of Tirana, Albania</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Department of Biological Geological and Environmental Sciences,Bologna University, Italy</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en" />
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Geographical information systems</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_35131</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Environmental analysis of flora, vegetation and zoningin the “Grand Park” of Tirana (Albania) were carried out for
management purposeswith GIS program.The Grand Park, which lies in the hills south of the city, covers a land area
of about 220 ha plus 48 ha of water. The Park was built on an existing area of vegetation where species of Albanian
flora were planted and some exotic species introduced, thus representing a "hybrid” park with natural and artificial
features. It is surrounded by residential buildings, commercial and national roads with heavy traffic.The species and
vegetation types of the park were sampled to identify the most important for conservation and management purposes</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">to analyse their origin and distribution in relation to anthropogenic impacts, and to provide general information on
their ecology.Distribution of different green areas within the park was derived by interpreting aerial photographs, and
by using Geographical Information Systems (Esri ArcGIS). The current map was compared with a previous one to
detect the dynamics of the green urban areas.The environmental diagnosis identified several types of activities
potentially harmful to the biodiversity of the “Grand Park” and the environmental quality of the city. Implementation
of a management plan would be essential to maintain and preserve this urban park, aiming to ensure its role in
improving the quality of urban life. The survey results showed that within the park area 69% of the species were wild
and 31% introduced.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">https://sites.google.com/a/ubt.edu.al/rssb/revista_3_2015_file/8_Mesiti%20A-N3_pp%20256-261.pdf?attredirects=0&amp;d=1</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Albanian Journal of Agricultural Sciences</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2218-2020</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.14/n.3</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>