<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="AL2016102279">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Exploring Strategy for Intervention at Cocoa Research Institute of Nigeria</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>BABALOLA FOLARANMI D.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Forest resources Management, University of Ilorin, Ilorin, Kwara State, Nigeria Centre for Environmental Economics and Policy in Africa, University of Pretoria, Pretoria, South Africa</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Inadequate funding has been identified as critical issue confronting researchers in Nigeria. However, information on the financial challenges faced by researchers in research institutes is scanty. The study therefore evaluates the funding issues faced by researchers in Cocoa Research Institutes of Nigeria (CRIN). Structured questionnaire was administered to randomly selected researchers across different cadres and sections of the institute. It was noted that the Government provides bulk of the funding use for research in the institute, but this fund is inadequate and irregular. The ease of getting information on funding and sponsorships (p=0.000), research funding (p=0.005), and provision of fund by the institute to attend conferences (p=0.001) are significant and depend on cadres of the researchers. Lower cadres of the researchers in the institute received the least funding opportunities. As a coping strategy, quite a number of the researchers spent their salary to conduct research, publish their research findings, and attend conferences. There is need for the institute to diversify its source of funding, and initiate collaborations with industry and other private sector. The researchers also need to initiate linkages and network with other researchers at local and international levels.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Albanian Journal of Agricultural Sciences</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2218-2020</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.13/n.1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>