<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="AL2016109645">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">“Optimum Currency Area” in the Balkan Region</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>SPAHO MATEO</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Faculty of Economics, European University of Tirana, Tirana - Albania</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Balkan</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Economic growth</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_799</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2474</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">In economics, an “Optimum Currency Area”, also known as an optimal currency region (OCR), is a
geographical region in which it would maximize economic efficiency to have the entire region share a single
currency. It describes the optimal characteristics for the merger of currencies or the creation of a new currency.
The theory is used often to argue whether or not a certain region is ready to become a currency union, one of the
final stages in economic integration. Over time, step by step, is expected to join the EU Albania too. In a
continuous and closer integration there’s a question if would have been profitable whether our country can adopt
a common currency (Euro), as many countries did in the EU, or is better to follow another example that stops a
further integration after EU membership, like (United Kingdom, Sweden, etc.).
It is Euro the right choice as a common currency for the EU? What are the criteria for an Optimum Currency
Area? Do have different countries profitability with different levels of wealth, different populations and
diversified products, adopting the samecurrencyor not? Through thetheoryof"Optimal CurrencyArea" elaborated
by RobertMundell, Ronald Mc Kinnon and Peter Kenneth,will beanalyzed notonly if Europe is one of the
Optimal Currency Area.It will be also analyzed whether the Balkan countries, divided byethnic, historical and
cultural reasons, will have benefits from a common currency or at the opposite, a common currency would slow
down their economic growth.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">https://sites.google.com/a/ubt.edu.al/rssb/revista_2_2015_files/1_SPAHO%20M_pp%2073-78.pdf?attredirects=0&amp;d=1</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Albanian Journal of Agricultural Sciences</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2218-2020</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.14/n.2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>