<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="AL2016109669">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Land Use Change in the Corridor Tirana-Durrës caused by Urban Development</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>SULAJ ANILA</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>THEMELKO HENRJETA</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>SHUMELI ARJAN</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Department of Foreign Languages, Faculty of Veterinary Medicine, Agriculture University of Tirana, Tirana, Albania</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Land</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4172</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Urban development in the study area is associated with the change of land use. From the data obtained in our study it is
shown that along the Tirana-Durres highway there has been noticed a change in the destination of the land use. Results
of the survey show that: 21.7% of surveyed persons claim that land is used for the construction of private housing where
many migrant families have had their pressing needs and social and economic interests that simultaneously created
various commercial activities. 54.7% of respondents claim that the land is used for agricultural purposes. Agriculture
remains one of the few important sectors of the economy despite the tendency of transformation of the whole area into
an industrial corridor. 20.5% of the land is used for various business activities and industries. The evaluation of the
residents for the land use shows more clearly the importance of this highway on the development of commerce and
industry where there is growth in the number of commercial and industrial activities.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">https://sites.google.com/a/ubt.edu.al/rssb/revista_2_2015_files/3_ANILA%20SULAJ_pp%2087-92.pdf?attredirects=0&amp;d=1</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Albanian Journal of Agricultural Sciences</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2218-2020</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.14/n.2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>