<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="BR2016202853">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Sanitary quality of castor bean seeds (cv. IAC-226)</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="pt">
      <dcterms:alternative>Qualidade sanitária de sementes de mamona (cv. IAC-226)</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Márcia Santos de Souza David Andréia</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Fontes Araujo Eduardo</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Fontes Araujo Roberto</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Hiydu Mizobutsi Edson</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Tiago Ribeiro Amaro Hugo</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Tavares Dos Reis Sidnei</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidade Estadual de Montes Claros, Janauba, MG, Brasil</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidade Federal de Viçosa, Viçosa, MG, Brasil</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Empresa de Pesquisa Agropecuária de Minas Gerais, Viçosa, MG, Brasil</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidade Estadual de Montes Claros, Janauba, MG, Brasil</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidade Federal de Viçosa, Viçosa, MG, Brasil</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidade Estadual de Montes Claros, Janauba, MG, Brasil</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F03</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Biodiesel</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Fungi</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en" />
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_35013</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3145</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1325847944301</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The objective of this work was to evaluate the fungicides efficacy on the castor seeds IAC-226 sanitary quality. The seeds were treated with two doses of the fungicides captan (250 and 300 g ai 100 kg-1 seed), thiophanate-methyl (100 and 150 g ai 100 kg-1 seed) and thiabendazole (100 and 150
g kg ai 100 seeds). Seeds without fungicide treatment were the control. The seeds sanitary quality was evaluated by sanity test, using 10 replications of 20 seeds per treatment/lot, superficially sterilized (sodium hypochlorite) and placed in plastic boxes (gerbox) with filter paper and sterilized distilled
water, under controlled temperature 25°C for 20 days. Seeds were examinated individually using a stereoscopic  microscope and optical microscope. The results were expressed as percentage of infected seeds. The experimental design was completely randomized in a factorial arrangement (2 x 7), two lots and seven treatments, with ten repetitions. The fungicides captan, tiabendazol and
tiofanato-metílico reduced the incidence of fungi, being recommended for the castor seeds IAC-226 treatment. There was a predominance of fungi Alternaria alternata, Aspergillus flavus, Aspergillus niger, Bipolar, Botrytis ricini, Curvularia sp., Penicillium sp. and Rhizopus sp.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="pt">Objetivou-se com este trabalho avaliar a eficiência de fungicidas na qualidade sanitária de sementes de mamona, cultivar IAC-226. As sementes foram tratadas com duas doses dos fungicidas captan (250 e 300 g i.a 100 kg-1 de sementes), tiofanato-metílico (100 e 150 g i.a 100 kg-1 de sementes) e tiabendazol (100 e 150 g i.a 100 kg-1 de sementes). Sementes sem tratamento constituíram a
testemunha. Para a avaliação da qualidade sanitária das sementes pelo teste de sanidade, utilizou-se de 10 repetições de 20 sementes por tratamento/lote, desinfestadas superficialmente (com hipoclorito de sódio) e acondicionadas em caixas plásticas tipo gerbox, com papel de filtro e água destilada esterilizados, permanecendo sob temperatura controlada de 25 ºC por 20 dias. Examinaram-se as sementes individualmente com auxílio de lupa estereoscópica e microscópio ótico, e os resultados expressos em porcentagem de sementes infectadas. O delineamento utilizado foi o inteiramente casualizado, em arranjo fatorial (2 x 7), sendo dois lotes e sete tratamentos, com dez repetições. Os fungicidas captan, tiabendazol e tiofanato-metilíco reduziram a incidência de fungos, sendo eficientes para o tratamento de sementes de mamona. Houve predominância dos fungos Alternaria alternata, Aspergillus flavus, Aspergillus niger, Bipolares, Botrytis ricini, Curvularia sp.
Penicillium sp. e Rhizopus sp.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://comunicata.ufpi.br/index.php/comunicata/article/download/452/258</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">en</dc:language>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">pt</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Comunicata Scientiae</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2176-9079</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.5/n.3</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>