<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="BR2016202447">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Bovine biofertilizer and irrigation layers on lettuce development and leaf chlorophyll</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="pt">
      <dcterms:alternative>Biofertilizante bovino e laminas de irrigação no desenvolvimento e clorofila foliar da alface</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Chiconato Denise Aparecida</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Faculdade de Ciências Agrárias e Veterinárias, Universidade Estadual Paulista “Júlio de Mesquita Filho”, Jaboticabal, SP, Brasil</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F62</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">water</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8309</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">It is necessary and urgent the search by sources of organic fertilizer and decrease the consumption of water for irrigation. In the context, the aim of this study was to evaluate the nutritional effects of the use of bovine biofertilizers incorporated into the soil and of the irrigation in the development of lettuce. The research was developed, using an experimental design in randomized blocks, factorial
scheme 6x2, with six levels of fertilization (4 doses of bovine biofertilizer and two witnesses: without fertilizer and mineral fertilizer) and two irrigation layers (80 and 100% of reference evapotranspiration) with four replications, in the field. The variables analyzed were: height, head diameter, chlorophyll,
leaf number, fresh matter and dry matter of plant tops. It was performed by analysis of variance of F test, comparison of means by Tukey test (p</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://comunicata.ufpi.br/index.php/comunicata/article/download/349/237</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">en</dc:language>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">pt</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Comunicata Scientiae</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2176-9079</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.5/n.2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>