<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="IN2016106147">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Study on yak husbandry in Mustang district of Nepal</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>ACHARYA KP</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">A50</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">inbreeding</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">feeding</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">health care</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3817</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2838</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_49891</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang=" ">Traditional livestock production
systems in highland areas of Nepal involve animals,
especially yak and yak cattle hybrids as a source of
food, prestige and security among the nomadic
communities. Yak, which is also known as 'the camel
of snow', is the livestock of choice among nomadic
communities and is considered as the symbol of
wealth. This study was done to document the present
status of yak husbandry system, problems and proscons
of transhumant pastoralism in the Mustang
District of Nepal. 32 yak herders and 15 key persons,
including the local leaders and traditional healers were
interviewed with semi-structured questionnaires during
February to May 2014. From this questionnaire survey
and field visits, it revealed that grazing system is the
only feeding system with little or no feed
supplementation. The population and herd size are
decreasing year by year. The herders are still following
the uncontrolled methods of breeding with one male
serving all the females, till its productive age, with a
high degree of inbreeding. Disease endemicity,
shortage of pasture, closure of Tibetan border for
pasturing, increased draught period, lack of technical
and veterinary facilities and low productivity are
compelling herders to abandon the yak farming. They the treatment of disease, pests and poisoning with very
little or no help from professional veterinarian.
Although single species transhumant pastoralist is
moderately efficient with the integration of local
knowledge in all aspects of animal husbandry, it needs
to be strengthened by integration of scientific method
in breeding and feeding of yaks. Immediate strong
extension programs, including the bilateral
coordination between yak herders and researchers
should be carried out, otherwise yak and their valuable
resources will be rooted out from this country.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.indianjournals.com/ijor.aspx?target=ijor%3Ajha&amp;volume=5&amp;issue=2&amp;article=003</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">en</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Journal of Hill Agriculture</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">0976-7606</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.5/n.2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>