<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="SK2016017134">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Analysis of texturometric properties of selected traditional and commercial sausage</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Zajác Peter</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Čurlej Jozef</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Barnová,  Miroslava</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">Q02</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">sausages</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Properties</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6824</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_49874</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Food texture is one of the main features that affect the consumer's judgment. Instrumental texture analysis is suitable method for objective assessment of the texturometric characteristic of food. In this experimental work we have analysed textural properties of different traditional and commercial sausages originating from Slovakia. Twenty sausages were classified in four groups. Group 1 (traditional home-made sausages purchased directly from a producer), Group 2 (traditional sausages purchased from butchery), Group 3 (non-traditional sausages purchased from a supermarket) and Group 4 (non- traditional sausages purchased from a hypermarket). Once taken, samples were immediately transported to the laboratory. Samples were analysed immediately and after the storage 72 h at 25 °C and 80% relative humidity. Samples were analysed with texturometer TA-XT2 plus and we have used the Warner-Bratzler probe. The main reason of this experiment was to find differences for two selected textural parameters, firmness and toughness of the fresh and stored sausages. The average firmness and toughness of fresh sausages before storage were 1.83 kg and 12.86 kg.s respectively. These values were increased after the storage. The average firmness and toughness of stored sausages were 2.74 kg and 19.23 kg.s respectively. It means, storage affects the textural properties of sausages (p</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.potravinarstvo.com/journal1/index.php/potravinarstvo/article/view/473/pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.9/n.1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>