<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="SK2016017116">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Seed protein electrophoresis for identification of oat registered cultivars</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Gregová,  Edita</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Šliková,  Svetlana</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>HOZLÁR P.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Slovak University of Agriculture, Nitra, Slovak Republic</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F30</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">oats</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Seed</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">varieties</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Identification</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5287</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6927</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8157</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3791</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The protein diversity of 15 registered oat genotypes (Avena sativa L.) was examined. Acid-PAGE (acid polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis) of avenins and SDS-PAGE (sodium dodecyl sulfate polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis) of the glutelins were used for seed analyses of oat varieties. The result of this study indicated that the genotypes of oat cultivars could effectively be differentiated on the basis of polymorphism, detected between protein patterns. SDS-PAGE result revealed that glutelins presented a higher differentiation power than avenins and could be used as a rapid method for the identification of oat varieties in breeding programmes. Avenin protein band numbers and molecular weight ranged from 5 to 11, and 8 to 45 kDa, respectively. Genetic similarity analysis based on avenin protein ranged from 0,071 to 1. The tree-cluster analysis illustrates the distribution of varieties in two major groups. The first major group was large with eight varieties and following varieties were determined as identical: Vendelín-Zvolen and Prokop-Václav. The second group consisted of six varieties and Detvan-Hronec and Izak-Važec were identical pairs. The number of glutelin protein markers was 22. Genetic similarity coefficients resulted from comparisons by glutelin pattern and they ranged from 0,125 to 0,929 all oat varieties were different from each other. Two Slovakian varieties Izak and Važec from Breeding Station Viglaš-Ptruša with similarity value 92,9% were grouped with variety Vendelin. Two varieties Kanton and Viliam with similiarity value 92% were grouped with Prokop and Valentin. All analysed cultivars could be distinguished by their glutelin pattern and will be useful in oat breeding process</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.potravinarstvo.com/journal1/index.php/potravinarstvo/article/view/513/pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Potravinárstvo</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1337-0960</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.9/n.1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>