<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="SK2016010838">
    <dc:title xml:lang="sk">Výskum vlastností ekologických kvapalín a nových testovacích metód mazacích olejov</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>The research of ecological liquid characteristics</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="">
      <dcterms:alternative>and new testing methods for lubricating oils</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Tkáč Zdenko</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Majdan Radoslav</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Kosiba  Ján</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Slovenská poľnohospodárska univerzita, Nitra</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:publisher>
      <ags:publisherPlace>Nitra</ags:publisherPlace>
    </dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">N01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">biodegradability</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">oils industry</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">hydraulic engineering</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">alternative agriculture</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_28259</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5335</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3713</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_28792</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang=" ">This scientific monograph presents the results of research into the characteristics of biodegradable transmission and hydraulic fluids. The research was focused on a new laboratory method of evaluation of the lubricating properties of fluids. There are three
types of fluids, two biodegradable and one conventionally used mineral oil based type HY. Biodegradable fluid type HETG was produced from rapeseed vegetable oil and synthetic fluid types HEPR was made of poly-alpha-olefin oil. The fluids were loaded
in a special laboratory test bench with tractor hydraulic pump as a main part. In the test bench was ingested temperature measured in the operation of tractor 65 Celsium grade. Fluids were loaded cyclical pressures from OMPa to the nominal pressure of hydraulic pump 20 MPa. The measurement of flow characteristics and decrease flow efficiency calculation shows that in the case of oil-type HV occurred only running-in of hydraulic pump, for biodegradable fluid type HEPR there was wear down and decrease of flow efficiency of 1.3% and highest wear occurred for biodegradable fluid type HETG expressed by decrease flow efficiency of 7.3%. In the research it was observed wear of
hydraulic pump parts such as gears, bearing faces, pins and sliding bearings. The aim was to evaluate a parameter, where hydraulic pump wear is greatest, and which can be evaluated available methods. Each other' s, we compared the visual surface of the teeth, pins and bearing faces, roughness and dimensions of functional surfaces, as well as weight of hydraulic pump components. Visual method requires quite difficult interpretation of the results and experience with this type of technical diagnostics.
Measurement of dimensions and surface roughness is characterized by the use of measuring instruments with high accuracy, the dispersion of the values is quite large and requires multiple repeat measurements and expensive measuring equipment.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN">978-80-552-1140-4</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Book</dc:type>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>