<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="SK2016012855">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Seeds germination of  Arabidopsis arenosa  (L.) Law. and its tolerance to high concentration  of copper</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="sk">
      <dcterms:alternative>Klíčivosť semien  Aradopsis arenosa  (L.) Law a jeho odolnosť na vysoké koncentrácie medi</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Štrba Tomáš</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Matej Bel University, Tajovského 40, 974 01 Banská Bystrica, Slovak Republic, e-mail: strba.thomas@gmail.com</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2013-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F70</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Arabidopsis</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Seed germination</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Copper</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">phytotoxicity</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33291</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_36513</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1868</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5848</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The paper presents the results of the research of seeds germination of Arabidopsis arenosa from the copper mine heap in the ore-district Špania Dolina – Staré Hory with comparison of germination of seeds from reference sites. Arabidopsis arenosa is a good model species and we selected it because of its dominance in floristic compositions on the heaps (together with Silene dioica (L.) Clairv., Acetosella vulgaris Fourr., Agrostis capillaris L.). We found that duration of cold dormancy has no influence on germination of seeds of A. arenosa. With increasing of the concentration of the copper in sulphate solution seed germination of A. arenosa is decreasing. In comparison of roots length of germinated plants (habitat factor) we observed differences in roots length of germinated plants at the 99 % level of confidence (tested by Student t-test). Roots of germinated plants on the heaps were longer than roots of germinated plants from reference sites. Similarly, length of roots of germinated plants (1.5 mm) in different concentrations of copper sulphate solution were considerable shorter than length of roots of germinated plants (8.28 mm) in water (control solution). This difference was statistically confirmed at 99 % level of confidence. The results show on good adaptation skills of this species and on the specific environment conditions of copper dump-fields, which are rich on heavy metals contents.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.tuzvo.sk/files/FEE/fakulta_fee/afe/afe_29.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">sk</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Acta Facultatis Ecologiae</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1336-300X</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.29/n.2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>