<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="SK2016010860">
    <dc:title xml:lang="sk">Fytoremediácia trávneho porastu v Národnom parku Nízke Tatry</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>Phytoremediation of grassland in the Low Tatras National Park</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Novák Ján</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Turanová Lýdia</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Slovak University of Agriculture, Nitra, Slovak Republic</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">phytoremediation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">grasslands</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_36976</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3366</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang=" ">The soils in the conservation areas are often degraded by high concentration of the pollutants folowing the abandonment of the pasture and it is necessary to restare them. The aim of this paper was to restare the degraded grassland (to decrease the amount of phosphorus and potassium in soil) by different methods. In 2004 the experiment was established on degraded sites at locality locality "Pod Kečkou" (Low Tatras National Park, 1 126 m a.s.l.) with three treatments (BM - unmanaged control, K - managed by cutting two times per growing season, PK -managed by cutting two times per growing season and seeding with 18 autochthonous species ing). After eight years in 2011 we noticed tha large decrease of nutrients content in soil (potassium, phosphorus) in K treatment and in PK treatment in comparison with BM treatment (without management), where content of potassium and phosphorus has remained without changes. The results show the method of mowing and seeding the autochthonous species is highly appropriate to restare the degraded sites due to decreasing concentration of pollutants in eutrophic soil.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Agrochémia</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1335-2415</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.19 (55)/n.1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>