<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="SK2016012894">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">The combined effects of application of biological waste from processing of  Jatropha curcas  L.  and organic waste compost on arbuscular mycorrhiza and ON Loss of ammonium nitrogen  from rhizosphere soil</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Elbl Jakub</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Šimečková Jana</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Kintl Antonín</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Foltýnová Anna</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Stroblová Michaela</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Plošek Lukáš</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Mendel University in Brno, Zemědělská 1, 613 00 Brno 13, Czech Republik, e-mail: jakub.elbl@mendelu.cz</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">P35</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Organic wastes</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Jatropha curcas</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">mycorrhizae</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">ammonium nitrogen</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Rhizosphere</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">soil fertility</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_35237</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_16254</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5023</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_37457</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6569</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7170</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Many countries throughout the world are facing to many problems of modern agriculture. The most significant problems are loss of agriculture land by soil erosion, depletion of soil fertility and soil degradation. Soil is a living, dynamic ecosystem essential for our lives. Only healthy arable soil is resistant against these negative phenomena and contents sufficient amount of nutrients which are necessary for crop growth. The cornerstone of this system is the organic matter which must be constantly replenished. This work deals with influence of different type of organic matter on arbuscular mycorrhiza and loss of ammonium nitrogen from rhizosphere soil. To investigate this influence the pot experiment was realized. Seven variants with different doses of compost or jatropha seed cake were prepared, each one in three repetition. The significant differences between individual variants in colonization of roots by arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi were not found. Although the highest level of root colonization was determined in variant with addition of compost and jatropha seed cake. Dose of 50 t/ha of organic matter (25 t of compost and 25 t of jatropha seed cake per hectare) was applied here. On the other hand significant differences were observed in leaching of ammonium-N (nitrogen). The highest loss of ammonium-N was found in variant with dose of 100 t/ha and the second highest loss was observed again in variant with addition of jatropha seed cake (50 t/ha). We conclude that: (1) colonization of roots by arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi can be affected by composition of jatropha seed cake and compost</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">(2) the leaching of ammonium-N from rhizosphere of arable soil is possible and is depended on type of organic matter which is applied there</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">(3) application of mixture of compost and jatropha seed cake positively affects retention of ammonium-N in rhizosphere soil (4) the application of jatropha seed cake without the addition of other organic materials (crop residues, manure, compost etc.) negatively affects leaching of ammonium-N from rhizosphere soil. This is due to composition of jatropha seed cake and its influence on soil microorganisms.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.tuzvo.sk/files/FEE/fakulta_fee/afe/acta-fee-31-2014.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">en</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Acta Facultatis Ecologiae</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1336-300X</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.31/n.2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>