<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="SK2016012464">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Microscopic determination of bamboo fiber in meat products</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Javůrková Zdeňka</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Pospiech Matej</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Zelenková Markéta</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Kameník Josef</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Petrášová Michaela</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Tremlová, B.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Slovak Agricultural University in Nitra, Nitra, Slovak republic</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">Q02</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">U40</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">food processing</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Meat</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">microscopes</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">bamboos</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">fibre crops</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_37969</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4669</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_12546</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_802</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2876</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Fiber, a suitable additive to meat products with water-holding capacity, reduces curing losses and maintains juiciness of the meat. The risk is the use of excessive amounts of flour or other ingredients of vegetable origin, in which the fiber is contained. In some cases, sensory characteristics of products can be affected. Detection of fiber may be prevention of adulteration in some meat products. It is therefore very important to regularly detect the amount of fiber in meat products and check its contents. Fiber in meat products can be detected by various methods, applied are for example gravimetric, spectroscopic, histochemical, and microscopic methods. For this reason, a model meat product (Vysočina salami) was prepared in our experiment with the addition of bamboo fiber of selected concentrations of 0%, 2%, and 3%. Subsequently, a series of microscopic sections was made on different days of curing (day no. 7, 14 of the drying phase and 28, 42 of storage). Individual sections were examined and captured using a polarization microscope, the amounts of fiber in individual sections were analyzed by means of image analysis software and the values obtained were compared with each other. Also the influence of drying on the measured area of fiber in sections was monitored. The results indicate a noticeable reduction in the area of fiber until the seventh day of ripening, which is caused by the rapid loss of water in the product. In contrast, sections of products from the following days of drying contained mildly increased concentrations of fiber, which was caused by gradual drying of the products, while the area of fiber refrained form becoming smaller. Between the individual days of drying, a difference that was statistically significant was demonstrated from the 14th day of (storage or drying). Correlation was observed between the date of (storage or drying) and amount of added fiber. Among the tested mean values for the sample with the addition of fiber concentration of 2 % an insignificant difference was found. The difference between test values (day/fiber) in the sample with addition of 3% fiber was, however, statistically significant.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.potravinarstvo.com/journal1/index.php/potravinarstvo/article/view/452/pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Potravinárstvo</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1337-0960</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.9/n.1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>