<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="SK2016012750">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Assessment of welfare and egg production of laying hens moravia SSL in small-scale breeding</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Angelovičová Mária</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Polačková Dana</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Slovak Agricultural University in Nitra, Nitra, Slovak republic</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">hens</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">eggs</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">welfare</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Efficiency</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_11525</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2502</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_331043</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2491</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The purpose of this study was to investigate  the welfare of laying  hens Moravia SSL housed in small-scale hen house with free range, behavior, egg production and selected physical indicators of eggs and chemical indicators of egg mass. The laying  hens were kept in a hen house on deep litter. Breeding facility of hen house was within the meaning of recommendation for applying the principles of welfare, i.e. the space and breeding  facility within the meaning of enriched breeding environment. Stocking density of the laying hens corresponded with recommendations for unrestricted movement and implementing natural activities.The hen house was equipped with the perch, nest, feeder and drinker. The commercial feed mixture was used for  feeding, which is intended for laying hens. The kitchen remains were added  to feed mixture, as are wet bread, the non-edible remains of foodstuffs. A feed mixture was served to laying  hens 825 g per day. The laying hens had free access to drinking water, grazing, ground pecking, ground scratching and dust-bathing and in  the free range. We focused investigation of on the egg  laying  intensity, selected parameters of physical egg  quality and chemical egg contents. Time to relax of laying  hens was adjusted according to the summer and winter breeding seasons. The main  activities of free-range  hens are grazing, ground pecking, ground scratching and dust-bathing. The main activities of free-range hens are grazing, ground pecking, ground scratching and dust-bathing. These activities were investigated in laying  hens too in dependent of year period, more in the summer. Housing of the hens was equipped with the perch. The laying hens  regularly used a perch. A beginning of  occupation the perch was at the time of time growing dark,at the end of the  light day. A nesting material was selected regular , Monthly exchange. It was meadow  hay of excellent quality for  the collection of high quality and safe eggs from nests in the hen house. The laying  hens had unlimited access to  feed and water. The commercial feed mixture was available ad libitum and fresh kitchen remnants were added in a small amount , provided  that they fed in the short term, so  that not subject to harmful degradation process. The management of our  experiment was scheduled at age of laying hens 30 to 90 weeks. The egg  laying intensity was observed 50% in a moment  of the experimental 1st week (age of laying  hens 30 weeks). High egg  laying intensity of laying  hens was at their age between 39 to 63 weeks. At the end of the experiment, at age of laying  hens 90 weeks was decreased egg laying intensity at 26.19%, which represents almost half of egg  laying  intensity recorded at the beginning of the experiment. An indicator of  egg  production in the our experiment was studied under defined conditions for small-scale breeding, i.e. in alternative production system with free  range, under defined conditions of nutrition and timing of investigation more than one year, from the end of October to the end of December of the following year. The results of our experiment can be related to the  season, months of the year. The laying  hens laid the eggs by individual weeks 33 - 90 weeks of age about average weight  from 57.5 to 75.0 g. The fat content of an egg  mass was 11.3 g.100-1 and  protein 12.39.g.100-1.The table  eggs from conditions of small - scale breeding  are an important source of foodstuffs  for the population, especially in rural areas. It must be given to this source of table eggs for human nutrition the highest quality and health safety too</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.potravinarstvo.com/journal1/index.php/potravinarstvo/article/view/514/pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Potravinárstvo</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1337-0960</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.9/n.1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>