<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="SK2016017790">
    <dc:title xml:lang="sk">Mikrobiologická kvalita cukrárenských výrobkov počas technologického procesu výroby</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>The microbiological quality of confectionery products during the technological processess of production</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Kačániová Miroslava</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Juhaniaková,  Ľubomíra</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Petrová Jana</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Slovak University of Agriculture, Nitra, Slovak Republic</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:publisher>
      <ags:publisherPlace>Nitra</ags:publisherPlace>
    </dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">Q01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">Q03</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">microbial contamination</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">technology</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en" />
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_37547</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7644</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The issue of the safety and wholesomeness of food plays a special role in the priorities of production control ling and food handling. Quality question and wholesomeness of food, together with regard to environmental protection are becoming increasingly of interest not only to experts from various professions and disciplines, but also the general public. The aim of our study was to evaluate the microbiological quality confectionery products during the technological process of production. For microbiological parameters were followed in particular the representation of total count microorganisms, mesophilic anaerobic sporulating microorganisms, coliform bacteria, yeast and microscopic filamentous fungi in samples of raw materials used in the manufacture of confectionery products. In addition to these groups ofmicroorganisms we monitored the presence of pathogenic microorganisms such as Salmonella sp. and Staphylococcus aureus in cream s and finished products. Except of microbiological parameters in product samples we followed the value of water activity aw. Relationships between microorganisms and water activity, not least were developed HACCP analysis of individua! confectionery products. In terms of the techno logical process, we have focused on the monitoring of microorganisms in the products of durability filling - perishable having consumed within 24 hours. For objectivity products we watched the differences between products that were prepare in various production facilities. Products are assessed according to the limit values of the number of microorganisms contained in the Codex Alimentary of the Slovak Republic. For microbio!ogical analysis of confectionery products, we take adequate samples of intermediate and finished products are carried out according to current health regulations. Selected confectionery products of samples were made collection s in home production of doctoral student, in a training classroom school kitchen and private production center of confectionery, and on the production of raw materials were used in retail stores network. The ob served species own confectioneries were: egg yolk-filled garIand butter cream, French cubes and punch lumps. For microbiological analysis were collected 10 samples of raw material s sugar, 10 samples of flavor, 10 samples of butter and 10 samples of eggs. Below were taken for microbiological examination samples of creams: 10 yolk samples of butter from cream- filled disposable bag, 5 samples of cream-filled multiple use of paid bag, 5 samples of cream-filled newly purchased paid bag, 5 samples of corpora egg garIand and 5 samples of the French cubes. Of the finished confectionery products were examined 45 samples of the punch lumps, 45 egg wreath samples and 45 samples French cubes. Total 205 samples were analyzed. For microorganisms cultivation of culture media were used for the capture different groups of microorganisms: VRBL agar for the isolation of CFU Escherichia coli and coliforrn bacteria, DRBC and DG 18 for microscopic fungi and yeasts, plate count agar for total count of microorganisms, meat peptone agar for mesophilic anaerobic sporulating bacteria. Comparing the microbiological quality of raw material s to the 
requirements of the Codex Alimentary SR (2009), we found that all the analyzed samples satisfy with the requirements imposed on the type of raw material. The average of total number of microorganisms in samples of eggs was 2.17 log CFUg-1, the average number of mesophilic anaerobic sporeforming microorganisms was 1.85 and 0.23 of microscopic filamentous fungi in log CFUg-1. In samples of creams and corpus was an increased occurrence of yeast, coliforrn bacteria, cells of Salmonella sp. and Staphylococcus aureus. The overall assessment of the microbiological quality of the punch lumps, we found that two samples from school factory and one sample from private producer did not meet with CA SR (2009) of the total number of microorganisms. Comparing the microbiological quality of egg wreath with CA SR (2009), we found that one sample of 
home production did not meet the threshold for this type of product. Comparing the results of the samples with French cubes CA SR (2009), we found that all the samples satisfy those requirements. Comparing the number of microscopic fungi PK SR (2009), we found that the two samples did not meet the requirements. The overall assessment of water activity of punch lumps we found that the water activity ranged from 0,849 in 
samples from the home production to 0.856 in samples from the school production. When watching the water activity of egg garI and was found that the water activity ranged from 0,841 in egg garland made in the school and the values obtained were within 0,921 for egg garland made in home production. When watching the water activity of the French cubes we noticed that water activity ranged from 0,840 of French cubes produced in the private manufacturing to 0,847 in school production.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN">978-80-552-1300-2</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Book</dc:type>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>