<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="SK2016017204">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Forest visualization as a tool for decision support and forestry education</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="sk">
      <dcterms:alternative>Vizualizácia lesa ako nástroj pre podporu rozhodovania a lesnícke  vzdelávanie</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Valent Peter</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Technical University in Zvolen, T.G. Masaryka 24, 960 53 Zvolen, Slovak Republic,  email:  peter.valent@tuzvo.sk</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Growth</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">forests</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Simulation models</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3394</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3062</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_24242</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Outputs from forest growth models are often very complexive. Their visualization is necessary for better understanding of relations between the modeled variables. The introduction of this paper deals with software and hardware tools for creation of visualization outputs from growth simulators. Visualization via virtual reality gets highest priority. Virtual reality is also present in growth simulator SIBYLA, where it allows not only displaying of virtual forest stand, but offers the possibility to do any thinning concept in such virtual environment. Virtual forest produced by growth simulator SIBYLA can be displayed in sophisticated visualizaton tool – system CAVE built at TU in Zvolen. Data connection between growth simulator and CAVE system is not established yet, so we are unable to launch growth prognosis automatically after user ́s interventions to forest stand. Objectives of the work aim on programming development of software solution, which will provide connection between CAVE system and growth simulator SIBYLA. Another task is to develop application capable of displaying important information about stand on simulation plot. Methods contains approaches to create necessary software solutions resulting from goals of the paper. Connecting CAVE system with growth simulator SIBYLA, the worldwide unique tool - thinning trainer, will be established. This tool will be significant contribution for science, education and Public Relations via popularization of forestry science.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.tuzvo.sk/files/3_3/Acta_Facultatis_Forestalis/aff_suppll_56_1_2014.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">sk</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Acta  Facultatis Forestalis Zvolen</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">0231-5785</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.56/n.Suppl. 1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>