<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="SK2016017768">
    <dc:title xml:lang="sk">Genetické hodnotenie parkúrových koní v Slovenskej republike</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>Genetic evaluation of showjumping horses in Slovak Republic</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Schubertová Zuzana</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Candrák, Juraj</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Slovak University of Agriculture, Nitra, Slovak Republic</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:publisher>
      <ags:publisherPlace>Nitra</ags:publisherPlace>
    </dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">horses</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">genetics</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">breeding value</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3668</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3222</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_16117</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The aim of this study was to estimate the breeding value s (BV) and basic genetic parameters within sport horses population in Slovak republic. The simulated genomic information was used for breeding values estimation in chosen group of warmblood horses 
as well. The data from showjumping competitions performed in 2004 - 2013 (Slovak Equestrian Federation) and data from Breeding information register (The National Stud Farm in Topoľčianky) were used in our work. There were 831 horses included in the analysis. The profit of converted penalty points (epp), profit of penalty points (PP) and ranking in the competition (R) were analyzed as the measures describing horse performance. The software package Cf'C 1.0 was used for computation of inbreeding coefficient (F) in given population. Input data (profit of epp, PP and R) were not normally distributed, therefore the transformation by Blom formula was made. Two ways of such transformation were used, the height of obstacles was taken into account in the second way of transformation. The influence of different effects on evaluated parameters was assessed by using the linear models. Various linear models were used, simulated genomic data in the form of SNP effect and genomic value were taken into account as well. The simulated genomic data had significant effect on given parameters. The heritability coefficient was 0.18 in epp, 0.17 in PP and 0.10 in R. The genetic correlations ranged from 0.81 to 0.97. 
The BV were estimated for epp, pp and R. In the case of epp, breeding values were estimated using genomic value. The using of simulated genomic value has led to the higher reliability of BV. The order of animals according to their BV with using of genomic data 
were differend as the order without this information. The BV for epp, R and epp (genomic data) were modified to the form of relative breeding values. The increase of genetic level of epp and R within population of showjumping horses has been observed in recent years.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN">978-80-552-1283-0</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Book</dc:type>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>