<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="SK2016017038">
    <dc:title xml:lang="sk">Vyhodnotenie bilancie živín a výkonnosti v integrovanom a lowinput systéme</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>Nutrient balance and crop productivity in integrated and lowinput system</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Žák Štefan</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Hrčková Katarína</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Slovak University of Agriculture, Nitra, Slovak Republic</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F08</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">plant production</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">trace elements</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5976</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7834</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Field experiment was established in 1999-2005. It was focused on comparison of low system and integrated system from the point of view of nutrient balance and crop productivity. In both systems, two levels of nitrogen fertilization were applied. Crop rotation was the same and it involved following crops: pea, winter wheat, maize and spring barley. Low input system was significantly more productive in conditions of intensive nitrogen fertilization. Higher nitrogen dose increased the productivity of all field crops. Response was intensive in case of spring barley and maize (5.5% and 5.3 % respectively). Reaction of pea and winter wheat was not so strong. The general balance of phosphorus, potassium and calcium in low input system was positive and the balance of nitrogen and magnesium was negative. Nutrient balance in integrated system was completely positive. In general, higher nitrogen dose caused a deficit in potassium and calcium balance. Phosphorus balance was not affected by nitrogen inputs. Balance of macronutrients (N, P and K) was positive in case of pea, but deficit of macronutrients (Mg and Ca) appeared. Maize was fertilized by organic fertilisers, so no deficit was recorded. In contrary, winter wheat nutrient balance was completely negative. Uptake of nitrogen by spring barley was higher than its input into both systems.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Agrochémia</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1335-2415</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.19 (55)/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>