<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="SK2016017521">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Effect of chromium nicotinate on oxidative stability, chemical composition and meat quality of growing-finishing pigs</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Bučko Ondrej</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Lehotayová Andrea</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Haščík Peter</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>BAHELKA I.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Gábor Michal</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Bobko Marek</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Debrecéni Ondrej</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Trembecká Lenka</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Slovak University of Agriculture, Nitra, Slovak Republic</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L51</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Swine</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Meat quality</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Additives</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7555</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_12459</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_118</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The effect of different organic sources of Cr on growth, feed efficiency and carcass value is known but there is a lack of information between chromium nicotinate (CrNic) and pork quality. Therefore, purpose of this research was to investigate the effects of CrNic on chemical composition, quality and oxidative stability of pork meat. In the study, pigs of Large White breed (40 pcs) were used. The pigs were divided into two groups, namely the control and the experimental of 20 pcs with equal number of barrows and gilts. The pigs were fed the same diet which consisted of three feed mixtures applied at the different growth phases, from 30 - 45 kg OS-03, 45 - 70 kg OS-04 and 70 - 100 kg OS-05. The pigs were allowed ad libitum access to feed and water. The diet of experimental group was supplemented with 0.75 mg.kg-1 CrNic in the form of chromium-inactivated yeast Saccharomyces cerevisiae. The fattening period in pigs lasted from 30 to 100 kg. The chromium supplementation led to a significantly higher content of chromium in longissimus thoracis muscle (LT) of experimental pigs. In addition, the results showed a statistically significant difference (p ≤0.05) in retention of chromium in the LT, monounsaturated and omega-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids content in experimental group compared with control. Moreover, there was highly significant (p £0.05) difference in essential fatty acids, as well as in oxidative stability in 7 days, among the groups. The highly significant differences were also observed among sexes, namely in total water, protein and intramuscular fat contents, colour CIE b* in both times, and oxidative stability. However, physical-technological parameters (pH, drip loss, shear force and meat colour) were not affected when pigs were fed the supplement. On the whole, the positive effect of chromium nicotinate in most of investigated parameters may be beneficial not only for pork industry but also for consumers.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.potravinarstvo.com/journal1/index.php/potravinarstvo/article/view/521/pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Potravinárstvo</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1337-0960</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.9/n.1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>