<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="SK2016013923">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Control of Cronobacter in reconstituded infant formula by combined application of cathelicidin LL-37 and bacteriophages</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Kajsík,  M.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Krahulec, J.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Tóth, C.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Drahovská, H.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Stuchlík, S.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Turňa, J.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Faculty of Natural Sciences, Comenius University, Mlynska dolina 1, 842 15 Bratislava, Slovakia. E-mail: drahovska@fns.uniba.sk</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">Q01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">BACTERIOPHAGES</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">weaning foods</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_769</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_32726</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Cronobacter spp. is responsible for rare but fatal cases of infections in neonates and immunocompromised infants. The reconstituded powdered infant formula (PIF) is one of main sources of newborn infections. The aim of our study was to assess application of recombinant human cathelicidin LL-37, an antimicrobial peptide, alone and in combination with bacteriophages against Cronobacter in PIF. The minimal inhibitory concentration (MIC) of LL-37 determined by radial diffusion method for ten representative Cronobacter strains ranged from 2.56 µg•ml-1 to 8.83 µg•ml-1, and the values were below MIC of E. coli standard strain. By testing the antimicrobial activity in liquid growth medium, substantial inhibition of strains was observed at 30 µg•ml-1 LL-37, whereas 20 µg•ml-1 showed only moderate effect. However, higher peptide concentrations were necessary to inhibit Cronobacter in reconstituted PIF. By using 50 µg•ml-1 and 100 µg•ml-1 LL-37, numbers of cells decreased after 4-hour cultivation by approx. 70% and 96%, respectively. Finally, simultaneous application of LL-37 and bacteriophage Dev-CS-701 resulted in synergistic effect, as a 1 300-fold reduction of cell numbers in PIF was observed. Application of the two antimicrobial agents thus facilitated their reduced dosing and decreased the probability of generation of phage-resistant cells.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vup.sk/index.php?mainID=2&amp;navID=14</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>JOURNAL OF FOOD AND NUTRITION RESEARCH</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">ISSN 1336-8672</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.54/n.2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>