<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="SK2016007943">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Effect of different drying methods on drying characteristics, colour and microstructure properties of mushroom</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Izli, N.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Isik, E.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Department of Biosystems Engineering, Faculty of Agriculture, University of Uludag, Gorukle Campus, 16059, Bursa, Turkey. E-mail: nazmiizli@gmail.com</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">Q01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">microwave treatment</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">edible fungi</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">colour</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_28461</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2487</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1773</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">In this study, the effects of microwave, convective and microwave-convective drying treatments on the drying para¬meters, colour and microstructure properties of mushroom samples were investigated. To select the best thin-layer drying models for the drying treatments, 9 mathematical models were fitted to the experimental data. Based on evaluation by statistical tests, the Midilli et al. model, the Diffusion Approach model, Logarithmic model, and Wang and Singh model were found to be the best-fitting models to describe the drying behaviour of the mushroom samples. The shortest drying time was provided with microwave method at 500 W (35 min). However, the drying time was significantly reduced by combining microwave treatment with conventional drying. The drying time at microwave-convective power combination level of 90 W – 50 C was by 33.8% shorter than drying by only microwave at a power of 90 W, and by 52.9% shorter than the drying by only convective treatment at a temperature of 50 C. The colour values of the samples dried at 50 C were closest to the fresh samples for all drying conditions. Scanning electron microscopy images revealed that a higher temperature or microwave power caused greater damage to the microstructure of the mushroom samples.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vup.sk/index.php?mainID=2&amp;navID=14</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>JOURNAL OF FOOD AND NUTRITION RESEARCH</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">ISSN 1336-8672</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.53/n.2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>