<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="SK2016017339">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Content of total polyphenols and antioxidant activity in selected varieties of onion (Allium cepa L.)</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Kavalcová Petra</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Bystrická Judita</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Trebichalský, Pavol</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Kopernická, Miriama</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Hrstková,  Miroslava</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Lenková Marianna</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Slovak University of Agriculture, Nitra, Slovak Republic</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F61</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">onions</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Polyphenols</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">antioxidants</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_12934</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_15881</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_511</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Onion (Allium cepa L.) is one of the most important vegetable crops widely consumed in the world. The bulb onion is grown as fresh shoots and as bulbs for consuming uncooked, cooked, and pickled or production of seed and sets. They can be eaten raw, boiled, steamed and roasted. Onion has high nutritional value. Onions are a good source of vitamins, minerals and major component like polyphenols, ﬂavonoids, fructooligosaccharides, thiosulﬁnates and other sulfur compounds. Polyphenols belong to significant antioxidants in human diet. Antioxidant compounds (polyphenols, flavonoids) scavenge free radicals, inhibit the oxidative mechanisms that lead to degenerative diseases. Antioxidant compounds in food play an important role as a health protecting factor. Onions have a wide range of beneficial properties for human health, such as anti-cholesterolaemic, anti-mutagenic and antioxidant capacity. In this work we evaluated content of total polyphenols and antioxidant activity in selected varieties of onion. Samples of plant material we collected at the stage of full maturity in the locality of Pružina. Pružina is locality without negative influences and emission sources. Total polyphenols content and antioxidant activity were measured in six varieties of onion, namely in red variety (Red matté), in yellow varieties (Boston, Bingo, Sherpa) and white varieties of onion (Diamond, White dry). The content of the total polyphenols was determined by using the Folin-Ciocalteu reagent (FCR).  Antioxidant activity was measured by using a compound DPPH˙. In the present experiment it was detected, that total polyphenols content in samples ranges from 142.01 mg.kg GAE (white variety of onion- White dry) to 1083.04 mg.kg GAE (red variety of onion- Red matté). Statistically significant highest value of total polyphenols (1083.04 mg.kg  GAE) was recorded in variety Red matté. Another indicator that has been evaluated and compared was the antioxidant activity. The values of antioxidant activity were in interval from 7.74% to 41.67%. Based on the measured values of antioxidant activity in onion the samples can beclassified as follows: Red matté (41.67%) &gt; Boston (25.77%) &gt; Sherpa (24.34%) &gt; Bingo (19.54%) &gt; White dry (8.10%) &gt; Diamond (7.74%).</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.potravinarstvo.com/journal1/index.php/potravinarstvo/article/view/524/pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Potravinárstvo</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1337-0960</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.9/n.1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>