<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="SK2016016921">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">The evaluations of hydrophysical properties of snow cover in area of Chopok  (The Low Tatras Mts.)</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="sk">
      <dcterms:alternative>Zhodnotenie hydrofyzikálnych vlastností snehovej pokrývky v oblasti Chopku za vybrané obdobie</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Hanzelová Miriam</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Hríbik Matúš</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Technical University in Zvolen, T.G. Masaryka 24, 960 53 Zvolen, Slovak Republic, email: mirowka@gmail.com</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2013-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">snow cover</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">snow</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Properties</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7125</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7124</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_49874</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The snow cover is important part of our landscape which affects hydrological regime of rivers. In net of meteorological stations of SHMU are measured basal snow characteristics as are the snow depth and the snow water equivalent. The problem is that the location of these stations is in low altitude but snow cover is produced mostly in mountain areas. Therefore we focus in our work on field measurements of mentioned properties. Once a month during the last four winter seasons we measured on altitude transect (from 1000 m a. s. l. to 2000 m a. s. l.) in the Low Tatras snow depth and snow water equivalent. Subsequently we researched the impact of altitude, forest and time on snow cover, We can summarize our results to following points:
o Snow depth and snow water equivalent increase to the altitude 1500 – 1800 m a. s. l. but in upper localities these characteristics decrease due to the snow drift.
O Values of the snow depth and the snow water equivalence are higher in the open space in comparison with the forest area.
o The maximum values of properties of snow were recorded from December to January in lower localities of studied area and in upper localities occurs the time shift of maximum values as we measured it there from February to March.
O At the beginning of winter season is the snow cover similar in all studied localities of the altitudinal transect.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.tuzvo.sk/files/3_3/katedry_lf/kltm/suppl._55-1-2013_web.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">sk</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Acta  Facultatis Forestalis Zvolen</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">0231-5785</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.55/n.Suppl. 1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>