<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="SK2016017313">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Siltation of water reservoir Hnusno II. and erosion potential of catchment</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="sk">
      <dcterms:alternative>Zanášanie vodnej nádrže Hnusno II. a erózny potenciál povodia</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Danko Michal</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Juško Vladimír</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Technical University in Zvolen, T.G. Masaryka 24, 960 53 Zvolen, Slovak Republic,  email:  jusko@tuzvo.sk</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">water reservoirs</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">sedimentation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">erosion</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">watersheds</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8324</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6926</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2651</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8334</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The paper solves problems of siltation of small water reservoir in the particular example of the water reservoir Hnusno II. Monitored basin is located in the cadastre of village Horná Lehota, Brezno District, on the south side of the Low Tatras. Within the field measurements was carried out detection condition of sedimentation monitored reservoir. Sedimentation was examined by sonar method from the vessel in full operation level. The measurement was performed in advance transverse profile, which we obtain from the original construction project of the basin. As a second comparative method we used direct measurement of the probe rod, which should confirm the accuracy of the measurement of sonar. Another objective was to determine the potential treat of catchment of water reservoir Hnusno II. by water erosion. To calculate the potential loss of soil from the catchment area were used Wischmeier – Smith equation USLE. Based on positive results was calculated average annual speed of reservoir siltation 520 m3.rok–1, that it represents annual loss 0.95% from storage capacity. Under period for last cleaning of reservoir (24 years) is decreased a storage capacity of reservoir about 23%. Measurement deviations of reservoir siltation by method of sonar and method of probe slat are not statistic significant. It makes possible a simplify of measurement with saving of time and degrease of laboriousness. Based on specify of potential loss of soil by water erosion in interest area and sediment amount in reservoir is result, that from the catchment is 24%, from the surface of forest roads is 31% and from washtubs of watercourses is probably 45% from total amounts of connate sediment in reservoir.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.tuzvo.sk/files/3_3/Acta_Facultatis_Forestalis/aff_suppll_56_1_2014.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">sk</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Acta  Facultatis Forestalis Zvolen</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">0231-5785</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.56/n.Suppl. 1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>