<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="SK2016017026">
    <dc:title xml:lang="sk">Vplyv dusikato-sirnei výživy a inhibitorov nitrifikáci na úrodu a kvalitu nažiek slnečnice ročnej (Helianhtus annus, L.)</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>Effect of nitrogen-sulphur nutrition and inhibitors of nitrification on the yield and quality of sunflower seed</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Slamka Pavol</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Ložek Otto</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Slovak University of Agriculture, Nitra, Slovak Republic</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F04</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Helianthus annuus</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">nutrients</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">nutrition</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Nitrogen</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3539</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5274</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_49892</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5192</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Effect of split application of nitrogen and nitrogen+sulphur nutrition in comparison with one shot application of nitrogen + sulphur + inhibitors of nitrification (dikyandiamid, DeD and 1, 2, 4 triazol, TZ) on the yield and quality of sunflower seed was examined in two-year small-plot experiment with sunflower (odroda "Alexandra") on heavy chernozem soi/. On the average of two experimental years one-shot application of nitrogen-sulphur nutrition in the form of ENSIN ferti!izer containing nitrification inhibitors applied before sunflower seeding at the rate of 100 kq.ha N and 50 kg.ha S showed the most considerable effect on all investigated parameters. On the average of two experimental years application of ENSIN fertilizer increased yield of sunflower seed by 0.98 t.ha, that is by 26.2%, at KNE = 9.8 and increment of yield achieving 330.8 EUR· ha. In addition fertlizer ENSIN also increased content of fat in sunflower seed by 1.25%, while DASA fertilizer by 1. 1 % and LAD fertilizer only by 0.35% in comparison to unfertilized control treatment on the average of three experimental years. During the whole growing season of sunflower cleariy higher contents of ammonium nitrogen against nitrate nitrogen were found in soil after application of ENSIN fertilizer and oppositely slightly higher contents of nitrate N against ammonium one were determined in soil after application LAD and OA SA fertilizers, respectively Heavy soil and course of weather supported reduction processes in soil and speed down oxidative processes In soil what contributed to more expressive effect of nitrification inhibitors in ENSIN fertilizer in comparison to DASA and LAD fertilizers.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Agrochémia</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1335-2415</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.19 (55)/n.3</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>