<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="SK2016016918">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Weathering of the skeleton as a process affecting material and energy flows  and the soil properties</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="sk">
      <dcterms:alternative>Zvetrávanie skeletu ako proces ovplyvňujúci látkovo-energetické toky a stav pôdy</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Jurášová Emília</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Technical University in Zvolen, T.G. Masaryka 24, 960 53 Zvolen, Slovak Republic,  email: emilia.jurasova@gmail.com</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2013-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">soil properties</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">cations</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">mineralogical soil types</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Cation exchange capacity</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_330883</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_16169</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4855</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_24981</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">This topic presents current knowledge about the role of soil skeleton in the context of intrasoil weathering. It is assumed that smaller fractions of the soil skeleton play an active role in plant nutrition. The selected physical (especially bulk density, specific density and porosity) and chemical (pH and cation  exchange capacity) properties of the soil skeleton were analyzed in the thesis. Measured data was compared with data measured in fine-earth fractions.We focused on the analysis of changes in physical and chemical properties of mineral fractions depending on preferential flow of water in the soil profile and as well as size of fine-earth and skeleton fractions. Particle size distribution analysis confirmed statistically significant effects of the preferential flow on the soil texture. The results of the pH mineral fractions measuring documented a correlation between these values and granulometry of size  fractions, whereupon the pH can be regarded as an indicator of the degree of their alteration. The results of the cation exchange capacity (CEC) measurements of the skeleton pointed out 
that the values had moved in the  analogous intervals as exist in fine earth. The analysis of cation  exchange capacity (CEC) by particular grain-size fractions of mineral constituents of soil showed the important role of
soil skeleton regarding the overall CEC value of soil. Through analysis of soil thin section and X-ray analysis of fine earth as well as soil skeleton, we gained important information material on the mineralogical composition of soils, pedogenetical specific processes taking place in the soils and connections between this geochemical data and the soil sorption complex.The geochemical study of both the fine-earth and the soil skeleton by XRF evealed the mobilization and translocation of aluminium, iron and silicon to be evident as within the fine-earth as well as the soil skeleton fractions. On this account we predict the soil mineral constituents in total (regardless of its grain-size classes) to be active during pedogenetic processes.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.tuzvo.sk/files/3_3/katedry_lf/kltm/suppl._55-1-2013_web.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">sk</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Acta  Facultatis Forestalis Zvolen</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">0231-5785</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.55/n.Suppl. 1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>