<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="SK2016012116">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Potential probiotic properties of Lactobacilli isolated from goat´s milk</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Tomáška Martin</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Drončovský Maroš</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Klapáčová Lýdia</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Slottová Anna</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Kološta  Miroslav</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Slovak Agricultural University in Nitra, Nitra, Slovak republic</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">Q04</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Goat milk</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Probiotics</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Lactobacillus</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_16083</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_32692</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4144</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The three strains of lactobacilli isolated from goat's milk - Lactobacillus (Lbc.) casei 21L10, Lbc. johnsonii KB2-1 and Lbc. plantarum 25/1L were selected in previous studies because they showed good processing and protective properties in production of cheeses or lactic acid beverages from heat-treated milk or in model conditions. The aim of this study was to evaluate their potential probiotic properties: resistance to lysozyme, survival in gastrointestinal tract, and hydrophobicity. Testing was carried out in vitro methods: comparison of growth and metabolic characteristics of the strains when cultivated in Man, Rogosa and Sharpe medium with and without the addition of lysozyme (400 mg.mL-1)</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">viability of strains after incubation in simulated environment of gastric juice (pH = 2.0, pepsin) and subsequently in simulated small intestinal juice (pH = 8.0, pancreatin, bile salts) and an ability to adhere to the non-polar solvent in the two-phase system: xylene-water. Lbc. casei 21L10 and Lbc. johnsonii KB2-1 were resistant to the effect of lysozyme, the strain Lbc. plantarum 25/1L was moderately susceptible. To the action of simulated gastric juice was resistant only the Lbc. johnsonii KB2-1, that was subsequently inhibited in simulated small intestinal juice. When using xylene as a model agent, all strains were not hydrophobic. From all the tested strains, Lbc. johnsonii KB2-1 showed good potential probiotic properties, particularly in relation to resistance to lysozyme and the simulated environment of gastric juice.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.potravinarstvo.com/journal1/index.php/potravinarstvo/article/view/434/pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Potravinárstvo</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1337-0960</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.9/n.1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>