<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="SK2016011121">
    <dc:title xml:lang="sk">Úroda a kvalita zrna pšenice letnej formy ozimnej</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>Yield and grain quality of winter wheat</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Candráková Eva</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Kašša Branislav</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Slovak University of Agriculture, Nitra, Slovak Republic</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F04</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Wheats</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Quality</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Yields</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8373</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6400</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8488</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The pilot-scale experiment with the cultivation of winter wheat was based on agricultural cooperative in Šenkvice, district Pezinok in the years 2011/2012 and 2012/2013. The experimental site is situated at an altitude of 190 m with an average annual temperature of 10.2 DC and annual rainfall of 550- 600 mm. Variety Alaeris was sown on medium heavy soil. Four variants of nitrogen fertilization were examined: K-control, A - dose 135 kg.ha, B - 108 kg.ha, C - 85 kg.ha. Three doses of the fertilizer LAD were used (restorative, productive and qualitative) in ratio 40: 40: 20. Grain yield and its quality, natural production and economic indicators were evaluated. Grain yield of wheat was statistically high significantly influenced by nitrogen dose and conditions of growing season. The highest grain yield of wheat has been achieved after application of 135 kg of nitrogen per hectare with the highest economic efficiency and profit. Natural efficiency reached 23.52 kilograms of grain per 1 kg of applied nitrogen. The lowest grain yield of winter wheat, as well as economic indicators were after applying nitrogen at a dose of 85 kg.ha, Higher doses of nitrogen positively influenced wet gluten content. The average values for both years were in interval from 29.2% (var. C) to 34.4% (var. A). At unfertilized variant, the gluten content was only 24.5%. Grain volume weight, falling number, and Zelenyho test met requirements for food processing use of wheat grain. The results showed that adequate nitrogen nutrition helps to winter wheat stands to overcome the less favorable weather conditions and it appears as a stabilizing factor of the harvest. winter wheat, fertilization, yield, crude protein, gluten.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Agrochémia</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1335-2415</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.19/n.1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>