<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="SK2016017021">
    <dc:title xml:lang="sk">Bilancia dusíka v integrovanom a ekologickom systéme hospodárenia na pôde</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>Balance of nitrogen in integrated and ecological farming system on soil</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Ložek Otto</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Hanáčková Eva</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Slovak University of Agriculture, Nitra, Slovak Republic</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F04</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Fertilization</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Nitrogen</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">farming systems</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2863</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5192</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2807</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Balance of nitrogen was evaluated in six-field crop rotation organized in both integrated (IS) and ecological (ES) farming system within small-pot field experiment in years 2010/2011 - 2012/2013. There were examined two treatments of ferlilization: unfertilized (O) and fertilized (OR).  Crop rotation consisted of the following crops: maize for silage - winter wheat - spring barley - common pea - bean + alfaIfa - alfalfa. The highest deficit of nitrogen(recalculated for one crop on the average of three experimental years) was found in control unfertilized treatment in integrated system (-86.32 kg·ha.yr). In ecological system deficit of nitrogen in unfertilized treatment (-79.46 kq. ha.yr) was lower in comparison with integrated system due to higher air nitrogen fixation by leguminous plants by 33.2 kg.ha.yr and also higher uptake of nitrogen by grow crops particularly by those of Fabaceae family. Deficit of nitrogen in fertilized treatment of integrated farming system represented -6.31 kg·ha.yr and percentage of nitrogen outputs substitution from nitrogen inputs achieved 96.9%. In ecological system deficit of nitrogen in fertilized treatments achieved -53.46 kg·ha.yr on the average of three years and was caused mainly by the absence of mineral fertilization. In comparison to deficit of nitrogen in integrated system at the same treatments, deficit of nitrogen in integrated system was higher by 47.15 kg·ha·yr. Percentage of nitrogen outputs substitution from nitrogen inputs achieved 74.8 % in ecological system of farming. 
balance of nitrogen, crop rotation, integrated farming system, ecological farming system, fertilizers, uptake of nitrogen</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Agrochémia</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1335-2415</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.19 (55)/n.3</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>