<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="SK2016017028">
    <dc:title xml:lang="sk">Vzt&amp;#039;ah množstva a kvality pôdnej organickei hmoty a vybraných parametrov pôdnej štruktúry</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>The relation of quantity and quality of the soil organic matter and selected parameters of the soil structure</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Tobiašová Erika</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Špaňo,  Miroslav</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Slovak University of Agriculture, Nitra, Slovak Republic</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">P30</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">P35</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">soil structure</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Fertility</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">organic matter</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7196</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2862</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5387</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Soil organic matter (SOM) is a key element in the formation of soil structure and on the other hand, the soil aggregates participate in a various way on the stabilization of organic substances, and this system is in the constant dynamics. In this study, the relation between the soil structure and quantity and quality of SOM through the selected parameters of soil structure in a response to differences in the SOM were studied. The experiment included four soil types (Eutric Fluvisol, Haplic Chernozem, Haplic Luvisol, Eutric Regosol) in four ecosystems (forest, meadow, urban, and agro-ecosystem). For the comparison of differences in the condition of soil structure in the soil types, the aggregate stability index (ASI) seems the most suitable parameter, while in the case of ecosystems, the vulnerability coefficient of soil structure (K) is more suitable parameter. With respect to the SOM, the ASI and also stability coefficient (Kw) seem sensible parameters, but the ASI is more sensitive, because responds not only on the differ-ences between the ecosystems (particularly in relation to carbon), but also on differences between the fields on the arable land (particularly in relation to nitrogen), and it is not only in relation to the quantity, but also quality of organic matter (Iabile forms, fractions of humus substances). The relation of SOM and soil structure is markedly influenced by the particle size distribution, therefore the parameters for evaluation of the soil structure, which include the parti-cIe size distribution are better indicators for the evaluation of this relationship.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Agrochémia</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1335-2415</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.19 (55)/n.3</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>