<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016310696">
    <dc:title xml:lang=" ">Balanced scorecard system is the instrument of management  strategy implemetation in the development of beet sugar subcomplex</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Svyatova O.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Soloshienko I.G.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Dorogavtseva I.G.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">E21</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang=" ">The investigation has shown that it is necessary to expand the traditional point system to have a comprehensive idea of results rating and the improvement of efficiency of beet sugar subcomplex. As a result there has been proposed a balanced system of its strategic suitability towards the synergy. We have presented this system as the projection of seven constitutive elements in terms of seven groups of the strategic objections: finance, investments</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">marketing, purchasers</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">endogenous processes</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">technologies, innovations, information</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">logistics, logistics infrastructure</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">training, the staff</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">governmental regulation. This scorecard characterizes the subsets partners’ interests and consumer needs. It enables to improve the endogenous processes in terms of the balance between the goals and actions due to synergy, collaboration and coordination of sub-complex business units’ activities. The practicability of results’ using of balanced scorecard system is substantiated in the article as the indicators of effective functioning of beet sugar subcomplex of A.I.C. It contributes to build up close links between subsets of subcomplex, to increase the competitiveness, to develop the strategic opportunities, to get the synergy effect of beet sugar cluster formation. Balanced scorecard system can be used in the economic analysis of subcomplex functioning. It can be also used to substantiate the federal and regional programs of the development of beet sugar subcomplex for the purpose to the support the food supply security in the country, particularly, to meet public and food industry enterprises’ requirements with the Russian beet-root sugar.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Экономика и предпринимательство</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1999-2300</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.9/n.8-2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>