<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016300109">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Legally Prohibited Target-Marketing Aimed at Children and Adolescents</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Heinrich Stefan</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2013-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">E14</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang=" ">The company Philip Morris International ran the MAYBE advertisement campaign intermittently from 2011 to 2012, illegally advertising the Marlboro filter cigarette. The campaign made use of keywords and images aimed specifically at minors. The characteristics and attitudes attributed to smokers through the campaign makes the advertisements highly appealing to minors. This is remarkable as advertising tobacco products in a manner that aims at minors has been prohibited for a long time. The following essay examines the current state of regulation-enforcement according to the Temporary Tobacco Law (VTabakG). It also presents possible tools for sanctioning violations and describes how tobacco corporations time and again manage to evade legal penalties. The advertising effect of the MAYBE campaign is analyzed, and is identified as a legal violation. Finally, it will be discussed whether or not a total ban on tobacco advertising is appropriate in order to protect minors from the dangers of smoking.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.intereconom.com/ISR/2013-3-2.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">en</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Международные научные исследования</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2076-9563</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.5/n.3</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>