<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="ES2016104917">
    <dc:title xml:lang="es">TEST DE CONGELACIÓN DE SEMEN DE BURRO CRIOLLO (EQUUS ASINUS)</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>ANALYSIS OF FREEZE SEMEN OF CREOLE DONKEY (EQUUS ASINUS)</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Toscano-Torres Irma</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Olivo Ingrid</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Núñez  Rosa</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Cajero Marcos</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Val-Arreola Daniel</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Conejo  Jesús</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Facultad de Medicina Veterinaria y Zootecnia de la Universidad Michoacana de San Nicolás de Hidalgo</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Facultad de Medicina Veterinaria y Zootecnia de la Universidad Michoacana de San Nicolás de Hidalgo</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Facultad de Medicina Veterinaria y Zootecnia de la Universidad Michoacana de San Nicolás de Hidalgo</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Instituto de Investigaciones Agropecuarias y Forestales de la Universidad Michoacana de San Nicolás de Hidalgo</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Instituto de Investigaciones Agropecuarias y Forestales de la Universidad Michoacana de San Nicolás de Hidalgo</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Facultad de Medicina Veterinaria y Zootecnia de la Universidad Michoacana de San Nicolás de Hidalgo</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Spermatozoa</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Viability</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7287</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8210</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">In Mexico, there has been a significant decline in population asinine in recent years, it continues this way would put the species at risk of extinction over the medium term. Aim: freeze semen of creole donkey (Equus asinus) using two commercial extensor, for horses (Equipro ®) and bovine (Triladyl ®) with and without seminal plasma. We obtained 15 ejaculates from 3 creole donkey’s reproductive stage by artificial vagina method. The sperm fraction was evaluated macroscopically and microscopically. Each ejaculate was divided and frozen in the above extensor with or without removal of seminal plasma (centrifugation (CENT) and non-centrifuged (N/C), respectively). The percentages of progressive motility (PM), viability (V) and functional status of the sperm plasma membrane (trained (T) untrained (UT) and acrosome reaction (AR)) by chlortetracycline in two stages: post-dilution (PD) and post-thawing (PT) were determined. An analysis of one way variance was performed. Results, Equipro: PM/PD 76.3±7.4 and 73.0 ± 6.2</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="es">PM/PT 35.7 ± 10.7 and 31.3 ± 9.2</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">V/PD 76.1 ± 9.6 and 77.7 ± 8.0</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">V/PT 67.7 ± 9.1 and 65.0 ± 11.6 CENT and N/C respectively.  Triladyl: PM/PD 72.0 ± 10.7 and 73.3 ± 5.6</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">PM/PT 40.3 ± 9.9 and 37.3 ± 8.0</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">V/PD 79.1 ± 7.9 and 78.9 ± 7.1</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">V/PT 66.6 ± 10.6 and 66.5 ± 8.9 CENT and N/C respectively. Non significative values were obtained (P&gt;0.05) compared Equipro vs Triladyl. T, UT and AR no changed. Conclusions: Triladyl and Equipro are effective for freezing creole donkey semen and local germplasm pool could be made.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">En México, ha habido un descenso significativo de la población asnal en los últimos años, que de seguir así pondría a la especie en riesgo de desaparecer a mediano plazo. Una estrategia que apoya la conservación de las razas locales es la criopreservación de semen. Los estudios sobre congelación de semen de burro se basan principalmente en la especie equina, con diferentes modificaciones. El presente trabajo tiene como objetivo la congelación de semen de burro criollo (Equus asinus) utilizando dos diluyentes comerciales diseñados para equino (Equipro®) y bovino (Triladyl®) con y sin plasma seminal. Se obtuvieron 15 eyaculados provenientes de 3 burros criollos en etapa reproductiva mediante vagina artificial. La fracción espermática se evaluó macro y microscópicamente. Cada eyaculado se dividió y congeló en los diluyentes antes mencionados con y sin remoción de plasma seminal (centrifugado (CENT) y no centrifugado (S/C), respectivamente). Se determinaron los porcentajes de movilidad progresiva (MP), viabilidad (V) y estado funcional de la membrana plasmática del espermatozoide (capacitados (CA) no capacitados (NC) y con reacción acrosomal (RA)) mediante clortetraciclina en dos momentos: postdilución (PD) y postdescongelación (PC). Se realizó un análisis de varianza de una vía. Resultados, Equipro: MP/PD 76.3±7.4 y 73.0± 6.2</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">MP/PC 35.7±10.7 y 31.3±9.2</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">V/PD 76.1±9.6 y 77.7±8.0</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">V/PC 67.7±9.1 y 65.0±11.6 CENT y S/C respectivamente. Triladyl: MP/PD 72.0±10.7 y 73.3±5.6</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">MP/PC 40.3±9.9 y 37.3±8.0</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">V/PD 79.1±7.9 y 78.9±7.1</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">V/PC 66.6±10.6 y 66.5±8.9 CENT y S/C respectivamente. No se encontraron diferencias significativas (P˃0.05) entre diluyentes, ni con semen CENT y S/C. Los porcentajes de CA, NC y RA fueron similares entre los tratamientos. Sin embargo, si hubo una disminución de la MP en el semen postdescongelado en cada uno de los tratamientos. Se concluye que el Equipro y el Triladyl son eficaces para la congelación del semen de burro criollo y que puede prescindirse de la centrifugación sin afectar la sobrevivencia de los espermatozoides.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.uco.es/conbiand/aica/templatemo_110_lin_photo/articulos/2014/Trabajo070_AICA2014.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">es</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Actas Iberoamericanas de Conservación Animal</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2253-7325</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.4/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>