<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="ES2016104899">
    <dc:title xml:lang="es">OVINOS CRIOLLOS Y MESTIZOS EN EL LITORAL SUR PERUANO</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>CREOLE AND CROSSBRED SHEEP IN THE PERUVIAN SOUTHERN COAST</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Montesinos Iván</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Catachura Anselmo</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Larrañaga Jéssica</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Castro Juan</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Arnhold Emmanuel</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>McManus Concepta</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Fioravanti Maria Clorinda</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Sereno José</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad Federal de Goiás</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad Nacional Jorge Basadre Grohmann</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad Nacional Jorge Basadre Grohmann</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad Nacional Jorge Basadre Grohmann</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad Federal de Goiás</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidade de Brasília</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad Federal de Goiás</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Embrapa Cerrados</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">In Peru the sheep production is a traditional activity for little farmers, which represent 75% of rural population and frequently have creole flocks, that survived centuries to severe conditions, but actually are ignored by the investigation and public politics, not being recognized as breed, showing low productivity and suffering absorbent crosses with imported animals for increasing the performance. This study aimed to characterize the phenotype of creole and Hampshire Down crossbred ewes, in the rural municipality of Ite, region Tacna, southern coast of Peru, as subsidy for racial recognition and genetic improvement of the Peruvian Creole Ovine. In the year 2012 were evaluated ewes from two environments: Wetlands and little ranches. The first is a coastal ecosystem of native vegetation, used for semi-extensive grazing by small ruminant breeders. In the ranches, farmers have a system of stake, inside alfalfa fields, grama and crop residues. Were reported 16 phenotypic measures in 200 adult females (50 Creole - Wetlands, 54 Creole - Ranches, 18 Crossbreed - Wetlands and 78 Crossbreed - Ranches). Means and significant difference to 5% were calculated with the procedure easyanova, from statistical program R. The results indicated that crossbred ewes are heavier and bigger. Morphometrically exist some miscegenation between flocks, maybe for living in the same environment. It could be dangerous for conservation of the creole genetic resource. Appeared the possibility of industrial cross, utilizing the hybrid vigor and certain adaptation of crossbred animals, for semi-extensive conditions in the Ite’s Wetlands.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="es">En Perú la crianza de ovinos es una actividad tradicional para pequeños productores, los cuales representan 75% de la población rural y poseen frecuentemente rebaños criollos, que sobrevivieron siglos a condiciones severas, mas actualmente son ignorados por la investigación y políticas públicas, no siendo reconocidos como raza, mostrando baja productividad y sufriendo cruzas absorbentes con animales importados para incrementar su desempeño. Este estudio objetivó caracterizar el fenotipo de ovejas criollas y mestizas Hampshire Down, en el municipio rural de Ite, región Tacna, litoral sur del Perú, como subsidio para el reconocimiento racial y mejoramiento genético del Ovino Criollo Peruano. En el año 2002 fueron evaluadas ovejas de dos ambientes: Humedales y chacras. El primero es un ecosistema litoráneo de vegetación nativa, usado para pastoreo semi-extensivo por criadores de rumiantes menores. En las chacras, agricultores tienen un sistema de estaca, dentro de campos de alfalfa, grama y residuos de cultivos. Fueron reportadas 16 medidas fenotípicas en 200 hembras adultas (50 Criollas - Humedales, 54 Criollas - Chacras, 18 Mestizas - Humedales y 78 Mestizas - Chacras). Promedios y diferencia significativa al 5% fueron calculados con el procedimiento easyanova, del programa estadístico R. Los resultados indicaron que las ovejas mestizas son más pesadas y mayores. Morfométricamente existe alguna miscigenación entre rebaños, quizás por vivir en el mismo ambiente. Esto podría ser peligroso para conservación del recurso genético criollo. Apareció la posibilidad de cruza industrial, utilizando el vigor híbrido y cierta adaptación de los animales mestizos, para condiciones semi-extensivas en los Humedales de Ite.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.uco.es/conbiand/aica/templatemo_110_lin_photo/articulos/2014/Trabajo049_AICA2014.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">es</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Actas Iberoamericanas de Conservación Animal</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2253-7325</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.4/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>