<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="ES2016104874">
    <dc:title xml:lang="es">CARACTERIZACIÓN MORFOLÓGICA DEL PERRO FINO COLOMBIANO EN CUATRO REGIONES DE COLOMBIA</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>MORPHOLOGIC CHARACTERIZATION OF COLOMBIAN FINO DOG IN FOUR COLOMBIAN REGIONS</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Jonathan Álvarez</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Jiménez Robayo  Ligia Mercedes</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Martínez Betancourt  Richard Esteban</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Leal Gutiérrez  Joel David</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Sánchez Carlos</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Grupo de Estudio en Genética Animal (GEGA)</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Grupo de Estudio en Genética Animal (GEGA)</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Grupo de Estudio en Genética Animal (GEGA)</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Grupo de Estudio en Genética Animal (GEGA)</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Grupo de Estudio en Genética Animal (GEGA)</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Hunting</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3697</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Hunting has been important in the lives of Colombian peasants and their development. Through this, remote communities get animal protein in their diet. Hunting activities originated using a native dog which was probably developed from imported hounds during the country's history and due to their specific use and environment they evolved as an ethnic group selected for their functionability and this continues currently as they still are used in the field. These dogs are known as Fino Dog, Tinajero, Bramador or Chapolo, depending on the region, and they are differentiated from the other Creole dogs by their skill and their phenotype. This study was methodically put together by studying body measurements and characteristics thereof. The data has been statistically analyzed using a model of hierarchal structure in SAS 9.2. Fieldwork was conducted between 2013 and 2014 and interviews were also conducted in 7 municipalities in 4 Departments, observing n = 54 dogs. Results show clearly the uniform phenotype of the dogs</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="es">their cultural impact has been ratified in the peasant community, and with this, obtaining the first steps towards the basis for setting the standard of the first official Colombian canine breed.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">En la cultura colombiana, la caza siempre ha sido un factor importante para el desarrollo de la vida campesina. Aunque muchas veces esta actividad se realiza por deporte, para algunas comunidades apartadas resulta ser un medio para conseguir proteína de origen animal. Las actividades cinegéticas han dado origen a un tipo de perro criollo probablemente desarrollado a partir de sabuesos importados a lo largo de la historia del país y que debido a las particularidades de uso y entorno, fue evolucionando como un grupo étnico canino, seleccionado por su funcionalidad y que actualmente sigue efectuando su labor zootécnica. A este perro se le conoce como: Perro Fino, Tinajero, Chapolo o Bramador, dependiendo de la región y es diferenciado por las comunidades campesinas de los demás perros criollos por sus aptitudes y fenotipo. La metodología del estudio se basó en el desarrollo de un formato para describir algunas medidas corporales para establecer la morfometría y caracterización de la variedad criolla. Los datos recolectados, fueron analizados estadísticamente, bajo un modelo de estructura jerárquica en el programa SAS versión 9.2 El trabajo de campo se llevó a cabo entre 2013 y 2014. Las entrevistas se realizaron en siete municipios de cuatro Departamentos (Santuario-Antioquia</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">Barbosa y Puente Nacional- Santander</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">Santana y San José de Paré- Boyacá</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">Yacopí y Anolaima- Cundinamarca) a un total de n=54 perros (47% machos y 53% hembras). En los resultados se destaca la uniformidad fenotípica del perro en las medidas valoradas, además de ratificar el impacto cultural del perro en la sociedad campesina, una aproximación al entorno social del mismo, asimismo obtener las  primeras medidas para la investigación, que podrían ser la base para establecer el estándar de la primera raza canina colombiana.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.uco.es/conbiand/aica/templatemo_110_lin_photo/articulos/2014/Trabajo038_AICA2014.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">es</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Actas Iberoamericanas de Conservación Animal</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2253-7325</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.4/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>