<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="ES2016104715">
    <dc:title xml:lang="es">ANIMALES DOMÉSTICOS Y MASCOTAS, ASIGNACIÓN  DIFERENCIADA POR LA GENTE CHAMULA (CHIAPAS, MÉXICO)</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>DOMESTIC ANIMALS AND PETS</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="">
      <dcterms:alternative>DISTINGUISHED ASSIGNMENT FOR PEOPLE IN CHAMULA (CHIAPAS</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="">
      <dcterms:alternative>MEXICO)</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Rodríguez Galván Guadalupe</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Zaragoza Lourdes</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Coutiño Alfredo</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Macdonal Hernández José Manuel</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad Autónoma de Chiapas</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad Autónoma de Chiapas</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad Autónoma de Chiapas</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad Autónoma de Chiapas</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The tzotzil world view defines different concepts to the conventional agricultural and livestock production elements. Our study aimed to differentiate the categories given to animals in the tzotzil household production unit. The field work took place in three different indigenous communities in Chiapas, for a period of 18 months between 2012 and 2014. The methodological process includes a community survey, a poll on the production unit and a semi-structured interview about family life and work organization inside the family. Moreover participative and transversal techniques (interaction, observation, discussion and feedback) were used to obtain additional information. The poll was mostly answered by women. As a result of the poll we obtain three different animal categories: the productive ones (including chickens, turkeys and sheep), the guard and protection animals (dogs, cats and ducks) and pets (rabbits, squirrels and parakeets). These results let us to conclude that the concept of pet has different senses depending on each particular culture.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="es">Reconociendo que la cosmovisión tzotzil con frecuencia determina conceptos distintos a los convencionales sobre los elementos la producción agropecuaria, este trabajo tuvo como objetivo diferenciar las categorías otorgadas a los animales domésticos en la unidad productiva tzotzil. Este trabajo se realizó en tres localidades indígenas de Chiapas, durante un periodo de 18 meses entre 2012 y 2014. La investigación siguió un protocolo metodológico que aplica una cédula informativa comunitaria, una encuesta sobre la Unidad de Producción y una entrevista semiestructurada sobre la familia y organización del trabajo. Además se practicaron herramientas participativas y técnicas transversales (interacción, observación, discusión y retroalimentación) para obtener datos complementarios. La encuesta respondida en su mayoría por mujeres registró tres categorías de animales, los productivos (que incluye a las gallinas, guajolotes y ovejas), los de guardia y protección (integrado por perros, gatos y patos) y las mascotas (conejos, ardillas y pericos). Tales resultados confirman una vez más, que los términos comunes pecuarios –ejemplo, el concepto de mascota– no son equivalentes en sociedades de culturas distintas.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.uco.es/conbiand/aica/templatemo_110_lin_photo/articulos/2014/Trabajo005_AICA2014.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">es</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Actas Iberoamericanas de Conservación Animal</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2253-7325</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.4/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>