<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="ES2016105050">
    <dc:title xml:lang="es">CONTROL DE LA ASCOSFEROSIS (Ascosphaera apis) MEDIANTE EL USO DE FONDOS HIGIÉNICOS DE REJILLA</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>CHALKBROOD (Ascosphaera apis) CONTROL USING HYGIENIC GRID BOTTOM</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Gómez Mayra</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Ronquillo Javier</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Delgado Juan Vicente</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad de Córdoba</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Unión Española de Ganaderos de Pura Raza Hispano</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad de Córdoba</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Apis mellifera</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_534</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Chalkbrood is a factorial disease that affects the larvae developing of Apismellifera. Outbreaks occur preferen-tially in spring and autumn, and their appearance is associated with predisposing causes. Different types of causes are proposed, the most common are: cooling or brood stress, ratio worker bee/brood unbalanced, or lack in the pollen input. In a routine check in the early days of January 2014, we detected five hives with obvious symptoms of this disease. In four of them the normal hives bottom were replaced by other modified and provided with grids (3 mm pore size). The 5 colonies were subjected to the same management as any apiary managed by a beekeeper. In May the state of the colonies provided with bottom grid was the follows: one hive (nº 26) had no symptoms of disease, and its evolution was similar to other hives that not showed any symptoms. Another colony (nº 213) swarmed and in brood frame we observed some mums, but despite the swarming the colony had a large population of bees. The other two colonies (nº 213 and 297) had a smaller population of bees, if we compared with the other colonies. We observed in this hives some white mums in the brood frames (between 5 and 20 mummies/frame), and on the grids white and some dark mumies. The colony without bottom grid had a high number of mummies (white and dark) on the bottom and on the brood frames. In conclusion we can accept that the bottom hive modified help to control the chalkbrood. We think that to improve its effectiveness is necessary apply other management measures such as removing brood very affected by this disease.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="es">La ascosferosis es una enfermedad factorial que afecta a las larvas en desarrollo de Apis mellifera. Los brotes se producen preferentemente en primavera y otoño, y su aparición está asociada a causas predisponentes. Las más habituales son: enfriamiento o estrés de la cría, desequilibrio en la proporción nodriza/cría, o carencias en el aporte polínico. En un control realizado en los primeros días del mes de enero, detectamos cinco colmenas con síntomas evidentes de ascosferosis. En cuatro de ellas se cambiaron los fondos normales por otros modificados provistos de rejillas. Las 5 colonias se sometieron a un manejo similar al de cualquier colmenar estante explotado por un apicultor. En el mes de mayo la situación de las colonias provistas de fondos fue: una de ellas no presentaba síntomas de enfermedad, su evolución y estado era similar al de otras colmenas sanas. Otra había enjambrado y recambiado la reina</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">en los cuadros de cría aun se observaban algunas momias blancas. Las dos restantes tenían una menor población de abejas, que las colmenas anteriormente citadas, además observamos algunas momias blancas en los cuadros de cría y restos de momias sobre las rejillas de los fondos. La colmena desprovista de rejilla presentaba una alta cantidad de momias tanto en el fondo como en los cuadros de cría. Como conclusión podemos aceptar que los fondos de rejilla ayudan a controlar los brotes de esta enfermedad, aunque pensamos que para mejorar su efectividad es necesario asociar esta medida a otras de manejo.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.uco.es/conbiand/aica/templatemo_110_lin_photo/articulos/2014/Trabajo110_AICA2014.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">es</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Actas Iberoamericanas de Conservación Animal</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2253-7325</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.4/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>