<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="ES2016104777">
    <dc:title xml:lang="es">DETERMINACIÓN MORFOESTRUCTURAL DEL BOVINO CRIOLLO BARROSO SALMECO EN GUATEMALA</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>DETERMINATION MORPHOSTRUCTURAL CREOLE CATTLE BARROSO SALMECO IN GUATEMALA</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Jiménez Raúl</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Gutiérrez Andrea</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Cordón Luis</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Osorio Merlin</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Vásquez Luis</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad de San Carlos de Guatemala</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad de San Carlos de Guatemala</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad de San Carlos de Guatemala</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad de San Carlos de Guatemala</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad de San Carlos de Guatemala</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The study was conducted on the farm of Don Victor Manuel Melgar located southeast of Guatemala. The fanerópticas, morphological and morphometric characteristics were evaluated, developing standard-Salmeco Barroso to determine the breed standard. With a sample of 49 females and 5 bulls over three years morphostructural body measurements, indices, morphological and fanerópticas (44 variables) characteristics were determined. A morphostructural variables and indices were performed univariate analysis to arithmetic mean, SD, CV, EE, Pearson and fanerópticas morphological and determine contingency tables. The morphostructure and indexes indicated a shortlined, rangy animal</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="es">predominate diameters in length, are part of a larger rectangle base</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">dolichocephalic, fineness skeleton, thoracic amplitude</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">dairy females fitness, body volume harmonized with bone development. The Barrosos-Salmecos are homogeneous body alignment to 19%</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">fanerópticamente (female / male): head without hairs on forehead, eyelids muddy color, continuous towel without umbilical fold, without hump, black skin, pink nose, dark hoof, udder / scrotum depigmented, short hair, thin, single uniform color, this footwear. Among the morphological females: Horizontal small ear, straight head profile, large head, medium round eyes, medium length neck, lumbar back line straight, belly collected, broad trunk, broad chest, slightly pronounced cross, croup sloping, online birth tail, buttock straight tail medium fineness, small tassel above the hock, correct aplomb, medium thick limbs, and insertion of normal udder firm, symmetrical rooms, udder and teats uniform medium, cylindrical with rounded tip. In males, long neck with trapezius development, large symmetrical testes, scrotum flexible, slightly pendulous foreskin.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">El estudio se realizó en la finca de Don Víctor Manuel Melgar situada al suroriente de Guatemala. Se evaluó las características fanerópticas, morfológicas y morfométricas, desarrollando el estándar del Barroso-Salmeco para determinar el patrón racial. Con una muestra de 49 hembras y 5 toros mayores de tres años de edad se determinaron las medidas corporales morfoestructurales, índices, características morfológicas y fanerópticas (44 variables). A las variables morfoestructurales e índices se les realizó un análisis univariado para determinar media aritmética, DE, CV, EE, Pearson y a las morfológicas y fanerópticas tablas contingencia. La morfoestructura e índices indicaron un animal brevilíneo, longilíneo</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">predominan los diámetros de longitud, se inscriben en un rectángulo de base mayor</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">dolicocéfalos, finura de esqueleto, amplitud torácica</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">hembras aptitud lechera, volumen corporal armonizado con desarrollo óseo. Los Barrosos-Salmecos son homogéneos de armonización corporal hasta 19%</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">fanerópticamente (hembra/macho): cabeza sin pelos en testuz, color de parpados barroso, toalla continua, sin pliegue umbilical, sin giba, piel color negra, morro rosado, pezuña oscura, ubre/ escroto despigmentados, pelo corto, fino, un solo color uniforme, calzado presente. Dentro de las morfológicas en hembras: oreja pequeña horizontal, perfil cefálico recto, cabeza grande, ojos medianos redondos, cuello longitud mediano, línea dorso lumbar recta, vientre recogido, tronco ancho, pecho amplio, cruz ligeramente pronunciada, grupa inclinada, en línea nacimiento de la cola, nalga recta, cola de finura mediana, borla pequeña arriba del corvejón, aplomos correctos, extremidades gruesas medianas, inserción de la ubre normal y firme, cuartos simétricos, ubre y pezones medianos uniformes, cilíndricos con punta redonda. En machos, cuello largo con desarrollo del trapecio, testículos simétricos grandes, escroto flexible, prepucio poco pendulante.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.uco.es/conbiand/aica/templatemo_110_lin_photo/articulos/2014/Trabajo019_AICA2014.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">es</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Actas Iberoamericanas de Conservación Animal</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2253-7325</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.4 /n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>