<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="ES2016104931">
    <dc:title xml:lang="es">DIVERSIDAD GENÉTICA MITOCONDRIAL EN POBLACIONES DE BOVINOS CRIOLLOS PERUANOS</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>MITOCHONDRIAL GENETIC DIVERSITY IN PERUVIAN CREOLE CATTLE POPULATIONS</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Vadell Antonio</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Risco Roger</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Yalta Claudia</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Veli Eudocio</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Bióloga. Ibagué. Colombia</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Facultad de Ciencias. Universidad Nacional Mayor de San Marcos</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Subdirección de Recursos Genéticos y Biotecnología</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Subdirección de Recursos Genéticos y Biotecnología</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Population genetics</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_34326</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Peruvian Creole cattle are composed of heterogeneous populations adapted to very specific local conditions (e.g. highlands). The deficient information about genetic variability, phenotypic and genetic structure of these population is a limitation for implementation of conservation programs and genebanks. In order to know the status and gene pool of this germplasm, mitochondrial genetic diversity of 510 creole cattle of 46 locations in 7 regions (Ancash, La Libertad, Junín, Huancavelica, Ayacucho, Apurimac and Puno), was analyzed from hypervariable segment I (262 bp) of the D-loop region of mitochondrial DNA using the SSCP technique and DNA sequencing. Analysis of diversity and genetic structure were executed. A total of 26 haplotypes were identified with 27 polymorphic sites</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="es">levels of genetic diversity (π) and haplotype (h) were high for all regions studied, especially Ancash and Apurimac, and lower in the region of Junin. Genetic differentiation (Fst - AMOVA) was very low among regions. Regarding the composition of matrilineal Peruvian Creole cattle, we determined that haplogroup T3 is the most commonly observed (0.51), which holds that most of ancestors is constituted by European cattle. However, haplogroups T1 (0.03) and T2 (0.4) show a significant frequency. The diversity of Old World lineages in Peruvian Creole populations, suggesting a greater effect of Iberian breeds especially Portuguese, as well as common lineages in East Africa (probably as a result of the Arab occupation in Europe). The results indicate that Peruvian Creole cattle populations represent important reservoirs of genetic diversity, and should be implemented appropriate conservation measures.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">En la actualidad, los bovinos criollos existentes en el Perú se encuentran conformados por poblaciones heterogéneas adaptadas a condiciones locales muy particulares (como zonas altoandinas). La escasez de información acerca de la variabilidad genética, fenotípica y estructuración genética de bovinos criollos peruanos genera deficiencias en los programas de conservación, mejoramiento e implementación de bancos de germoplasma. Con el objetivo de conocer el estado y acervo genético de este germoplasma, la diversidad genética mitocondrial de 510 bovinos criollos de 46 localidades en 7 regiones del país (Ancash, La Libertad, Junín, Huancavelica, Ayacucho, Apurímac y Puno), fue analizada a partir del segmento hipervariable I (262 pb) de la región D-loop del ADN mitocondrial, utilizando la técnica se SSCP y secuenciamiento de ADN. Análisis de diversidad y estructuración genética fueron ejecutados. Un total de 26 haplotipos fueron identificados con 27 sitios polimórficos</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">los niveles de diversidad genética (π) y haplotípica (h) fueron altos para todas las regiones estudiadas, especialmente Ancash y Apurímac, y con niveles más bajos en la región de Junín. La diferenciación genética (Fst – AMOVA) fue muy baja entre regiones y el test de Mantel no arrojó ningún tipo de correlación espacial. En cuanto a la composición matrilineal de las poblaciones de ganado bovino criollo en el Perú, se pudo determinar que el haplogrupo T3 es el más comúnmente observado (0.51), lo que sustenta que la mayor parte de ancestros está constituido por ganado europeo. Sin embargo, las poblaciones también muestras frecuencias considerables del haplogrupo T2 (0.4) y muy bajas para T1 (0.03). La distribución y diversidad de los linajes del viejo mundo en las poblaciones criollas peruanas, sugieren un mayor efecto de razas ibéricas especialmente portuguesas, así como linajes comunes en el este de áfrica (probablemente como resultado de la ocupación árabe en Europa, así como el intercambio de ganado con países Africanos). Los resultados indican que las poblaciones bovinas criollas en Perú, representan reservorios importantes de diversidad genética, por lo cual deberían ser implementadas medidas apropiadas de conservación.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.uco.es/conbiand/aica/templatemo_110_lin_photo/articulos/2014/Trabajo082_AICA2014.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">es</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Actas Iberoamericanas de Conservación Animal</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2253-7325</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.4/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>