<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="ES2016105062">
    <dc:title xml:lang="es">VENTA TRADICIONAL DEL GUAJOLOTE NATIVO (Meleagris gallopavo) EN EL SUR DE MÉXICO</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>TRADITIONAL SALES OF NATIVE TURKEY (Meleagris gallopavo) IN SOUTHERN MEXICO</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Camacho Escobar Marco</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Jerez  Martha</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Vázquez-Dávila Marco</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Ávila-Serrano Narciso</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Sánchez-Bernal Edgar</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Arroyo-Ledezma Jaime</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad del Mar</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Instituto Tecnológico del Valle de Oaxaca</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Instituto Tecnológico del Valle de Oaxaca</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad del Mar</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad del Mar</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad del Mar</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="es">The present study was undertaken in order to identify the different marketing systems that gives the production of native turkey backyard in the states of Oaxaca, Veracruz and Chiapas in southern Mexico. Eight traditional markets were visited, and by using a semi-structured interview, information about the criteria for selecting turkeys to sell, as well as sales channels of native turkeys were obtained through interview with thirty-three sellers of native turkeys. Traditional marketers backyard turkey, are mostly the same producers who take them out of economic necessity to sell at flea markets and traditional tianguis. They travel at least an hour and spend over $50 Mexican pesos, which are not recovered in the price of the bird, because they set the price without considering the costs generated by the sale. Is necessary to develop theoretical models that help producers to estimate the cost of production and selling price backyard turkeys sold in traditional markets and traditional tianguis.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">El presente estudio se realizó con la finalidad de identificar los diferentes sistemas de mercadeo que da para la producción de guajolote nativo de traspatio en los estados de Oaxaca, Veracruz y Chiapas en el Sur de México. Se visitaron 8 mercados tradicionales y ahí, mediante una entrevista semiestructurada se recabó información sobre los criterios y canales de venta de los guajolotes nativos, en 33 vendedores de guajolotes. Los vendedores tradicionales de guajolotes de traspatio, en su mayoría son los mismos productores, quienes por necesidad económica los llevan a vender a los mercados y tianguis tradicionales, Se desplazan al menos una hora y gastan más de $50 que no recuperan en el precio del ave, debido a que establecen el precio sin considerar los gastos que genera la venta. Es necesario desarrollar modelos teóricos que ayuden a estimar el costo de producción y el precio de venta de los guajolotes de traspatio comercializados en mercados y tiánguis tradicionales.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.uco.es/conbiand/aica/templatemo_110_lin_photo/articulos/2014/Trabajo118_AICA2014.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">es</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Actas Iberoamericanas de Conservación Animal</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2253-7325</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.4/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>