<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="ES2016104925">
    <dc:title xml:lang="es">MANEJO TRADICIONAL DE LAS MAJADAS DE OVEJAS CRIOLLAS DEL OESTE FORMOSEÑO</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>TRADITIONAL MANAGEMENT OF THE CREOLE SHEEP FLOCKS THE WEST OF FORMOSA</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>de la Rosa Carbajal Sebastian</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Revidatti María Antonia</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Orga Antonio</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Tejerina Emilse</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Cappello  Juan</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Pilotti Pablo</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad Nacional del Nordeste - FCV</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad Nacional del Nordeste - FCV</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Centro de Validación de Tecnologías Agropecuarias</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad Nacional del Nordeste - FCV</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad Nacional del Nordeste - FCV</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad Nacional del Nordeste - FCV</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">biological diversity</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">food security</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Sheep</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33950</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_10967</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7030</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The objective of this work was to define patterns of traditional management of locals sheep flocks in western Formosa, Argentina. We worked on 20 sites uniformly distributed in the territory (n=82), where structured interviews were conducted asking about aspects related to sheep production systems. The data were processed by descriptive analysis. Most producers have got mixed livestock systems (87.5%) large -small livestock, the rest produce only small livestock (12.5%) both use family labor. The average stock is around 52 sheep heads /producer, stratifying as follows: less than 50 (63.5%) 51-100 (27.1%) 101-200 (7.1%) and more than 200 (2.4%). The structure of the flock is: ewes (70%), replacement hoggets (23.3%) rams (3.9%) and young replacement rams (2.8%). The 8 hours grazing system include night enclose, moving animals to average distances of 1.15 km per day, having sheepdogs (58.1%). During lambing turns away and retain parturient ewes before releasing the flock for grazing (52%). Lambs do not go with ewes during the first month of life (67.7%), they do not have adequate surface in pens, nor drinkers. Only 25.8% of farmers supplement animals at sometimes of the year. The antiparasitic application is the only health treatment (65.6%). The management carried out with this sheep corresponds to a typical backyard production, where women and children are responsible for care of the animals.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="es">El objetivo del presente fue definir las pautas de manejo tradicionales a las que son sometidas las majadas de ovejas criollas en el oeste de la provincia de Formosa. Para ello se trabajó en 20 sitios de muestreos distribuidos uniformemente en el territorio, donde se realizaron encuestas estructuradas (n=82) indagando sobre los aspectos relacionados a los sistemas productivos que poseen ovinos. Para el procesado de los datos se realizó un análisis descriptivo. La mayoría de los productores realiza explotación ganadera mixta (87,5%), combinando producción de ganado mayor con menor, el resto produce solo ganado menor (12,5%) ambos utilizan mano de obra familiar. Las existencia media ovina es de 52 cabezas por productor, estratificándose de la siguiente manera: menos de 50 (63,5%), entre 51 y 100 (27,1%), entre 101 y 200 (7,1%) y más de 200 (2,4%). La estructura de la majada se compone de: ovejas (70%), borregas de reposición (23,3%), carneros (3,9%) y carneritos de reposición (2,8%).La totalidad de los productores realiza pastoreo con encierre nocturno que rondan las 8 horas de duración, desplazándose los animales a distancias medias de 1,15 km diarios, tienen perros pastores (58,1%). Durante la época de parición se aparta y retiene las parturientas antes de largar a pastar la majada (52%). Los corderos no salen con las madres al pastoreo durante el primer mes de vida (67,7%). Los corrales no tienen la superficie necesaria de acuerdo al número de animales, ni es costumbre colocar bebederos con agua en los mismos. Solo un bajo porcentaje suplementa a los animales en alguna época del año (25,8%).  El único tratamiento sanitario que se realiza  es la aplicación de antiparasitarios (65,6%). El manejo que se lleva adelante con los ovinos se corresponde a una típica producción de traspatio, donde las mujeres y los niños son los encargados de la atención de los animales.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.uco.es/conbiand/aica/templatemo_110_lin_photo/articulos/2014/Trabajo079_AICA2014.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">es</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Actas Iberoamericanas de Conservación Animal</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2253-7325</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.4/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>