<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="GE2016007536">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Problems on commercialization of agricultural biotechnology in Georgia.</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Didebulidze A.K.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">A01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">agriculture</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Biotechnology</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">botany</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Economic analysis</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_203</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_16165</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1023</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2469</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The agriculture is extremely important to the economy of Georgia and has a direct effect on the lives of the majority of Georgians, but after the restoration of independence the agricultural and food sector has undergone a deep crisis and the country of agricultural net-export changed into the country of net-import. Development of agricultural biotechnology can contribute to the economic growth of the country by commercializing plant culti- vars that possess improved genetic characteristics. Despite increasing use of the modern agricultural biotechnol- ogy elsewhere, efforts to put these inventions and launch profitable products in Georgia were unsuccessful due to protests from the public and politicians against genetically modified plants. The authorities have developed a complex legislation for agricultural biotechnology that limits research, development, production and imports. The discussions can lead to constructive ideas on how to resolve some of agricultural biotechnology’s most pressing issues and allow safe applications to be commercialized in Georgia. The report summarizes biotechnology com- mercialization in the world, marks significant agricultural biotechnologies and accents results in biotechnology commercialization in Georgia. The analysis has been made by using various sources of agriculture and biotech- nology statistics.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.agrscience.ge</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Annals of agrarian science</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1512-1887</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.12/n.3</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>