<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="R12016018293">
    <dc:title xml:lang="ln">Reduction of Relaxation Oscillation Resonance of Wheel Brake Devices of Lumber Trucks</dc:title>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2016-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">forestry</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3055</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang=" ">This article analyzes the potential increase of the relative speed of deformation of the elastic member in the calculating and dynamic system of a friction pair of “brake shoe (band) – counterface” of the automotive brake at the beginning and the end of braking, and therefore the corresponding components of a friction pair of a real brake to reduce the self-oscillations due to the compressed air supply on the friction surfaces during braking. The problem of the research is the theoretical attempt to analyze qualitatively the influence of the positive phys-ical phenomena of the investigated braking process of a vehicle wheel on the self-
oscillations and their resonant consequences. We offer to use the technical and theoretical approaches related to the compressed air supply on the brake friction surface in the process of braking during the period of the friction pair entering in full contact, up to a complete stop of a wheel. Due to the high speed of airflow we should expect the fewer amounts of wear products in the micropits of surface roughness in the process of compressed air supply-ing during wheel braking and the kinematic friction into the variable clearance between the friction surfaces than without scavenging. In addition, the expected intensification of cool-ing of the friction surfaces is real. As a result, the undesirable smearing and vulcanization processes of the facing material are less active</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">and the elastic properties of the wheeled brake facing have a longer life, compared with the existing designs. This fact reduces the self-oscillations in the brake devices, which in case of possible short-term resonance phe-nomena are a source of noise of the wheeled automobile brakes and a reduction of increased wear of the friction facing material, as well as to a decrease of the response time of facing. As an example, the idealized diagram of a friction pair of a drum brake is mathematically modeled</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">the positive effects obtained after the introduction of the compressed air supply circuit in the current clearance of the friction pair in the process of closing and separation at the automobile braking action are reflected.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://lesnoizhurnal.narfu.ru/issuesarchive/?ELEMENT_ID=246796</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">en</dc:language>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Lesnoy Zhurnal (Forestry journal)</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">0536-1036</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>