<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="R12016017315">
    <dc:title xml:lang="lg">Selective Logging, Challenges and Solutions</dc:title>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2016-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">forestry</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3055</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang=" ">Selective loggings are carried out in order to ensure timely harvesting of ripe and over-ripe parts of the stands, creating of favorable conditions for rapid restoration of timber resources, stands conservation of uneven-aged structure, their stability, enhancement the forests productivity and their protective functions. The article deals with the problems and
importance of selective logging, their applicability in a variety of natural and industrial conditions, technologies potential of different types of selective logging in the operational and protective forests (where clear-cuttings are prohibited in accordance with the current regulations). The analysis of the application of harvesting techniques with the use of traditional technologies and modern multifunction logging machines is carried out. We studied the possibilities of full-circle feller bunchers with the pick-cutting head, equipped with a storage device and equalizing counterweight to conduct the selective cutting of high efficiency. It
reduces the defectiveness of tree stands, weight of the feller-bunchers, and provides high productivity even in the smallwood felling. A new method of harvesting is proposed. It contemplates the timber transporting from the cutting areas by way of the butt and apical segments with the crowns, as well as wood chips, resulting in a new shear and chipping and skidding machine. As at the selective logging the volume of one-time felling of wood per unit of area is less than at the final felling, so the forest infrastructure density should be supported by the construction of the network of spur tracks, branches, continuous skidding trails that can be also used to carry out forest management activities. Implementation of new logging equipment, in particular full-circle feller-bunchers, will significantly increase the cost-
effectiveness of selective cutting in a variety of natural and industrial environments, integrated use of forest raw materials, damage reduction of forest stands.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://lesnoizhurnal.narfu.ru/en/article_index_years.php?ELEMENT_ID=242555</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">lg</dc:language>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Lesnoy Zhurnal (Forestry journal)</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">0536-1036</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.2016/n.2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>