<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="R12016017388">
    <dc:title xml:lang="lg">Silvicultural Effectiveness of Improvement Cutting in the Pine Forests of Kazakh Upland</dc:title>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2016-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">forestry</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3055</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang=" ">Based on the materials of the research carried out in the permanent study areas we analyzed the silvicultural effectiveness of the improvement cutting in the pine forests of Kazakh up-land for 58-year period. The improvement cutting in the dry pine forests of Kazakh upland (pine forests of a dead-lichen type) carried out in the 35-year-old pure pine stand even 58 years after can not provide a stock volume similar to that in the control stands where thin-ning has not been carried out. At the same time the improvement cutting minimize the attri-tion and increase a mean diameter of a stand, which improves the commercial value of cul-tivated stands, resistance to adverse natural and anthropogenic factors (recreation, forest fires, etc.), and increases the recreational appeal. Pine plantations of this forest type are characterized by high responsiveness to thinning. Even with a decrease in the relative densi-ty in 35-years of age less than 0.5, they maintain stability and by age of 93 (in 58 years after thinning) reproduce the relative density of a normal stand. As thinning improves the sustain-ability of pine plantations, and all the forests of Kazakh upland belong to the protective pur-pose forests, we can recommend conducting moderate thinning on stock volume by low thinning in the close 30–40-year-old pine forests of a dead-lichen type.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://lesnoizhurnal.narfu.ru/issuesarchive/?ELEMENT_ID=244100</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ln</dc:language>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Lesnoy Zhurnal (Forestry journal)</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">0536-1036</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.2016/n.3</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>