<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="R12016017407">
    <dc:title xml:lang="ln">Numerical Modeling of Long Logs Barking in the Barking Drums</dc:title>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2016-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">forestry</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3055</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang=" ">A significant part of wood chips for pulp and paper and wood-based panels production is produced in the Wood Yards of the wood processing enterprises. One of the main operations of the technological process is the pulpwood debarking in the barking drums. The pulpwood length entering a barking drum typically does not exceed 1.2 m. This fact reasonably allows us to neglect its possible lateral bending at processing because of its stiffness. However, recently the foreign Wood Yards began to practice long timber barking. This can signifi-cantly improve the performance of the Wood Yards, reduce energy consumption and the wood losses at the stage of wood debarking. Tapering and bending strain have a significant impact on the quality when debarking of long logs. As the development of the earlier studies we consider barking of long logs and stems in a barking drum, which is significantly shorter than stems. In this context, there is an actual problem of the quality research of debarking of long logs in the shortened drums. The objective of the paper is the application of numerical modeling to assess the impact of long logs bending in accordance with their tapering. A software complex of the finite element analysis ANSYS is used as an instrument of the re-search. As a result of the simulation the adequacy of the proposed modeling techniques is proved. Its use confirms the previously formulated hypothesis that not only the collision, but also the resulting flexural strain and stresses can cause destruction of structures, weaken the adhesive power of bark and wood and laminas.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://lesnoizhurnal.narfu.ru/issuesarchive/?ELEMENT_ID=244111</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ln</dc:language>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Lesnoy Zhurnal (Forestry journal)</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">0536-1036</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.2016/n.3</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>