<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="BR2016F00581">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Degradability of dry matter and crude protein of dry grains and wet grain silages from different processing corn hybrids (Zea mays)</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="pt">
      <dcterms:alternative>Degradabilidade da matéria seca e da proteína bruta de grãos secos e de silagens de grãos úmidos de híbridos de milho (Zea mays)</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="">
      <dcterms:alternative>submetidos a diferentes processamentos.</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>REIS, W.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>COSTA, C.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>MEIRELLES,  P. R. L.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>SILVA,  M.G. B.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>FACTORI,  M. A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>HADLICH,  J. C.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>OLIVEIRA, K.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>SANTANA,  E. A. R.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>PARIZ,  C. M</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>SILVA, J. A. V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2013-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">silage</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">ruminants</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">degradation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en" />
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Nutritive value</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7060</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6695</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2159</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1326100966995</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5278</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The objective of this work was to evaluate the effect of processing two corn hybrids
conserved, dry and humid grains, the dry matter (DM) and crude protein (CP) degradability in
situ. The particle size was determined and difference was verified in MGD (Medium Geometric
Diameter) of processed ingredients. Three sheep were used with rumen canulated, in a completely
randomized design, using a factorial outline 2 x 2 x 3, being two corn hybrid, two conservation
methods and three processing forms (whole, coarsely and finely ground), with five times of
incubation (3, 6, 12, 24 and 48 hours). The fraction A in SDC (silage of dent corn) of DM was
superior to GDC (grain of dent corn) in all of the particles size. The ensiling process increased the
DM solubility, reducing the fraction B in comparison to dry grain. The values regarding the
fractions DP and DE the 5% per hour of the protein, were larger for SDC and GDC, it presents a
decreasing when the incubation time advances. The fermentation rate was superior for SDC and
GDC. The ensiling process has positive effect in the decreasing of DM and CP in comparison to
GDC</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="pt">Este trabalho avaliou o efeito do processamento em dois híbridos de milho secos e
ensilados úmidos, sobre a degradabilidade in situ da matéria seca (MS) e da proteína bruta (PB). A
granulometria apresentou diferença no DGM (Diâmetro Geométrico Médio) dos ingredientes
submetidos à moagem. Foram utilizados três ovinos fistulados no rúmen, em delineamento
inteiramente casualizado, em esquema fatorial 2 x 2 x 3, sendo dois híbridos de milho (textura
dura e mole), dois métodos de conservação e três processamentos (moído grosso, médio e fino),
com cinco tempos de incubação (3, 6, 12, 24 e 48 horas). Os valores da fração A na SMM (silagem de
milho mole) da MS foram superiores ao GMM (grão de milho mole) em todas as granulometrias.
A ensilagem aumentou a solubilidade da MS dos ingredientes, diminuindo a fração B comparada
ao grão seco. Os valores das frações DP e DE a 5%/h da proteína foram maiores para SMM e GMM,
apresentando maior desaparecimento com avanço do tempo de incubação. Para a MS a ensilagem
aumentou a degradabilidade do milho textura mole. A taxa de fermentação foi superior para
SMM e GMM. A ensilagem influencia positivamente no desaparecimento da MS e PB comparada
com o GMM</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.iz.sp.gov.br/pdfsbia/1389723086.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">pt</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Boletim de Indústria Animal</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">0067-9615</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.70/n.3</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>