<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X17626">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">THE INFLUENCE OF MACRONUTRIENTS AND GROWTH REGULATORS ON YIELD AND QUALITY OF WINTER WHEAT KAZANSKAYA 560 IN THE CONDITIONS OF MIDDLE VOLGA REGION</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ВЛИЯНИЕ МАКРОЭЛЕМЕНТОВ И РЕГУЛЯТОРОВ РОСТА НА УРОЖАЙНОСТЬ И КАЧЕСТВО ЗЕРНА ОЗИМОЙ ПШЕНИЦЫ КАЗАНСКАЯ 560 В УСЛОВИЯХ СРЕДНЕГО ПОВОЛЖЬЯ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Isaychev Vitaly A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Andreyev Nikolay N.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Polovinkin Vasily G.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F62</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Winter wheat</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">plant growth substances</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">inorganic fertilizers</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">crop yield</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">plant condition</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8412</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5968</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_27870</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_10176</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_25398</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>4 tables, 11 ref.</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">In 2008-2011, field experiments were conducted in the conditions of the agricultural production cooperative in the Ulyanovsk region to study the effects of microelements and plant growth regulators on productivity of winter wheat Kazanskaya 560 cultivar and the quality of the products. Method of laying field experience is common to large-plot experiments, repeatability is four times, accommodation options in experience  are randomized, square plots of 50 sq. m.  At the beginning of tillering stage background processing of crops was conducted by the studied Krezatsin, Humimax, Albite growth regulators. There were two backgrounds. 1st background is natural fertility, 2nd background is mineral fertilizers based on planned yield 35 t/ha. It was established that growth regulators and plant development increase the protein content in the grain of the culture experienced by 0.53 to 1.55% - on a natural background and 1,21-3,09%, on the fertilized background. The results show that the gluten content in grain of winter wheat ranged from 21.8% to 25.3% on average over the years of study, depending on the variant. There was 2.7 to 3.5% increase, depending on the background diet. The quality of grain gluten of experienced culture changes under the influence of used plant growth regulators and fertilizers. IDK readings vary from 46 to 74 units, depending on the option, and corresponds to the I group of quality. The applied growth regulators and mineral fertilizers have a significant positive impact on the yield of winter wheat. The yield of winter wheat has increased by 120-540 kg/ha over the years of study, depending on the variant. The most effective was the use of an Albite growth regulator, especially on the background of NPK.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Проведены полевые опыты в 2008-2011 годах в условиях сельскохозяйственного производственного кооператива в  Ульяновской области по изучению влияния макроэлементов и регуляторов роста растений на продуктивность озимой пшеницы сорта Казанская 560 и качество полученной продукции. Методика закладки полевого опыта общепринятая для крупноделяночных опытов, повторность четырехкратная, размещение вариантов в опыте рендомизированное, площадь делянок – 50 кв.м. В начале фазы кущения проводилась фоновая обработка посевов исследуемыми регуляторами роста Крезацин, Гумимакс, Альбит.  В опыте присутствовали два фона. 1 фон – естественное плодородие, 2 фон – минеральные удобрения из расчета на запланированный урожай 35 ц/га. Установлено, что используемые регуляторы роста и развития растений способствуют увеличению содержания белка в зерне опытной культуры на 0,53-1,55% - на естественном фоне и на 1,21-3,09% - на удобренном фоне. Результаты исследований показывают, что содержание клейковины в зерне озимой пшеницы в среднем за годы исследований колебалось от 21,8% до 25,3%, в зависимости от варианта. Прибавка составила 2,7 – 3,5%, в зависимости от фона питания. Качество клейковины зерна опытной культуры изменяется под действием используемых регуляторов роста растений и минеральных удобрений.  Показания ИДК изменяются от 46 до 74 условных единиц, в зависимости от варианта, что соответствует I группе качества. Применяемые регуляторы роста и минеральные удобрения оказывают существенное положительное влияние на урожайность озимой пшеницы.  В среднем за годы исследований урожайность озимой пшеницы увеличивалось на 1,2-5,4 ц/га, в зависимости от варианта. Наиболее эффективным являлось применение регулятора роста Альбит, особенно на фоне NPK.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik.ugsha.ru/contentse/4-15-Isaychev.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.4(32)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>