<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X12023">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Electromechanical hardening of working surfaces of splined bushings of agricultural  machinery</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Электромеханическая закалка рабочих поверхностей шлицевых втулок техники  сельскохозяйственного назначения</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Morozov A.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Fedorova L.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Fedotov G.D.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Moscow STI named after N.E. Bauman</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">N20</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">farm equipment</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">technical properties</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">wear</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">resistance to injurious factors</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_25753</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2572</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_24914</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6520</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>8ref.</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">In the construction of commercially available and newly developed tractors and agricultural machines there are widely used sline joint for transmitting power from the power unit to the propeller, working bodies and other components of the machine. The nature of the damage of sline joints is considered. Special attention is paid to the runout of the working surfaces of the sline joint, on the basis of which an effective method of Electromechanical hardening (EMH) of working surfaces of the splined bushing is offered. Tool for implementing the proposed method is designed and manufactured. Laboratory studies of the influence of the electric current to changes in microstructure and microhardness of hardened surfaces of splined bushings are carried out. Joint power and high-temperature effects on steel with EMH gives the surface a unique properties: structureless martensite has simultaneously high hardness and toughness, which can significantly improve the durability of the spline mates, working in conditions of abrasive runout and high contact loads.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">В конструкциях серийно выпускаемых и вновь разрабатываемых тракторов и сельскохозяйственных машин широко применяются шлицевые соединения для передачи мощности от силового агрегата к движителям, рабочим органам и другим узлам и агрегатам машины. Рассмотрен характер повреждений шлицевых соединений. Особое внимание уделено износу рабочих поверхностей шлицевого соединения, на основании чего предложен эффективный способ электромеханической закалки (ЭМЗ) рабочих поверхностей шлицевой втулки. Спроектирован и изготовлен инструмент для осуществления предложенного способа. Проведены лабораторные исследования влияния силы тока на изменение микроструктуры и микротвердости закаленных поверхностей шлицевых втулок. Совместное силовое и высокотемпературное воздействие на сталь при ЭМЗ придает поверхности уникальные свойства: бесструктурный мартенсит имеет одновременно и высокую твердость и ударную вязкость, что позволяет существенно повышать долговечность шлицевых сопряжений, работающих в условиях абразивного изнашивания и высоких контактных нагрузок.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik.ugsha.ru/contentse/2-15-%D0%9C%D0%BEr%D0%BEz%D0%BEv.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.2(30)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>