<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X13637">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">SELECTION OF PROMISING PRODUCTION STRAIN BACILLUS ANTHRACIS FOR CONSTRUCTION OF PHAGE BIOLOGIC DRUG</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ПОДБОР ПЕРСПЕКТИВНОГО ПРОИЗВОДСТВЕННОГО ШТАММА BACILLUS ANTHRACIS ДЛЯ КОНСТРУИРОВАНИЯ ФАГОВОГО БИОПРЕПАРАТА</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Feoktistova Natalya А.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Vasilyev D.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Кlimushkin Еvgeny I.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L70</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">bacillus anthracis</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">BACTERIOPHAGES</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">biological properties</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Phages</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_9040</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_769</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1501</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_13274</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The article presents the results of research on the selection of promising production avirulent strain Bacillus anthracis for the cultivation of specific virulent bacteriophage. Conducted research to study the biological properties of isolated and studied anthracic bacteriophage showed that when cultured on different avirulent strains of B. anthracis, it has stable performance lytic activity (strain Bacillus anthracis Shuya- 15 - 1,0х108±0,1х108 BOЕ in 1 ml of phage lysate, strain Bacillus anthracis 55-Vniivvim — 1,9х106±0,1х106  BOE in 1 ml of phage lysate, the strain of Bacillus anthracis STI - 1,4х107±0,1х107 BOE in 1 ml of phage lysate, strain Bacillus anthracis 34 F2  - 3,0х108±0,1х108 BОЕ in 1 ml of phage lysate), that do not change during storage without add the preservative in the conditions of a domestic refrigerator (2-4 0С) for three months. Based on these data, future production strain believe Bacillus anthracis Shuya-15, which when seeding on meat-peptone agar (MPA), negative colonies with clear edge and clear center are formed, which is very important for their visual counting in the case of the reaction of increase of phage titer (IPT). The practical significance of the work is determined by effective microbiological and technological methods, which allow to adapt the production of the bacteriophage to the conditions of mass production of biological products. The creation of a new integrated phage preparation expands the Arsenal of antibacterial anthracic funds.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">В статье представлены результаты исследований по подбору перспективного производственного авирулентного штамма Bacillus anthracis для культивирования специфического вирулентного бактериофага. Проведенные исследования по изучению биологических свойств выделенного и изучаемого сибиреязвенного бактериофага показали, что он при культивировании на различных авирулентных штаммах B. anthracis имеет стабильные показатели литической активности (на штамме Bacillus anthracis Шуя-15 - 1,0х108±0,1х108 БОЕ в 1 мл фаголизата, на штамме Bacillus anthracis 55-ВНИИВВиМ - 1,9х106±0,1х106 БОЕ в 1 мл фаголизата, на штамме Bacillus anthracis-СТИ - 1,4х107±0,1х107 БОЕ в 1 мл фаголизата, на штамме Bacillus anthracis 34 F2  - 3,0х108±0,1х108 БОЕ в 1 мл фаголизата), которые не изменяются при хранении без добавления консерванта в условиях бытового холодильника (2-4 0С) в течение трех месяцев. На основании полученных данных, перспективным производственным штаммом считаем Bacillus anthracis Шуя-15, на котором при высеве на мясо-пептонном агаре (МПА) образуются негативные колонии с четким краем и прозрачным центром, что чрезвычайно важно при их визуальном подсчете в случае постановки реакции нарастания титра фага (РНФ). Практическая значимость работы определяется разработанными эффективными микробиологическими и технологическими приемами, позволяющими адаптировать процессы изготовления бактериофага к условиям массового производства биопрепаратов. Создание нового комплексного фагового препарата расширяет арсенал антибактериальных сибиреязвенных средств.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik.ugsha.ru/contentse/3-15-Feoktistova.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.3(31)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>