<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X13467">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">STRUCTURE OF THE CONSUMPTION OF METABOLIZABLE ENERGY AND THE INFLUENCE OF THE PRIMARY EXCHANGE ON MILK PRODUCTION</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>СТРУКТУРА РАСХОДА ОБМЕННОЙ ЭНЕРГИИ И ВЛИЯНИЕ ОСНОВНОГО ОБМЕНА НА МОЛОЧНУЮ ПРОДУКТИВНОСТЬ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Моkhоv Boris P</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Shabalina Еlеnа P</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Cows</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Milk performance</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Energy value</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Metabolism</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1939</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_24276</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_10613</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4769</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>3 tables, 21 ref.</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The metabolizable energy is used to provide the various elements of animals. This is to begin with the further dissimilation, the disintegration of complex organic compounds and the release of energy, then assimilation, the formation of new substances, consumption and accumulation of energy, which is subsequently used for the synthesis and functioning of cardiovascular, respiratory, nervous and other body systems. Energy is expended in the process of muscular and productive activities of animals, and also for heat dissipation. Two groups of cows at the age of three calving and older with similar breed type, conformation and body composition, and differing in milk production were studied. Dynamics and structure of consumption of metabolizable energy was set at the costs of basal metabolism, milk production, heat production and physical activity. In the structure of the expense of metabolizable energy depending on productivity costs of the main exchange are 27,9 - 22,3 %, on the productivity — 20,1 - 26,0 %, on heat generation — 44,9% and on other expenses - 7 %. Low productive cows per one MJ of nutritional value of milk spend 4.9 MJ of energy feed, and high - yielding 2 – 3,8 MJ. Rhythm of ruminant process of high yielding cows is better developed compared to low productive. The speed of assimilation and basal metabolic rate of high yielding cows is higher by 9 – 10% at td = 2.8 and the probability P&gt;0,99. Experimentally established the intensity of ruminant process and the evidence of his connection with the main exchange allows to evaluate the energy cost at the level of the whole organism. Methods of biological statistics can determine the vector of the interaction of metabolic processes and productivity at the level of the whole organism.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Обменная энергия, поступившая в организм, используется для обеспечения различных элементов жизнедеятельности животных. Это прежде всего дальнейшая диссимиляция, распад сложных органических соединений и выделение энергии, затем ассимиляция, образование новых веществ, расход и накопление энергии, которая впоследствии используется для синтеза и работы сердечнососудистой, дыхательной, нервной и других систем организма. Энергия затрачивается в процессе мышечной и продуктивной деятельности животных, а также при теплоотдаче. Изучены две группы коров в возрасте трех отелов и старше аналогичные по породности, экстерьеру и конституции и различающиеся по молочной продуктивности. Динамика и структура расхода обменной энергии устанавливалась по затратам на основной обмен, производство молока, теплопродукцию и двигательную активность. В структуре расхода обменной энергии в зависимости от продуктивности затраты на основной обмен составляют 27,9 - 22,3 %, на продуктивность 20,1 - 26,0 %, на теплопродукцию 44,9 % и остальные расходы 7 %. Низкопродуктивные коровы на один МДж питательности молока затрачивают 4,9 МДж энергии корма, а высокопродуктивные - 2 – 3,8 МДж. Ритмичность жвачного процесса у высокопродуктивных коров развита лучше по сравнению с низкопродуктивными. Скорость ассимиляции и интенсивность основного обмена у высокопродуктивных коров выше на 9 – 10 % при td = 2,8 и вероятности Р&gt;0,99. Экспериментально установленная интенсивность жвачного процесса и очевидность его связи с основным обменом позволяет дать оценку энергетических затрат на уровне целостного организма. Методы биологической статистики могут определить вектор взаимодействия обменных процессов и продуктивности на уровне целостного организма.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik.ugsha.ru/contentse/2-15-%D0%9C%D0%BEkh%D0%BEv.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.2(30)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>