<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X12861">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">BIOCHEMICAL AND MORPHOLOGICAL PARAMETERS OF BLOOD AND THE LEVEL OF NATURAL RESISTANCE OF COWS OF HOLSTEIN BREED</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>БИОХИМИЧЕСКИE И МОРФОЛОГИЧЕСКИЕ ПОКАЗАТЕЛИ КРОВИ И УРОВЕНЬ ЕСТЕСТВЕННОЙ РЕЗИСТЕНТНОСТИ КОРОВ ГОЛШТИНСКОЙ ПОРОДЫ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Мudarisov R.M.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Аkhmetzyanova G.R.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Khakimov I.N.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Bashkir state agrarian university</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Bashkir state agrarian university</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Samara State Agricultural Academy</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Cows</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Breeds (animals)</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">pedigree livestock</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">blood</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">chemical composition</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1939</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_13185</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_959</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1794</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">We identified exterior features of fresh cows of Holstein breed and connection with milk production. Studies conducted on Holstein heifers of German, Finnish and Hungarian breeding. To establish the features of the exterior, the main physique measurements were taken and physique indexes were defined. Milk productivity of animals we counted for 305-day, the content of fat and protein in milk was determined. The studies showed that heifers of Holstein breed of different breeding groups have differences according to the development of conformation and milk production. The Hungarian breeding animals have a more stretched body, deep chest, compared with animals of German and Finnish breeding and strong bones, which resulted in higher milk production and protein content. They were superior of cows of German breeding by 914,2 kg according to the yield of milk and mass fraction of fat by 0,25%, and Finnish cows breeding by 215,0 kg and 0,34%, respectively.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Выявляли экстерьерные особенности коров–первотелок голштинской породы и взаимосвязи с молочной продуктивностью. Исследования проведены на первотелках голштинской породы немецкой, финской и венгерской селекции. Для установления особенностей экстерьера были взяты основные промеры телосложения и определены индексы телосложения. Молочная продуктивность животных пересчитывали на 305 дней, были определены содержание жира и белка в молоке. В ходе исследований установлено, что первотелки голштинской породы разных селекционных групп имеют различия по развитию экстерьера и молочной продуктивности. Животные венгерской селекции имеют более растянутое тело, более глубокую грудь по сравнению с животными немецкой и финской селекции и крепкий костяк, что обусловило более высокую их молочную продуктивность и содержание белка. Они на 914,2 кг превосходили по удою коров немецкой селекции и по массовой доли жира на 0,25%, а коров финской селекции на 215,0 кг и на 0,34%, соответственно.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik.ugsha.ru/contentse/2-15-%D0%9Cudarisov.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.2(30)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>