<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X12961">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">FUNGICIDE ON SPRING WHEAT IN  CONDITIONS OF TRANS-URALS</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ФУНГИЦИДЫ НА ЯРОВОЙ ПШЕНИЦЕ В УСЛОВИЯХ ЗАУРАЛЬЯ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Nemchenko V.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Кеkаlо A.Yu.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Zargaryan N.Yu.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Kurgan scientific research Institute of agriculture</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F60</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Triticum aestivum</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">fungicides</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">plant growth substances</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">foliar diseases</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Crop yield</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7951</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3146</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5968</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_25240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_10176</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>10 ref.</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Fungicidal treatment of crops is a method of rapid response to the negative change of the phytosanitary situation in agrocenosis. Their use must be economically and environmentally justified. The aim of the research is to study of fungicides on spring soft wheat for the selection of the most effective one that improves the phytosanitary condition of crops, increasing the crop yield and quality of grain produced in Trans-Ural region. Field experiments were conducted in 2004 and 2013, at the Central experimental field of the Kurgan research Institute of agriculture (v. Sadovoye). The research objects were the varieties of spring soft wheat Omsk 18 (in 2004-2006), Omsk 36 (in 2007-2013). The soil is leached medium loamy and humus Chernozem. Predecessor – pure steam. Observations and counts were conducted by standard methods (VIZR, State variety testing of agricultural crops (1971)</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">root rot by the method of V. A. Chulkina) [2,3,4]. Multicomponent fungicides (falcon, colosal pro, alto super) are characterized by high economic and biological efficiency (16-23% and 80%, respectively) in the years of the existence of mass of leaf diseases, biofungicides (fitosporin-M, bactofit) inhibit pathogens weaker. In single lesions of leaf by diseases using chemicals of fungicidal action is not economically justified. Long-term field experiments showed that in the years of epiphytotic diseases of leaves with wheat yields of over 20 t/ha the economically viable level of stored crop due to application of fungicides is 4-5 kg/ha, biopreparations – 2,5-3 kg/ha</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">in years of moderate defeat of leaves of wheat from biopreparations – 2 kg/ha, from fungicides – 3,5-4,0 kg/ha</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">in the years of depressive development of leaf cauline diseases the fungicide application on wheat is not economically justified unless there is danger of infection of the ear.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">Фунгицидные обработки посевов – метод оперативного реагирования на негативное изменение фитосанитарной обстановки в агроценозе. Их применение должно быть и экономически,  и экологически оправдано. Цель исследований - изучение фунгицидов на яровой мягкой пшенице для подбора наиболее эффективных из них, улучшающих фитосанитарное состояние посевов, повышающих продуктивность культуры и качество получаемого зерна в условиях Зауралья. Полевые опыты проводились в 2004-2013 годах на Центральном опытном поле Курганского НИИСХ (с. Садовое). Объектами исследований выступали сорта яровой мягкой пшеницы  Омская 18 (в 2004-2006гг.), Омская 36 (в 2007-2013гг.). Почва – чернозем выщелоченный среднесуглинистый среднегумусный. Предшественник – чистый пар. Наблюдения и учёты проводились по  общепринятым методикам (ВИЗР, Государственного сортоиспытания сельскохозяйственных культур (1971)</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">корневые гнили по методике В.А. Чулкиной) [2,3,4]. Высокой хозяйственной и биологической эффективностью (16-23% и более 80% соответственно) в годы массового проявления листовых болезней характеризуются поликомпонентные фунгициды (фалькон, колосаль про, альто супер), биофунгициды (фитоспорин-М, бактофит) слабее подавляют патогены. В условиях единичного поражения листьев болезнями использование химических препаратов фунгицидного действия экономически не оправдано. Многолетние полевые опыты показали, что в годы эпифитотии болезней листьев при урожайности  пшеницы более 20 ц/га экономически оправданный уровень сохраненного урожая за счет применения фунгицидов составлял 4-5 ц/га, биопрепаратов – 2,5-3 ц/га</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">в годы умеренного поражения листьев пшеницы от биопрепаратов – 2 ц/га, от фунгицидов – 3,5-4,0 ц/га</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">в годы депрессивного развития листостеблевых болезней применение фунгицидов на пшенице экономически не оправдано, если нет опасности заражения колоса.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik.ugsha.ru/contentse/3-15-Nemchenko.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.3(31)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>