<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X17289">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">ULTRASTRUCTURE PECULIARITIES OF QUAILS OVARIAN TUBE GLANDULOCYTES</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ОСОБЕННОСТИ УЛЬТРАСТРУКТУРЫ ГЛАНДУЛОЦИТОВ ЯЙЦЕВОДА ПЕРЕПЕЛОК</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Kot Таtyana F.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Zhytomyr national agroecological university</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2016-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L70</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Birds</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">oviducts</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Animal glands</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">ultrastructure</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_935</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5461</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_27958</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8045</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">We investigated the electron microscopic glandulocytes structure of the mucous membrane of the isthmus, protein and eggshell segment of the ovarian tube of Japanese quails breed during the laying period (150-day age). The work was carried out on the basis of electronic microscopy laboratory of National medical university named after A. A. Bogomolts (Ukraine, Kiev). We used conventional classical methods for electron microscopic research. It was established that glandulocytes have high synthesizing activity, caused by the presence of well-developed synthesizing organelles and secretory inclusions in their cytoplasm. There are cracks of considerable length between glandulocytes, that alternate with parts of simple, dense and desmosomal intercellular connections. Intercellular spaces are the widest in eggshell segment. Outgrowths of cytoplasm (microvilli) are noticeable both on the apical pole glandulocytes and in the intercellular space. Among the organelles of general purpose the granular endoplasmatic reticulum is well-developed. Its long and dilated ductules contain low electron density secretion in the lumen and a large number of ribosomes on the outer membrane. There are secretory granules between the ductules of granular endoplasmatic reticulum. They have different diameter (5,12±0,43 µm in the protein segment, 2,44±0,15 µm in isthmus, 1,03±0,06 µm in the eggshell segment), round or oval shape, they contain a homogeneous, high electron density material. Сhondriosomes are localized between the structures of granular endoplasmatic reticulum and near the plasmolemma. They are round or oval shape, with well-defined membranes and cristae, and contain a matrix of moderate electron density. The peculiarities of the glandulocytes ultrastructure of ovarian tube mucous membrane of clinically healthy quails should be used as indicators of norms in the diagnosis of different genesis diseases and in conducting experimental research.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Исследовали электронно-микроскопическое строение гландулоцитов слизистой оболочки перешейка, белкового и скорлупового отделов яйцевода перепелок Японской породы в период яйцекладки (150-суточный возраст). Работу проводили на базе лаборатории электронной микроскопии Национального медицинского университета им. А.А. Богомольца (Украина, г. Киев). Использовали общепринятые классические методы электронно-микроскопических исследований. Установлено, что гландулоцитам свойственна высокая синтезирующая активность, которая обусловлена наличием в их цитоплазме хорошо развитых синтезирующих органелл и секреторных включений. Между гландулоцитами есть щели значительной протяженности, которые чередуются с участками простых, плотных и десмосомных межклеточных соединений. В скорлуповом отделе межклеточные пространства наиболее широкие. Выросты цитоплазмы (микроворсинки) заметны как на апикальном полюсе гландулоцитов, так и в межклеточном пространстве. Среди органелл общего назначения хорошо развита гранулярная эндоплазматическая сетка. Ее длинные и расширенные канальцы содержат секрет низкой электронной плотности в просвете и большое количество рибосом на внешней мембране. Между канальцами гранулярной эндоплазматической сетки расположены секреторные гранулы. Они имеют разный диаметр (5,12±0,43 мкм в белковом отделе, 2,44±0,15 мкм в перешейке, 1,03±0,06 мкм в скорлуповом отделе), округлую или овальную форму, содержат гомогенный, большой электронной плотности материал. Митохондрии локализованы между структурами гранулярной эндоплазматической сетки и возле плазмолеммы. Они имеют круглую или овальную форму, четко выраженные мембраны и кристы, содержат матрикс умеренной электронной плотности. Особенности ультраструктуры гландулоцитов слизистой оболочки яйцевода клинически здоровых перепелок следует использовать как показатели нормы при диагностике заболеваний.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik.ugsha.ru/contentse/1-16-kot.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.1(33)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>