<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X13294">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">EVALUATION OF GENETIC POLYMORPHISM OF KAPPA-CASEIN GENE IN ANIMALS OF BLACK-MOTLEY BREED</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ОЦЕНКА ПОЛИМОРФИЗМА ГЕНА КАППА-КАЗЕИНА У ЖИВОТНЫХ ЧЕРНО-ПЕСТРОЙ ПОРОДЫ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Shaydullin R.R.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Ganiyev A.S.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Kazan state agrarian university</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Cattle</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Animal genetics</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">genotypes</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Polymorphism</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">alleles</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1391</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_49986</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3225</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6088</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8724</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>5 tables, 14 ref.</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Presents the results of studies on the polymorphism and determining the frequency of occurrence of allelic variants in the gene Kappa-casein at 122 heifers, 142 fresh cows, 208 high yielding cows of black-motley breed. Heifers genotype gene Kappa-casein AA had 66,4 %, genotype AB was 30,3 % and the BB genotype — 3,3 %. The frequency of genotypes in fresh cows reached AA – 62,7 %, AB – 32,4 %, BB – 4,9 %, high yielding cows, respectively AA - 55,3 %, AB is 40,4 %, BB 4,3% of cows. In all studied animal groups the predominant is allele A gene Kappa-casein with frequency from 0,75 to 0,82. Statistical method of Hardy-Weinberg and χ2 method for detecting deviations of the empirical distribution of frequencies of genotypes of Kappa-casein from the theoretical showed that in a population of black-motley cattle of farms there is no statistically significant shift in genetic equilibrium according to none of the three genotypes at the locus of the gene Kappa-casein. The influence of genotypes on gene Kappa-casein on the main indicators of milk production of cows is studied. Based on the results of the DNA test, the animals were divided into three groups with genotypes AA, AB and BB. Cows with the genotype of Kappa-casein BB at the highest level of milk yield have better indicators of output of milk fat and protein.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Представлены результаты исследований по изучению полиморфизма и определению частоты встречаемости аллельных вариантов по гену каппа-казеина у 122 телок, 142 коров-первотелок, 208 высокопродуктивных коров черно-пестрой породы. У телок генотип гена каппа-казеина АА имели 66,4 %, генотип АВ 30,3 % и генотип ВВ 3,3 %. Частота генотипов у коров-первотелок достигла АА – 62,7 %, АВ – 32,4 %, ВВ – 4,9 %, у высокопродуктивных коров соответственно АА - 55,3 %, АВ 40,4 %, ВВ 4,3 % коров. Во всех изученных групп животных преобладает аллель А гена каппа-казеина с частотой от 0,75 до 0,82. Статистический метод Харди-Вайнберга и метод χ2 для выявления отклонений эмпирического распределения частот генотипов каппа-казеина от теоретического показал, что в популяции черно-пестрого скота хозяйства не имеется статистически достоверного сдвига генетического равновесия ни по одному из трех генотипов по локусу гена каппа-казеина. Изучено влияние генотипов по гену каппа-казеина на основные показатели молочной продуктивности коров. На основании результатов анализа ДНК животные были подразделены на три группы с генотипами АА, АВ и ВВ. коровы с генотипом каппа-казеина ВВ при наиболее высоком уровне удоя обладают лучшими показателями выхода молочного жира и белка.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik.ugsha.ru/contentse/3-15-Shaydullin.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.3(31)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>