<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X13329">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Studies of the process of formation and use of additional driving force of machine-tractor unit as a result of application of propulsion-rippers</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Исследования процесса образования и использования дополнительной  движущей силы машинно-тракторного агрегата в результате применения движителей-рыхлителей</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Mingalimov R.R.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Musin R.M.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Samara State Agricultural Academy</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">N01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">farm equipment</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Mechanization</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_25753</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4685</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Shares unit with propulsion-rippers, driven from PTO (PTO) through mechanical drive is proposed. Experimental guided unit was created on the basis of tractor T-25A and cultivator SCC-4.2V. Unlike serial cultivator, experimental cultivator has a propulsion-rippers, which through a chain transmission, gearbox and cardan transmission are driven from the tractor PTO. When moving the unit there is soil cultivation using passive working bodies. Propulsion-rippers create momentum and simultaneously loosen the soil on the trail of tractor. The reduction of traction resistance is due to the additional driving force from the propulsion-rippers, during the rotation from PTO of the tractor, through a chain transmission, gearbox and cardan transmission rippers interact with the soil, loosen it and due to the resistance forces prevent slipping of propulsion-rippers, and also help to reduce the passive resistance of the working bodies in the soil. In the present paper the authors developed a model of interaction of propulsion-ripper with the soil, which allows to determine optimal design, technology and operational parameters of the proposed technical means with the drum cam. The angle at which cam drum and angular velocity of the wheel at which occurs the maximum tangential traction of propulsion-ripper is justified. It is revealed that the installation angle of the eccentric drum depends on radius of the propulsion, radius of the drum, ength of the ripper, width of the propulsion, physico-mechanical properties of soil.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Предложен культиваторный агрегат с движителями-рыхлителями, приводимыми в движение от вала отбора мощности (ВОМ) через механический привод. Экспериментальный культиваторный агрегат созданна базе трактора T-25A и культиватора КРН-4,2. В отличие от серийного культиватора, экспериментальный культиватор имеет движители-рыхлители, которые через цепную передачу, редуктор и карданную передачу приводятся во вращение от ВОМ трактора. При движении агрегата производится культивация почвы с помощью пассивных рабочих органов. Движители-рыхлители, создают движущую силу и одновременно разрыхляют почву по следу трактора. Снижение тягового сопротивления происходит вследствие получения дополнительной движущей силы от движителей-рыхлителей, при вращении которых от вала отбора мощности трактора, через цепную передачу, редуктор и карданную передачу рыхлители взаимодействуют с почвой, разрыхляют ее и за счёт сил сопротивления препятствуют буксованию движителей-рыхлителей, а также способствуют снижению сопротивления пассивных рабочих органов в почве. В представленной статье авторами теоретически разработана модель взаимодействия движителя-рыхлителя с почвой, которая позволяет определить оптимальные конструктивно-технологические и эксплуатационные параметры предлагаемого технического средства с барабанным эксцентриком. Обоснован угол установки эксцентрикового барабана и угловая скорость колеса, при которой возникает максимальная касательная сила тяги движителя-рыхлителя. Выявлено, что угол установки эксцентрикового барабаназависит от радиуса движителя, радиуса барабана, длины рыхлителя, ширины движителя, физико-механических свойств почвы.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.1(29)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>