<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X11488">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">INFLUENCE OF PREDECESSORS AND MINERAL FERTILIZERS ON YIELD OF SPRING BARLEY</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ВЛИЯНИЕ ПРЕДШЕСТВЕННИКОВ И МИНЕРАЛЬНЫХ УДОБРЕНИЙ НА УРОЖАЙНОСТЬ ЯРОВОГО ЯЧМЕНЯ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Evdokimova M.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Mari State University</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Hordeum</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">crop rotation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">profitability</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Crop yield</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3660</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6662</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6214</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_10176</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>4 tables;12 ref.</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Due to the fact that in the cultivation of spring barley in the Republic of Mari El its soil and climatic conditions are not used in productive way, the objective of our research was to determine the best predecessor and study the influence of mineral fertilizers on the yield of barley. To achieve this goal it was necessary to solve the following tasks: to identify the influence of predecessors and mineral fertilizers on productivity of barley plants</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">to determine the recoupment of mineral fertilizers in the production of barley grain. Research was conducted by methods of two-factor field experience and laboratory testing according to generally accepted and recommended for zone techniques. The scheme of experiment:factor A - predecessors of barley</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">factor B - doses of mineral fertilizers.  The studies found that selection of the predecessor and certain combinations of fertilizers can significantly increase the efficiency of fertilizers, increase the production of agriculture.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">В связи с тем, что при возделывании ярового ячменя в Республике Марий Эл ее почвенно-климатические условия используются не продуктивно, целью наших исследований являлось установление лучшего предшественника и изучение влияния минеральных удобрений на урожайность ячменя. Для достижения поставленной цели необходимо было решить следующие задачи: выявить влияние предшественников и минеральных удобрений на продуктивность растений ячменя</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">определить окупаемость минеральных удобрений при производстве зерна ячменя. Исследования проводили методами полевого двухфакторного опыта и лабораторных анализов по общепринятым и рекомендованным для зоны методикам. Схема опыта: фактор А - предшественники ячменя</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">фактор В -дозы минеральных удобрений/ В результате исследований установлено, что путем подбора предшественника и определенных сочетаний удобрений можно значительно повысить эффективность удобрений, увеличить производство продукции земледелия.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.1(29)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>