<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X13326">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Determination of the optimal parameters haulm removing machine for sowing onion</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Определение оптимальных параметров ботвоудаляющей машины на посевах  лука</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Frolov D.I.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Kurochkin A.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Shaburova G.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Penza state technological university</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">N01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">farm equipment</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">weed control equipment</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">onions</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_25753</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_15296</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_12934</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">We confirmed in real conditions the possibility of application of the haulm machine to remove the haulm of onions and weeds during sowing before the harvest of onion and pearl onion and the determination of its optimal design and operating parameters. To achieve this goal the design of a haulm machine for removal of the leafy mass before the harvest of onion has been developed and manufactured. To determine the optimal parameters of a haulm machine laboratory and field studies were conducted. The experimental results were processed by the method of correlation and regression analysis. As a result there are dependencies of the completeness of the removal of haulm and weeds on setting angle of the blades, the height of installing of the working body relative to the surface of the field h, the traveling speed of the machine and the speed of the working bodies. Based on these dependencies, we managed to obtain optimal values of the structural kinematic parameters of a haulm machine under the fullness removal of leafy mass = 95...of 98,2 %. These values amounted to: = 52...56 deg,. h = 7...9 cm = 0,7...0,9 m/s and = 1500...2200 min-1.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Подтверждены в реальных условиях возможности применения ботвоудаляющей машины для удаления ботвы лука и сорных растений на посевах перед уборкой лука-репки и лука-севка и определение её оптимальных конструктивных и режимных параметров. Для достижения указанной цели была разработана конструкция и изготовлена ботвоудаляющая машина для удаления листостебельной массы перед уборкой лука. Для определения оптимальных параметров ботвоудаляющей машины были проведены лабораторнополевые исследования. Результаты экспериментальных исследований были обработаны методом корреляционно-регрессионного анализа. В итоге были получены зависимости полноты удаления ботвы лука и сорных растений от угла установки ножей, высоты установки рабочего органа относительно поверхности поля h, поступательной скорости машины и частоты вращения рабочих органов. На основе этих зависимостей удалось получить оптимальные значения конструктивно-кинематических параметров ботвоудаляющей машины при полноте удаления листостебельной массы = 95...98,2 %. Эти значения составили: = 52.56 град,. h = 7.9 см, = 0,7.0,9 м/с и = 1500.2200 мин-1.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.1(29)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>