<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X13485">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">SPREAD OF MASTITIS IN COWS IN FARMS OF ULYANOVSK REGION</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>РАСПРОСТРАНЕНИЕ МАСТИТА У КОРОВ В ХОЗЯЙСТВАХ УЛЬЯНОВСКОЙ ОБЛАСТИ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Теrеntyeva Natalya Yu.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Ermolaev Valery А.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L70</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Cows</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Milk performance</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Mammary glands</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">bovine mastitis</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Diagnosis</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">disease recognition</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1939</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_24276</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4562</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_9378</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2238</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3400</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>4 tables, 21 ref.</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Studied the incidence of mastitis of cows in Ulyanovsk region, defined microbial background under this disease, identified the sensitivity of highlighted microflora to antibiotics. Were analysed statistical data on the spread of mastitis for 2012-2014 provided by the veterinary department of the area, conducted a clinical examination of cows on three farms to identify the extent of damage to the breast. Studied microbial landscape with mastitis, for this  in accordance with "Guidelines for bacteriological examination of milk and udder secretions" tested the sample content of breast of animals down with subacute catarrhal-purulent mastitis.  As a result it was found out that according to the statistical data, the number of cases of mastitis cows relative to the existing population is small, and is only 2,5 to 3,02%. Mastitis was detected in 26,17-49,26% of cows. Subclinical form of mastitis thus dominates the clinical forms of the disease and is 60,0-83,75%. Clinically, the disease manifests itself in 16,25 to 44.68% of cows down with mastitis with prevalence of subacute catarrhal-purulent forms. Bacteriological examination of samples of secretion breast has allowed us to establish that microorganisms Staphylococcus aureus and Streptococcus pyogenes were the causative agents of mastitis of cows. Determining the sensitivity of isolated strains to different antibiotics it was found out that the growth of colonies of microorganisms suppressed  antibiotics of fluoride-quinolones series.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Изучали частоту заболеваемости коров маститом в Ульяновской области, определяли микробный фон при данной патологии, выявляли чувствительность выделенной микрофлоры к антибактериальным препаратам. Были проанализировали статистические данные по распространению маститов за 2012-2014 гг, предоставленные департаментом ветеринарии области, провели диспансеризацию коров в трех хозяйствах для выявления степени поражения молочной железы. Изучили микробный пейзаж при маститах, для чего в соответствии с «Методическими указаниями по бактериологическому исследованию молока и секрета вымени» протестировали пробы содержимого молочной железы от животных больных подострым катарально-гнойным маститом. В результате установили, что согласно представленным статистическим данным число заболевших маститом коров относительно имеющегося поголовья невелико, и составляет всего 2,5-3,02%. В то время как при проведении нами диспансеризации животных, маститы выявили у 26,17-49,26% коров. Субклиническая форма мастита при этом доминирует над клиническими формами заболевания и составляет 60,0-83,75%. Клинически заболевание проявляется у 16,25-44,68% больных маститом коров с преобладанием подострой катарально-гнойной формы. Бактериологические исследования проб секрета молочной железы позволило нам установить, что возбудителями маститов коров являлись микроорганизмы видов Staphylococcus aureus и Streptococcus pyogenes. Определяя чувствительность выделенных штаммов к различным антибиотикам выяснили, что рост колоний микроорганизмов подавляли антибиотики фторхинолового ряда.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik.ugsha.ru/contentse/2-15-%D0%A2%D0%B5r%D0%B5ntyeva.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.2(30)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>