<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X17558">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">THEORETICAL DESCRIPTION OF OPERATION OF DEVICE FOR TURNING GRAIN MATERIAL</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ТЕОРЕТИЧЕСКОЕ ОПИСАНИЕ РАБОТЫ УСТРОЙСТВА ДЛЯ ВОРОШЕНИЯ ЗЕРНОВОГО МАТЕРИАЛА</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Isayev Yury M.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Semashkin Nikolay M.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Коshkina Аnastasiya O.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2016-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">N20</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">farm equipment</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Mechanization</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Grain</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_25753</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4685</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3346</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Devices with working body in shape of a spiral are now widely used in agricultural production to move liquid or granular materials. However, the existing theoretical descriptions of such processes are not resolved accurately and require significant improvements. The most effective device for grain turning is a flexible spiral transport system. The main element of this system is spiral screw, made of special high-strength spring steel. During the designing of spiral-screw device, it is necessary to have a data on the pattern of interaction between modal parameters and kinematic characteristics of moved material. Correct theoretical solution of the considered problem is difficult due to complex movement of moved grain material. Device settings for turning of grain material in grain storages were analyzed. As a result of theoretical research of devices for turning of grainmaterial, movement speed of device on the pile of grain, speed of grain movement inside the device, and the nozzle pressure of the device on the output of grain were determined. The studies revealed that the convergence of theoretical and experimental results is not less than 95 %. It means that the proposed method of research of devices for grain turning is accurate, and proposed device quite justifies its purpose of grain turning to prevent it from hay-heating and spoiling. In this case the specific energy consumption for grain turning did not exceed 1,117 (kWh)/kg.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Устройства с рабочим органом в виде спирального в настоящее время широко применяют в сельскохозяйственном производстве для перемещения жидких и сыпучих материалов. Однако существующие теоретические описания таких процессов решены не достаточно точно и требуют существенных доработок. Наиболее эффективным устройством для ворошения зерновой насыпи, являются гибкие спиральные транспортные системы. Основной элемент такой системы – спиральный винт, который изготавливается из специальной высокопрочной пружинной стали. Проектируя спирально-винтовые устройства необходимо располагать данными о характере взаимодействия между его режимными параметрами и кинематическими характеристиками перемещаемого материала. Правильное теоретическое решение рассматриваемой задачи представляет трудности в связи со сложным движением перемещаемого зернового материала. Рассмотрены параметры устройства для ворошения зернового материала в зерноскладах. В результате проведенных теоретических исследований устройства для ворошения зернового материала, определены скорость перемещения устройства по насыпи зерна, скорость движения зерна внутри устройства, а также давление в сопле устройства при выходе зерна. В результате исследований выявлено, что сходимость результатов теоретических и экспериментальных составляет не менее 95 %. Это означает, что предложенная методика исследований устройства для ворошения зерна является достоверной, а предлагаемое устройство вполне оправдывает своё назначение – ворошение зерна, исключающее его самосогревание и порчу. При этом удельные энергозатраты на ворошение зерна не превысили 1,117 (кВт∙ч)/кг.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik.ugsha.ru/contentse/1-16-isayev.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.1(33)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>