<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X12953">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">EFFICACY OF MICRONUTRIENTS AND GROWTH REGULATORS ON PEAR IN THE ARID CONDITIONS OF ASTRAKHAN REGION</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ЭФФЕКТИВНОСТЬ ПРИМЕНЕНИЯ МИКРОУДОБРЕНИЙ И РЕГУЛЯТОРОВ РОСТА НА ГРУШЕ В ЗАСУШЛИВЫХ УСЛОВИЯХ АСТРАХАНСКОЙ ОБЛАСТИ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Ivanenko E.N.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Zaytseva V.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Caspian scientific research Institute of arid agriculture</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F61</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Pyrus communis</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">micronutrient fertilizers</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">plant growth substances</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Crop yield</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">keeping quality</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6391</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4806</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5968</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_10176</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4082</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>3 tables, 10 ref.</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">One of the requirements of the modern intensification of horticulture is the use of precision technology of cultivation of fruit crops. Namely, the use of foliar macro - and micronutrients, growth regulators in the cultivation. The purpose of this study was to substantiate the efficiency of foliar nutrition with biologically active substances, macro - and micronutrients on the background of mineral nutrition in plantings of pears. The study was carried out in 2013-2014 based on the experimental garden of Caspian scientific research Institute of arid agriculture, located in the second agro-climatic area of Astrakhan region. The object of study - the trees and fruits of pear variety Talgarskaya krasavitsa on seed stock of planting 2003 with the layout 8×4 m. As a top dressing we used agrochemicals: a 0,5% aqueous solution of a special fertilizer with a complete set of essential nutrients and micronutrients plantafol, growth regulators Obereg (1 ml/5 l of water) and "Zavyaz plodovaya" (10 g/5 l water). It was found out that foliar treatment with growth regulators and micronutrients rather poorly intensified growth processes of pear trees. The increase in circumference of trunk and leaf area of experienced trees were smaller than trees in the control. Experimental data indicate that foliar treatments had a positive effect on the productivity of the studied varieties. The yield increase from the use of drugs was 2,2-13,0 t/ha. The increased supply of mineral macro - and micronutrients and activation of physiological processes as a result of application of growth regulators has helped to improve the commercial quality of the fruit. Drugs "Zavyaz plodovaya" and plantafol provided the greatest yield of the higher and first grade (80,1-82,4%), whereas in the control this rate was 79.8%. Thus, the use of foliar treatments of growth regulators and micronutrients suitable for fruit-bearing pear plantings, because the drugs significantly increase productivity, ensure high quality products.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Одним из требований интенсификации современного садоводства является использование высокоточных технологий возделывания плодовых культур. А именно, применение в технологии возделывания некорневых подкормок макро- и микроэлементами, регуляторами роста. Целью наших исследований являлось обоснование перспективности использования некорневого питания биологически активными веществами, макро- , микроудобрениями на фоне минерального питания в насаждениях груши. Исследования проводили в 2013-2014 гг. на базе опытного сада Прикаспийского НИИ аридного земледелия, расположенного во втором агроклиматическом районе Астраханской области. Объект исследования - деревья и плоды груши сорта Талгарская красавица на семенном подвое посадки 2003 года со схемой размещения 8×4 м. В качестве некорневых подкормок использовали агрохимикаты: 0,5%-ный водный раствор специального удобрения с полным набором основных питательных элементов и микроэлементов плантафол, регуляторы роста «Оберег» (1 мл/5 л воды) и «Завязь плодовая» (10 г/5 л воды). Было установлено, что некорневые обработки регуляторами роста и микроудобрениями довольно слабо активизировали ростовые процессы деревьев груши. Прирост окружности штамба и площадь листьев опытных деревьев были меньше, чем у деревьев в контроле. Экспериментальные данные свидетельствуют, что некорневые обработки положительно сказались на продуктивности исследуемого сорта. Прибавка урожая от применения препаратов составила 2,2-13,0 т/га. Усиление минерального питания макро- и микроудобрениями и активизация физиологических процессов в результате применения регуляторов роста позволили улучшить товарные качества плодов. Препараты «Завязь плодовая» и плантафол обеспечили наибольший выход плодов высшего и первого сорта (80,1-82,4%), тогда как в контроле этот показатель составил 79,8%. Таким образом, использование некорневых обработок регуляторами роста и микроудобрениями целесообразно на плодоносящих насаждениях груши, поскольку препараты существенно увеличивают урожайность, обеспечивают высокое качество продукции.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik.ugsha.ru/contentse/3-15-Ivanenko.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.3(31)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>