<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X13515">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">CONCEPTUAL APPROACHES TO THE CREATION AND MAINTENANCE OF THE RED BOOK OF SOILS OF ULYANOVSK REGION</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>КОНЦЕПТУАЛЬНЫЕ ПОДХОДЫ К СОЗДАНИЮ И ВЕДЕНИЮ КРАСНОЙ КНИГИ ПОЧВ УЛЬЯНОВСКОЙ ОБЛАСТИ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Grigoryan Boris R</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Кulagina Valentina I.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Karpov Аlexander V</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Institute of ecology and environmental sciences</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Institute of ecology and subsoil use AS RT</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">P01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">P30</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">agricultural soils</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Soil conservation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">soil resources</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">environmental protection</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33934</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7165</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7187</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_15898</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The necessity and possibility of creation of the Red book of soils of Ulyanovsk region is explained, to develop a possible structure of the red book of soils of Ulyanovsk region, including the amendments to the concept of separation of categories of soils. The object of analysis was the data for the study of the soil cover of Ulyanovsk region. The article presents the analysis of the conducted studies of the soils of Ulyanovsk region over a long period. The urgency and necessity of creation of the Red book of soils of Ulyanovsk region is explained. Background and the possibility of implementing this project are objectively described as the study of soil, including in Simbirsk province, formed the basis of the work of Vasily Vasilyevich Dokuchayev "Russian Chernozem" (1883), the year of release of which is the year of the beginning of the soil science. The need for additional work on the identification of individual soils for protection is indicated. In the structure of the Red book of soils of Ulyanovsk region it is proposed to distinguish the following categories: 1. Rare soil 2. Endangered soil. 3. Soil of memorial value. 4. Soil of high culture of farming. 5. Soil – the monitoring object. 6. Samples. It is noted that the materials of the Red book of soils will allow to track changes, and the level of conservation of soils and can be used in the analysis of the functioning of soils of agro-ecosystems and the basis for the development of measures to restore soil fertility.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Обоснована необходимость и возможность создания Красной книги почв Ульяновской области, разработать предполагаемую структуру Красной книги почв Ульяновской области, включая поправки к концепции выделения категорий почв. Объектом анализа являлись данные по изучению почвенного покрова Ульяновской области. В статье приведен анализ проведенных исследований почв Ульяновской области за длительный период. Обоснована актуальность и необходимость создания Красной книги почв Ульяновской области. Объективно изложены предпосылки и возможность реализации данного проекта, поскольку изучение черноземов, в том числе в Симбирской губернии, легло в основу труда Василия Васильевича Докучаева «Русский чернозем» (1883 г), год выхода которого в свет и считается годом начала научного почвоведения. Указывается необходимость дополнительной работы по выявлению отдельных почв, подлежащих охране. В структуре Красной книги почв Ульяновской области предлагается выделить следующие категории: 1. Редкие почвы 2. Исчезающие почвы. 3. Почвы мемориального значения. 4. Почвы высокой культуры земледелия. 5. Почвы – объекты мониторинга. 6. Эталоны. Отмечается, что материалы Красной книги почв позволят проследить изменения и степень сохранности почв и могут быть использованы при анализе функционирования почв агроэкосистем и основой при разработке мер по восстановлению почвенного плодородия.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik.ugsha.ru/contentse/3-15-Grigoryan.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.3(31)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>