<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X17308">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">FORMATION OF MEAT PRODUCTIVITY OF PIGS WHILE INSERTION OF FEED ADDITIVES «TETRA +» AND «GLIMALASK» IN THE DIET</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ФОРМИРОВАНИЕ МЯСНОЙ ПРОДУКТИВНОСТИ СВИНЕЙ ПРИ ВВЕДЕНИИ В РАЦИОН КОРМОВЫХ ДОБАВОК «ТЕТРА+» И «ГЛИМАЛАСК»</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Serdyukova Yuliya А.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Volgograd State Agrarian University</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2016-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L02</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Swine</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Feed additives</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">rations</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">fats</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7555</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2827</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6461</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2816</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>3 tables, 7 ref.</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">We investigated the effect of feed additives «Tetra +» and «Glimalask» on meat productivity of pigs. Scientific and economic experiment was held in stud farmkolkhoz named after Lenin in Surovikinskiy district of Volgograd region. For this purpose, three groups of pigs of large white breed with 20 animals each were formed in accordance with the pairs-analogues method. Feed additives were inserted into the diets of young pigs of experimental groups: I experimental - «Tetra +» 	in amounts of 40 kg/t, II experimental – «Glimalask» in amounts of 40 kg/t. The results of research revealed that the main indicators of meat productivity (pre-slaughter live weight, slaughter weight, hot carcass weight,carcass yield, area of «muscle eye») of young pigs of experimental groups outperformed analogues from the control group. Analysis of the morphological composition of carcasses revealed that piglets of experimental groups surpassed the control group upon indications of chilled carcass weight – by 5,58 and 3,11 kg, beef yield – by 1,39 and 0,82 %, fleshing index – by 0,18 and 0,07 %. The data obtained by chemical analysis of the average sample of carcasses pulp of experimental animals, indicates that the meat of young pigs of experimental groups compared to the control group, amount of dry matter was more by 0,88 and 0,72 %, protein – by 0,78 and 0,58%, fat – by 0,08 by 0,11 %, organic matter – by 0,86 and 0,69 %. On the basis of conducted research it is possible to concluded that feed additives «Tetra +» and «Glimalask» inserted into the diets of fattening young pigs, in comparison to the control group, contributed to the increase of meat productivity of animals.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Было изучено действие кормовых добавок «Тетра+» и «Глималаск» на мясную продуктивность свиней. Научно-хозяйственный опыт был проведен в ПЗК им. Ленина Суровикинского района Волгоградской области. Для этого были сформированы по методу пар-аналогов три группы подсвинков крупной белой породы по 20 голов в каждой. В рационы молодняка свиней опытных групп были введены кормовые добавки: I опытной - «Тетра +» в количестве 40кг/т , II опытной – «Глималаск» в количестве 40кг/т. По результатам исследований было установлено, что по основным показателям мясной продуктивности (предубойная живая масса, убойная масса, масса парной туши, выход туши, площадь «мышечного глазка») молодняк свиней опытных групп превосходил аналогов контрольной группы. Анализ морфологического состава туш показал, что молодняк свиней опытных групп, превосходил контрольную по массе охлажденной туши – на 5,58 и 3,11 кг, по выходу мяса – на 1,39 и 0,82 %, по индексу мясности – на 0,18 и 0,07 %. Полученные данные по химическому анализу средней пробы мякоти туш подопытных животных, свидетельствуют, что в мясе молодняка свиней опытных групп, по сравнению с контрольной группой, содержаниесухого вещества было больше на 0,88 и 0,72 %, белка – на 0,78 и 0,58%, жира – на 0,08 и 0,11 %, органического вещества – на 0,86 и 0,69 %. На основании проведенных исследований можно сделать заключение, что кормовые добавки «Тетра+» и «Глималаск» вводимые в рационы откармливаемого молодняка свиней, в сравнении с контрольной группой, способствовали повышению мясной продуктивности животных.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik.ugsha.ru/contentse/1-16-serdyukova.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.1(33)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>