<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X17293">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">BLOOD MINERAL METABOLISM OF COWS, ILL WITH PURULENT PODODERMATITIS</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>МИНЕРАЛЬНЫЙ ОБМЕН КРОВИ У КОРОВ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="">
      <dcterms:alternative>БОЛЬНЫХ ГНОЙНЫМ ПОДОДЕРМАТИТОМ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Маryin Еvgeny М.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Ermolaev Valery А.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Idogov Valery V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Federal Service for veterinary and phytosanitary surveillance in Ulyanovsk region</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2016-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L70</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L73</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Cows</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">blood</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">MINERAL METABOLISM</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">inflammation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">pododermatitis</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1939</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_959</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4850</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3856</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_16800</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Aim of this work was the research of biologically draining sorption drugs influence on the parameters of blood mineral metabolism of cows with purulent pododermatitis. Experimental research was carried out on basis of LLC PAC «Krasnaya Zvezda» in Ulyanovsk district of Ulyanovsk region. We selected 15 animals with diseases of distal extremities, with purulent pododermatitis diagnosis among examined animals of black-motley breed in age from 4 to 10 years old with live weight of 500...550 kg. Biochemical studies were performed before treatment, on the 7th, 14th, 21st and 28th days. Mineral elements were determined in plasma, which was prepared by centrifugation of experimental animals’ stabilized blood, on Biochem SA automatic biochemical analyzer. received digital material was subjected to statistical processing by computer program «Statistika 6». Established character of changes in dynamic of experimental animals’ biochemical indicators during treatment, namely, increased content of calcium, phosphorus, sodium, magnesium, decreased potassium levels may indicate a decrease of acute purulent inflammation intensity, the predominance of reduction processes in tissues of pathological focus and a favorable progress of the disease. In the control group, some parameters were less pronounced than in the experimental groups. It should be noted that these mineral metabolism changes can be associated with an earlier resolution of infection in area of pathological focus and an earlier normalization of metabolic processes in affected tissues of the experimental groups animals.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Целью данной работы явилось изучение влияния биологически дренирующих сорбционных препаратов на показатели минеральногоо обмена крови у коров с гнойными пододерматитами. Экспериментальные исследования проводили на базе ООО ПСК «Красная Звезда» Ульяновского района Ульяновской области. Из числа обследованных животных чёрно-пёстрой породы в возрасте от 4 до 10 лет, с живой массой 500…550 кг, было отобрано 15 с заболеваниями дистального отдела конечностей, с диагнозом гнойный пододерматит. Биохимические исследования проводили до начала лечения, на 7-е, 14-е, 21-е и 28-е сутки. Минеральные элементы определяли в плазме, которую готовили путём центрифугирования стабилизированной крови подопытных животных, на автоматическом биохимическом анализаторе Biochem SA. Полученный цифровой материал подвергали статистической обработки на компьютерной программе «Statistika 6». Установленный характер изменений в динамике биохимических показателей у подопытных животных в процессе лечения, а именно, увеличение содержания кальция, фосфора, натрия, магния, снижение уровня калия может свидетельствовать о снижении интенсивности острого гнойного воспаления, преобладании восстановительных процессов в тканях патологического очага и благоприятном течении заболевания. В контрольной группе отдельные показатели были менее выражены, чем в опытных группах. Следует отметить, что данные изменения минерального обмена могут быть обусловлены более ранним купированием местных воспалительных процессов в области патологического очага и более ранней нормализацией обменных процессов в поражённых тканях у животных опытных групп.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik.ugsha.ru/contentse/1-16-maryin.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.1(33)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>