<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X12757">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">EFFICIENCY OF SYSTEMS OF THE BASIC SOIL CULTIVATION IN THE LINK OF THE CROP ROTATION WITH GREEN MANURE STEAM</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ЭФФЕКТИВНОСТЬ СИСТЕМ ОСНОВНОЙ ОБРАБОТКИ ПОЧВЫ В ЗВЕНЕ СЕВООБОРОТА С СИДЕРАЛЬНЫМ ПАРОМ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Kulikova A.Kh.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Dozorov A.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Zakharov N.G.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Markova N.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Polnyakov M.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2012-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F07</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">arable soils</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Tillage</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">crop rotation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Crop yield</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_568</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7771</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6662</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_10176</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The purpose of the work - to study the influence of basic cultivation systems of the soil and their impact on main characteristics of the black soil fertility and also the formation of yield in the crop rotation with green fallow. Our field rotation consisted from six crops - winter wheat - permanent grasses - spring wheat - pea - oats (the cultures are placed in the order of succession). The scheme of the experiment included four systems of basic soil cultivation: with the turn of soil layer, surface cultivation and combined in the crop rotation. We have discovered that the tillage with a turn of soil layer and combined systems of soil cultivation lead to the formation of optimal physical and chemical states of the soil in the crop rotation with green fallow. That combination of cultivation systems are favorable for humification of the soil organic matter and positive balance of the humus. A tillage with the turn of soil layer and combined system of soil cultivation are effective in the defense of crops against weeds. The conditions of forest-steppe of the Volga region allow to form the productivity of winter wheat on green fallow more than three and t/ha. During years 2007-2009 average yield was 3,20 t/ha. Higher efficiency of spring wheat was marked on layer-turn and combined soil cultivation system: 1,87 t/ha and 1,84 t/ha of grain accordingly. The system of the basic soil cultivation is more effective in the cultivation of spring wheat and turn-layer in winter wheat sowed after green fallow.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Цель работы - изучить влияние систем основной обработки почвы и их воздействие на основные параметры плодородия чернозема выщелоченного, формирование урожайности и продуктивность звена севооборота с сидеральным паром. Исследования проводились в 6-ти польном сидеральном зернотравяном севообороте: пар сидеральный - озимая пшеница- многолетние травы (выводное поле) - яровая пшеница - горох- овес. Схема опыта предусматривает 4 системы основной обработки почвы: отвальную (ПЛН 4-35), мелкую (БДМ 3х4), комбинированную в севообороте (под викоовсяную смесь плуг со стойкой СибИМЭ, озимую и яровую пшеницу БДМ 3х4) и поверхностную (КПШ-5 + БИГ-3А). Установлено, что оптимальные агрофизическое и агрохимическое состояние почвы в звене с сидеральным паром обеспечивали отвальная и комбинированная в севообороте системы обработки. При сочетании в севообороте систем основной обработки в соответствии с требованиями культур в пахотном слое создаются более благоприятные условия для гумификации поступающего в почву органического вещества, в результате чего создается бездефицитный баланс гумуса. Задачам борьбы с сорными растениями в посевах культур звена севооборота с сидеральным паром в большей степени отвечают также отвальная и комбинированная в севообороте системы обработки почвы. Условия лесостепи Поволжья позволяют формировать урожайность озимой пшеницы по сидеральному пару до 3 и более тонн на одном гектаре. За 2007-2009 гг. по отвальной системе обработки она составила 3,20 т/га. Более высокая продуктивность яровой пшеницы отмечалась по отвальной и комбинированной в севообороте системам обработки почвы: 1,87 т/га и 1,84 т/га зерна соответственно. При возделывании яровой пшеницы в звене севооборота с сидеральным паром экономически более эффективной является комбинированная в севообороте система основной обработки почвы, озимой пшеницы - отвальная под сидеральный пар.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.3(19)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>