<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X12748">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">METHODS OF BUDGET PLANNING AT THE ENTERPRISES OF THE AGROINDUSTRIAL COMPLEX</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>МЕТОДИКА БЮДЖЕТНОГО ПЛАНИРОВАНИЯ НА  ПРЕДПРИЯТИЯХ АПК</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Dozorova T.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Hirova D.R.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2012-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">E10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Planning</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Dairy cattle</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">evaluation techniques</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">agricultural economics</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5951</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2108</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_29775</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8672</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The methodological basis of the development of the operational budget in the agricultural organizations are considered by the example of dairy cattle breeding LLC «Spring», which is a separate center of financial responsibility in the General system of budget planning of the enterprise. It is necessary to take into account the fact that a well-designed scheme of formation of the budget contributes to the implementation of two of the most important functions of management: planning and control. With a view to monitoring of the implementation of the indicators of developed budgets, of accounting deviations from the budget indicators and of the identification of the reasons of their occurrence in the enterprise the special form of the report on the implementation of the budget costs should be used there. These reports are compiled by the centers of the financial responsibility and for a more accurate factor analysis take into account the deviation of the indicators, both in physical and in cost expression. Cost management through the budgeting process with the use of accounting information allows you to prevent unnecessary losses, to increase the production efficiency, to control the expenses of productive resources and to use them rationally in the future. The budget, being an integral part of the management control, creates an objective basis for the assessing of the results of activities of the enterprise as a whole and its separate subdivisions.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Методические основы разработки операционного бюджета в сельскохозяйственных организациях рассмотрены на примере отрасли молочного скотоводства ООО «Весна», которая является отдельным центром финансовой ответственности в общей системе бюджетного планирования предприятия. Необходимо брать во внимание то, что правильно выстроенная схема формирования бюджетов способствует реализации двух важнейших функций управления: планирования и контроля.  С целью контроля выполнения показателей разработанных бюджетов, учета отклонений от бюджетных показателей и выявления причин их возникновения на предприятии должна быть использована определенная форма отчета о выполнении бюджета затрат. Данные отчеты составляются центрами финансовой ответственности и для более точного факторного анализа учитывают отклонения показателей, как в натуральном, так и в стоимостном выражении. Управление затратами посредством бюджетирования с применением учетной информации позволяет предотвратить ненужные потери, повысить эффективность производства, контролировать расходы производственных ресурсов и рационально использовать их в будущем. Бюджет, являясь составной частью управленческого контроля, создает объективную основу оценки результатов деятельности предприятия в целом и отдельных его подразделений.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.2(18)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>