<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X12847">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">CRYSTALLOGENIC PROPERTIES OF MILK OF COWS WITH MASTITIS</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>КРИСТАЛЛОГЕННЫЕ СВОЙСТВА МОЛОКА КОРОВ ПРИ МАСТИТАХ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Маrtusevich A.K.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Samodelkin A.G.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Shubina O.I.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Nizhny Novgorod State Agricultural Academy</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Privolzhsky Federal medical research centre» of the Ministry of health of Russia</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Kirov state medical Academy</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Cows</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">bovine mastitis</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">milk</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">crystallization</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1939</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_9378</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4826</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1994</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The aim of the study was to study the characteristics of dehydration structuring of milk of cows with mastitis. It was performed a comparative study of crystallogenic and initiating properties of milk of 20 healthy cows examined for the presence of mastitis, and 35 cows with subclinical or manifestirebuli mastitis. Analysis of crystallogenic and initiating properties of milk was produced with the use of a number of semi-quantitative indicators. The range used for thesi-graphic test of basic substances were included: 0,45%, 0,9% and 3% solutions of sodium chloride and a 0.1H sodium hydroxide solution. Relevant parameters for the fullest possible accounting of the characteristics of the crystal scopic and thesi-graphic facies included crystallizability of sediment, characteristic microscopic zones, the correctness of the morphology and arrangement of individual elements and their groups, texture features of facies and other parameters. Statistical processing of results was performed using Statistica 6.0. the studies revealed that the presence of mastitis causes strengthening of crystallogenic activity of milk, which is manifested in a sharp increase of the index of structure and crystallizability of  biomaterial, and in violation of the correctness of structuring, as evidenced by the increase in the intensity of destruction of elements. Overall, on the basis of morphological data and visualations assessment it can be concluded that crystallogenic properties of milk for mastitis significantly transform that has a pathogenetic and diagnostic value.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Целью исследования служило изучение особенностей дегидратационной структуризации молока коров при мастите. Было выполнено сравнительное исследование кристаллогенных и инициирующих свойств молока 20 здоровых коров, обследованных на наличие мастита, а также 35 коров, имеющих субклинический или манифестировавший мастит. Анализ кристаллогенных и инициирующих свойств молока производили с использованием ряда полуколичественных показателей. В спектр использованных для тезиграфического теста базисных веществ были включены: 0,45%, 0,9% и 3% растворы хлорида натрия, а также 0,1Н раствор гидроксида натрия. Параметры, значимые для максимально полного учета характеристик кристаллоскопической и тезиграфической фации, включали кристаллизуемость биосубстрата, характеристику зон микропрепарата, правильность морфологии и расположения отдельных элементов и их групп, особенности текстуры фации и другие параметры. Статистическую обработку результатов проводили с использованием программы Statistica 6.0. исследования позволили установить, что наличие мастита обуславливает усиление кристаллогенной активности молока, что проявляется в резком увеличении индекса структурности и кристаллизуемости биоматериала, а также в нарушении правильности структуризации, о чем свидетельствует нарастание выраженности деструкции элементов. В целом, на основании данных морфологической и визуаметрической оценки можно заключить, что кристаллогенные свойства молока при мастите существенно трансформируются, что имеет патогенетическое и диагностическое значение.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik.ugsha.ru/contentse/2-15-%D0%9C%D0%B0rtusevich.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.2(30)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>