<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X19264">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">ECONOMICLY-USEFUL QUALITIES AND GENETIC PARAMETERS OF HIGHLY PRODUCTIVE HERD OF LLCSTUD FARM «PUSHKINSKOE» IN NIZHNY NOVGOROD REGION</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ХОЗЯЙСТВЕННО-ПОЛЕЗНЫЕ КАЧЕСТВА И ГЕНЕТИЧЕСКИЕ ПАРАМЕТРЫ ВЫСОКОПРОДУКТИВНОГО СТАДА ООО ПЛЕМЗАВОД «ПУШКИНСКОЕ» НИЖЕГОРОДСКОЙ ОБЛАСТИ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Vоrobyeva Natalya V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Коmissarova Таtyana N.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Shishkin Аnton V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Nizhny Novgorod State Agricultural Academy</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2016-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Cows</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">body weight</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Milk yield</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">reproductive performance</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Bulls</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1939</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_15846</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_15998</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6510</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1148</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>2 tables. 7 ref. DOI: 10.18286/1816-4501-2016-2-117-122</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Through the use of methods of accumulation and reproductive cross breeding and breeding in «itself» a highly productive herd of cows was created in LLC stud farm «Pushkinskoe». We used black - motley cows of local origin, local and Holstein bulls tested on progeny. The offspring by the age of 15 months had a live weight of 400 - 416 kg. Cows of the herd have a productivity of 10 thousand kg of milk, with 3.7% fat content. They are characterized by high coefficient of lactation persistency. The coefficient of milking capacity in the herd is high, for the first-calf heifers it was 1343 - 1726 kg, for the full-grown cows top producers - 2000-2244 kg. All cows of stud farm are characterized by proportional but more angular than the Holstein cows body build, long, wide and deep body, even topline with voluminous middle part of the body, muscularity is insufficient, but appropriate for the dairy type of cattle. 83-95% of cows have optimal size, the udder bottom is smooth. Half of the cows have the milk flow rate 2 kg/minute or more, there are cows with greater milk flow rate 2,20 – 2,75 kg/minute. The calf crop in recent years was 90%. Service period for appraisal lasts 90 - 97 days. Genotype is determined by specific bulls and lines. Livestock belongs to three genealogical lines: Vis Ideal, Reflection of Sovering and Pabst Governor, most of the livestock of Vis Ideal line is presented by daughters of great grandsons of bull Elevation - 1491007. Thus, in LLC «Pushkinskoe» during 20 years of deep selection work with a sufficient food reserve there was obtained the cattle livestock exceeding the requirements of black-motley breed on productive and genealogical parameters.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Путем использования методов поглотительного и воспроизводительного скрещиваний и разведения в «себе»  создано высокопродуктивное стадо коров в ООО племзавод «Пушкинское». Использовались черно-пестрые коровы местного происхождения голштинские и местные быки, проверенные по потомству. Потомство к возрасту 15 месяцев имело живую массу 400- 416 кг, телки в этом возрасте случались. Коровы стада имеют продуктивность -  10 тыс. кг молока, с содержанием жира 3,7%. Характеризуются высоким коэффициентом постоянства лактации. Коэффициент молочности в стаде высокий, по первотелкам составил 1343-1726 кг, по полновозрастным коровам рекордисткам - 2000-2244 кг. Все коровы племзавода характеризуются пропорциональным, но более угловатым, чем голштины, телосложением, длинным широким и глубоким туловищем, ровной линией верха с объемистой средней частью туловища, обмускулистость недостаточная, но соответствующая молочному типу скота. 83-95% коров имеют оптимальные размеры, дно вымени у коров ровное. У половины коров скорость молокоотдачи составляет 2 кг/минуту и более, имеются коровы с большей скоростью молокоотдачи 2,20- 2,75 кг/минуту. Выход телят в последние годы составил 90%. Сервис период по бонитировке продолжается 90- 97 дней. Генотип определяется конкретными быками и линиями. Поголовье принадлежит к трем генеалогическим линиям: Вис Айдиала, Рефлекшн Соверинга и Пабст Говернор большая часть поголовья линии Вис Айдиал представлена дочерями правнуков быка Элевейшн- 1491007. Таким образом, в ООО «Пушкинское» за 20 лет глубокой селекционной работы с достаточной кормовой базой получено поголовье крупного рогатого скота, превосходящее по продуктивным и генеалогическим параметрам требования черно-пестрой породы.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik.ugsha.ru/contentse/2-16-Vorobyeva.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.2(34)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>