<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X13298">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">RESULT OF LABORATORY RESEARCH OF TECHNOLOGY OF PROCESSING PIG MANURE IN AEROTANK USING CIRCULAR CLARIFIERS</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>РЕЗУЛЬТАТ ЛАБОРАТОРНЫХ ИССЛЕДОВАНИЙ ТЕХНОЛОГИИ ПЕРЕРАБОТКИ СВИНОГО НАВОЗА В АЭРОТЕНКЕ С ИСПОЛЬЗОВАНИЕМ ЦИКЛИЧЕСКИХ ОТСТОЙНИКОВ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Shalavina E.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Bryukhanov A.Yu.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Institute of agro-engineering and environmental problems of agricultural production</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Animal Husbandry</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">animal manures</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Agricultural research</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Environmental impact assessment</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8532</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_27876</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8679</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33483</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The developed technology of biological treatment of pig manure in the aerotank using primary circular clarifiers allows to concentrate the nutrients in the solid fraction and to obtain a clarified liquid, suitable for purification on filtration fields. The research was conducted at one of the pig farms of the Leningrad region and in the laboratory. All stages of biological treatment technology for the purpose of determining the loss in weight, total nitrogen and total phosphorus were investigated. The greatest mass loss was observed under a long-term incubation by lowering the moisture content. Losses amounted to 46,31% (2,8 kg). At the stage of aeration of secondary sedimentation the loss of mass was 15,41% (1,9 kg) due to evaporation during aeration clarified liquid. At the stage of primary sedimentation the amount of mass loss (1,9% - 0,3 kg). The total mass loss - 25% (5 kg). The greatest losses of total nitrogen were observed at the stage of aeration with secondary sedimentation – 25,38% (23637 mg), and lowest at the stage of primary sedimentation – 1,51% (791 mg). The total losses of total nitrogen amounted to 19.6%.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Разработанная технология биологической очистки свиного навоза в аэротенке с использованием первичных циклических отстойников позволяет сконцентрировать питательные вещества в твердой фракции и получить осветленную жидкость, пригодную для доочистки на полях фильтрации. Исследования проводились на одном из свинокомплексов Ленинградской области и в лабораторных условиях. Были исследованы все стадии технологии биологической очистки с целью определения потерь по массе, общего азота и общего фосфора. Наибольшие потери массы наблюдались на стадии длительного выдерживания за счет понижения влажности осадка. Потери составили 46,31% (2,8 кг). На стадии аэрации с вторичной седиментацией потери массы составили 15,41% (1,9 кг) за счет активного испарения при аэрировании осветленной жидкости. На стадии первичной седиментации величина потерь массы (1,9% - 0,3 кг). Суммарные потери массы во всей технологии составили 25% (5 кг). Наибольшие потери общего азота наблюдались на стадии аэрации со вторичной седиментацией – 25,38% (23637 мг), наименьшие – на стадии первичной седиментации – 1,51% (791 мг). Суммарные потери общего азота составили 19,6%.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik.ugsha.ru/contentse/3-15-Shalavin.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.3(31)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>