<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X12836">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">AGE-RELATED CHANGES IN THE EXPRESSION OF GLIAL FIBRILLARY ACIDIC PROTEIN IN THE BRAIN OF RATS CHRONICALLY EXPOSED TO CADMIUM</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ВОЗРАСТНЫЕ ИЗМЕНЕНИЯ ЭКСПРЕССИИ ГЛИАЛЬНОГО ФИБРИЛЛЯРНОГО КИСЛОГО БЕЛКА В МОЗГЕ КРЫС ПРИ ХРОНИЧЕСКОМ ВОЗДЕЙСТВИИ КАДМИЯ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Sukharenko E.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Nedzbetsky  V.S.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Маksimov V.I.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>FSBEI HPE &amp;quot</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Kerch state Maritime technological University</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Dnepropetrovsk national university</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>FSBEI HPE &amp;quot</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Moscow state Academy of veterinary medicine and biotechnology named after K. I. Skryabin&amp;quot</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate />
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L50</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Cadmium</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Rats</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">perinatal period</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">age differences</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1178</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6464</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_29378</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33931</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Cadmium is one of the most toxic heavy metals for most phylogenetic groups of vertebrates. Ions Cd2+ have a negative impact on many physiological and biochemical processes of the brain, including in the early periods of development of the organism. A study of chronic exposure to low doses of cadmium on the state of the astrocytes of the brain of animals in the period from 28 to 70 days of postnatal development was carried out on Wistar rats in the laboratories of the Department of Biophysics and biochemistry of Dnepropetrovsk national University (Ukraine). Control group rats (n=36) was kept on a standard diet, the experimental group (n=36) received a solution of CdCl2 in drinking water at a concentration of 10 μm. The expression and distribution of the marker of astrocytes – glial fibrillary acidic protein (GFAP) – in the brain (the hippocampus, the cerebellum, the cerebral cortex) was determined by the method of immunoblotting. It is established  that the ions Cd2+ cause changes in the content of both soluble and filament forms of GFAP and induce proteolytic degradation of intermediate filaments. Intoxication with cadmium for 6 weeks leads to a significant (P</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Кадмий является одним из наиболее токсичных тяжелых металлов для большинства филогенетических групп позвоночных. Ионы Cd2+ оказывают негативное воздействие на многие физиологические и биохимические процессы головного мозга, в том числе и в ранние периоды развития организма. Исследование хронического влияния малых доз кадмия на состояние астроцитов головного мозга животных в период с 28-го по 70-й дни постнатального развития проводили на крысах линии Wistar в лабораториях кафедры биофизики и биохимии Днепропетровского национального университета (Украина). Контрольная группа крыс (n=36) содержалась в условиях стандартной диеты, экспериментальная группа (n=36) получала раствор CdCl2 с питьевой водой в концентрации 10 мкМ. Методом иммуноблотинга определяли экспрессию и распределение маркера астроцитов – глиального фибриллярного кислого белка (ГФКБ) – в отделах головного мозга (гиппокампе, мозжечке, коре больших полушарий). Установлено, что ионы Cd2+ вызывают изменения в содержании как растворимой, так и филаментной форм ГФКБ, а также индуцируют протеолитическую деградацию промежуточных филаментов. Интоксикация кадмием на протяжении 6 недель приводит к достоверному (Р</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik.ugsha.ru/contentse/2-15-Sukharenko.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.2(30)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>