<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X12073">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Effects of systems of tillage of crop on yield and product quality at the level of crop rotation pea-oats</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Влияние систем обработки почвы на урожайность культур и качество продукции в звене севооборота горох—овес</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Polnyakov M.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Kulikova A.Kh.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Zakharov N.G.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F07</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">arable soils</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Tillage</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">crop rotation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Crops</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_568</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7771</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6662</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1972</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>4 tables, 20 ref.</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang=" ">Tillage is the fundamental basis of farming and the most powerful impact on the fertility of the soil, and consequently, crop yield and product quality. The goal of the research was to study the efficiency of primary processing in the cultivation of peas and oats at the level of crop rotation. Last are some of the major crops in the Middle Volga region, with important food and feed value. Studies were conducted in the field largeplot experience, where 4 tillage systems were studied: moldboard, small, combined in a crop rotation and superficial. The results showed that on leached Chernozem soils of foreststeppe of the Middle Volga region in the link of crop rotation pea— oats it is advisable to carry out combined in crop rotation tillage, combining the use of moldboard processing to a depth of 25 - 27 cm by unit PLN-4-35 for peas and fine processing of disk tool BDM 3x4 to a depth of 12-15 cm for oats. This processing system helps to create optimal soil conditions of plant growth and yield formation which is higher than in other variants (shallow and superficial processing) in the cultivation of peas by 0.26-0,37 t/ha, oats - 0,28 - 1,33 t/ha</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Обработка почвы является фундаментальной основой земледелия и средством наиболее сильного воздействия на плодородие почвы, а следовательно, на урожайность культур и качество продукции. В связи с этим целью исследования являлось изучение эффективности основной обработки при возделывании гороха и овса в звене севооборота. Последние являются одними из основных культур в Среднем Поволжье, имеющих важное продовольственное и фуражное значение. Исследования проводились в полевом крупноделяночном опыте, где изучались 4 системы обработки почвы: отвальная, мелкая, комбинированная в севообороте и поверхностная. Результаты исследований показали, что на выщелоченных черноземах лесостепи Среднего Поволжья в звене севооборота горох - овес целесообразно проводить комбинированную в севообороте обработку почвы, сочетающую применение отвальной обработки на глубину 25 - 27 см агрегатом ПЛН -4-35 под горох и мелкую обработку дисковым орудием БДМ- 3х4 на глубину 12-15 см под овес. Данная система обработки способствует созданию оптимальных почвенных условий произрастания растений и формированию урожайности, превышающую другие варианты (мелкую и поверхностную обработки) при возделывании гороха на 0,26—0,37 т/га, овса - 0,28-1,33 т/га.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.1(25)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>