<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X13617">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">STUDY OF WORKING BODIES OF RIDGER-SEEDER IN THE LABORATORY</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ИССЛЕДОВАНИЕ РАБОЧИХ ОРГАНОВ ГРЕБНЕВОЙ СЕЯЛКИ В ЛАБОРАТОРНЫХ УСЛОВИЯХ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Kurdyumov V.I.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Zykin Еvgeny S.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Таtаrоv Grigory L.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">N20</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">sowing equipment</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">seedbed preparation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">ridge tillage</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Soil</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_26059</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6943</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_25818</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7156</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Source component of any technology of cultivation of row crops is to prepare the field for the purpose of creating conditions for subsequent seeding, stimulation of growth and development of the root system of plants. This machining must not violate the optimal structure of the soil, but preserve soil fertility, protect from erosion processes, and preserve moisture. One of the main conditions of the successful implementation of ridge technology of cultivation of tilled crops is the use of agricultural machines of higher technical and technological levels that radically change the traditional technology. Method of planting tilled crops and ridge-seeder for its implementation were developed, the use of this ridge-seeder allows to make pre-sowing cultivation, to seed on moist soil layer on pressed receptacle, to form a mound of soil of the required size  over seeds, to roll the mound of soil from three sides and finally to form a ridge of soil of the required size and density in it in one pass. Design and operating parameters of working bodies with flat discs of ridge-seeder are experimentally substantiated. Revealed that to achieve the maximum value of the coefficient of compliance with the standard kсэ = 0,92 while forming the mound of soil you need to choose flat disks with a diameter 0,35 m, to ensure the speed of movement of the ridge-seeder 1,76 m/s (system 6,34 km/h) and set them to the direction of movement of the unit at the angle α = 22 deg.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Исходным компонентом любой технологии возделывания пропашных культур является качественная подготовка поля с целью создания условий для последующей заделки семян, стимулирования роста и развития корневой системы растений. При этом механическая обработка не должна нарушать оптимальную структуру почвы, а сохранять ее почвенное плодородие, предохранять от эрозийных процессов и максимально сохранять влагу. Одним из главных условий успешной реализации гребневой технологии возделывания пропашных культур является применение сельскохозяйственных машин более высокого технического и технологического уровней, позволяющих коренным образом изменить традиционные технологии. Разработан способ посева пропашных культур и гребневая сеялка для его осуществления, применение которой позволяет за один проход выполнить предпосевную культивацию, высев семян во влажный слой почвы на уплотненное ложе, сформировать над семенами бугорок почвы требуемых размеров, прикатывание бугорка почвы с трех сторон и окончательно сформировать гребень почвы требуемых размеров и плотности в нем. Экспериментально обоснованы конструктивные и режимные параметры рабочих органов с плоскими дисками гребневой сеялки. Выявлено, что для достижения максимального значения коэффициента соответствия эталону kсэ = 0,92 при формировании бугорка почвы необходимо выбрать плоские диски диаметром 0,35 м, обеспечить скорость движения гребневой сеялки 1,76 м/с (6,34 км/ч) и установить их к направлению движения агрегата под углом α = 22 град.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik.ugsha.ru/contentse/3-15-Kurdyumov.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.3(31)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>