<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X17638">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">INFLUENCE OF AGROTECHNICAL METHODS ON THE NUMBER OF SOIL PATHOGENS IN THE CULTIVATION OF WINTER RYE</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ВЛИЯНИЕ  АГРОТЕХНИЧЕСКИХ ПРИЕМОВ НА ЧИСЛЕННОСТЬ ПОЧВЕННЫХ ПАТОГЕНОВ ПРИ ВОЗДЕЛЫВАНИИ ОЗИМОЙ РЖИ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Marina-Chermnykh  Olga G.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Evdokimova Margarita A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Mari State University</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F07</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F08</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">secale cereale</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Pathogens</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">fertilizers</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en" />
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">cultivation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">mulches</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">soil density</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6919</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5630</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2867c82c5e5a</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2018</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4977</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7167</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">In article results of researches of influence of different types of main soil tillage, fertilizers, predecessors and mulch on the number of soil pathogens that cause diseases in winter rye. In recent years, in the cultivation of winter rye in the Republic of Mari El has deteriorated, the phytosanitary state of the soil, through the breach of farming, leading to lower productivity. The conducted research aimed at determining the most effective farming practices that improve the phytosanitary condition of the soil, reducing the number of pathogens. We studied the effects of different types of main soil tillage (plowing, disking, cultivation), fertiliser (green manure, mineral), predecessors (spring wheat, pea) and mulch on the number of soil microflora. The results showed that the detected micromycete organisms in the agroecosystem rye fields are a necessary component of soil and are actively involved in environmental regulation. Use as a primary treatment for winter rye, tillage, green manures, mulch pea predecessor helps to activate the microorganisms in the soil and reduces the number of pathogens. Pea mulch and green manure fertilizer, organic material, improve agrophysical and biological properties of soil, improve its fertility. These farming techniques allow to regulate the phytosanitary condition of the soil and, in General, rye agrocoenosis.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">В статье изложены результаты исследований влияния различных видов основной обработки почвы, удобрений, предшественников и их мульчи на численность почвенных патогенов, вызывающих заболевания озимой ржи. В последние годы при возделывании озимой ржи в Республике Марий Эл ухудшилось фитосанитарное состояние почвы, за счет нарушения агротехники, что привело к снижению ее продуктивности. Проведенные исследования направлены на определение наиболее эффективных агротехнических приемов, позволяющих улучшить фитосанитарное состояние почвы, снижая численность патогенов. Было изучено влияние различных видов основной обработки почвы (вспашка, дискование, культивация), удобрений (сидерат, минеральные), предшественников (яровая пшеница, горох) и их мульчи на численность почвенной микрофлоры. Результаты исследований показали, что выявленные микромицетные организмы агроэкосистемы ржаного поля, являются обязательным компонентом почвы и активно участвуют в ее экологической регуляции. Применение в качестве основной обработки под озимую рожь вспашки, сидеральных удобрений, мульчи горохового предшественника способствует активизации микроорганизмов в почве и снижает количество патогенов. Гороховая мульча и сидеральное удобрение, как органический материал, улучшают агрофизические и биологические свойства почвы, повышают ее плодородие. Указанные агротехнические приемы позволяют регулировать фитосанитарное состояние почвы и в целом ржаного агроценоза.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik.ugsha.ru/contentse/4-15-Marina.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.4(32)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>