<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X16925">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">THE SELECTION OF BACTERIOPHAGES OF KLEBSIELLA OXYTOCA UNDER X-RAY IRRADIATION</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ВЫДЕЛЕНИЕ БАКТЕРИОФАГОВ KLEBSIELLA OXYTOCA ПОД ДЕЙСТВИЕМ РЕНТГЕНОВСКОГО ОБЛУЧЕНИЯ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Sadrtdinova Guzeliya R.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Vasilyev Dmitry А.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Zolotukhin Sergey N.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2016-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L70</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">bacteria</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">BACTERIOPHAGES</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en" />
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">extraction</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">techniques</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Morphology</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_765</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_769</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_36910</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_14816</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_49903</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>DOI 10.18286/1816-4501-2016-1-76-80
2 tables, 2graphs, 11 ref.</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Klebsiella oxytoca bacterium are resistant microorganisms which can be the cause of many infectious diseases with severe progress. In the work we used bacterial strains obtained from the museum of the department of microbiology, virology, epizootology and veterinary-sanitary examination of Ulyanovsk state agricultural academy named after P. A. Stolypin. Main techniques were studied and tested for allocation of bacteriophages. Allocation of bacteriophages was associated with the use of inducer, x-irradiation, allowing to аllocate two phage active in a relation to Klebsiella oxytoca 1 and  Klebsiella oxytoca 24. Cultures were exposed to radiation in three modes, and in the first series of experiments there was a confluent growth of culture throughout the volume of the cup, in the second series of experiments on some cups (K. oxytoca 1, K. oxytoca 24) there were areas of bacterial growth absence (negative colonies), in the third series of experiments – most of the crops were characterized by intermittent growth of a culture. We studied some biological properties allowing to note the possible differences between negative colonies of allocated phages. In both cases, colonies size ranged within 1,0+0,5 mm and had the form of transparent round-shaped negative colonies. The allocated phages had quite high activity against the studied crops:  bacteriophage F-1 against indicator culture K.oxytoca 1 – 10 and 1х10 , bacteriophage F-24 against indicator culture K.oxytoca 24 – 10  and 4х10  по Appelman and Gratsia respectively,</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Бактерии вида Klebsiella oxytoca представляют собой устойчивые микроорганизмы, являющиеся причиной многих инфекционных заболеваний с тяжелым течением. В работе были использованы штаммы  бактерий, полученные из музея кафедры МВЭиВСЭ Ульяновской ГСХА им.П.А. Столыпина. Для выделения бактериофагов были изучены и апробированы основные методики. Выделение бактериофагов было связано с использованием индуцирующего фактора – рентгеновского облучения, что позволило выделить два фага, активных в отношении Klebsiella oxytoca 1 и  Klebsiella oxytoca 24. Культуры были подвержены облучению в трех режимах, причем в первой серии опытов отмечался сплошной рост культуры по всему объему чашки, во второй серии опытов на некоторых чашках (K.oxytoca 1, K.oxytoca 24) отмечались  зоны отсутствия  бактериального роста (негативные колонии), в третьей серии опытов – большая часть посевов характеризовалась прерывистым ростом культуры. Изучали некоторых биологические свойства, позволяющее отметить возможные отличия негативных колоний выделенных фагов. В обоих случаях размеры колоний варьировались  в пределах 1,0+0,5 мм и представляли собой прозрачные негативные колонии округлой формы. Выделенные фаги имели достаточно высокую активность в отношении изучаемых культур:  бактериофаг Ф-1 в отношение индикаторной культуры K.oxytoca 1 - 10 и 1х10 , бактериофаг Ф-24 в отношение индикаторной культуры K.oxytoca 24- 10  и 4х10  по Аппельману и Грациа соответственно.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik.ugsha.ru/contentse/1-16-sadrtdinova.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.1(33)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>