<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X17560">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">INFLUENCE OF MACROELEMENT AND GROWTH REGULATORS ON THE DYNAMICS OF NITROGEN, PHOSPHORUS, POTASSIUM AND SULFUR IN PLANTS OF WINTER WHEAT OF BIRYUZA VARIETIY IN FOREST-STEPPE CONDITIONS OF MIDDLE VOLGA REGION</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ВЛИЯНИЕ МАКРОЭЛЕМЕНТОВ И РЕГУЛЯТОРОВ РОСТА НА ДИНАМИКУ АЗОТА</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="">
      <dcterms:alternative>ФОСФОРА</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="">
      <dcterms:alternative>КАЛИЯ И СЕРЫ В РАСТЕНИЯХ ОЗИМОЙ ПШЕНИЦЫ СОРТА БИРЮЗА В УСЛОВИЯХ ЛЕСОСТЕПИ СРЕДНЕГО ПОВОЛЖЬЯ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Isaychev Vitaly A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Andreyev Nikolay N.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Plechov Dmitry V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2016-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F62</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Winter wheat</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">plant growth substances</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">inorganic fertilizers</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Mineral content</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8412</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5968</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_27870</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4848</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>4 tables, 13 ref.</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">We conducted field research on the experimental field of Ulyanovsk SAA in 2011-2015 to study the influence of different growth regulators and complex mineral sulfureous fertilizers on the macroelements dynamics in winter wheat plants of Biryuza variety (nitrogen, phosphorus, potassium and sulphur). The soil of the experimental field is a medium power medium loamy leached black soil. Total area of the working plot is 40 m2, registration plot – 20 m2, experiment replication is four times with randomized block design. It was established that the nitrogen content in winter wheat organs varied depending on soil-climatic conditions, growth regulators application and development of plants and mineral fertilizers. During the years of research the average increase from used factors ranged from 0.12 to 0,24% on the background without fertilizers, and from 0.06 to 0.29% on the background of NPK, depending on experiment variant. The maximum phosphorus content in leaves and footstalk was observed during the seedling and tillering stage, that was 0.79-1.27% and 0.65-1.1%, respectively. Terraflex variant had the greatest effect on the given indicator, on all backgrounds of cultivation. During the years of research the average increase was 0.12-0.30%, depending on the type and phase of growth and development. The obtained results show that potassium content in leaves and footstalk of winter wheat was at maximum during the phases of seedling, tillering and stem stem-extention, that confirms the greatest potassium need of plants during the period of intense growth. During the years of research the average increase from used factors ranged from 0.01 to 0.04% and on the background without fertilizers, from 0.02 to 0.05% on the background with NPK, from 0.06 to 0.09% on the background with NPK+S, compared to the control. Sulphur content in reproductive organs increases under the influence of growth regulators and mineral fertilizers. The maximum increase is noted in the variants of TerraFlex and Tsetsetse on all the backgrounds of experiment, and that increase ranges from 0.04 to 0.09%.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Проведены полевые исследования в 2011-2015 гг. на опытном поле Ульяновской ГСХА по изучению влияния различных регуляторов роста и комплексных минеральных серосодержащих удобрений на динамику в растениях озимой пшеницы сорта Бирюза макроэлементов (азота, фосфора, калия и серы). Почва опытного поля – чернозем выщелоченный среднемощный среднесуглинистый. Общая площадь делянки 40 м2, учетная – 20 м2, повторность опыта четырехкратная, расположение делянок рендомизированное. Установлено, что содержание азота в органах озимой пшеницы изменялось в зависимости от почвенно-климатических условий, применения регуляторов роста и развития растений и минеральных удобрений. В среднем за годы исследований увеличение от используемых факторов составило от 0,12 до 0,24% - на фоне без удобрений, от 0,06 до 0,29% - на фоне с NPK, в зависимости от варианта опыта. Максимальное содержание фосфора в листьях и стеблях наблюдается в фазу всходов и кущения, что составляет 0,79-1,27% и 0,65-1,1%, соответственно. Наибольший эффект по данному показателю отмечен в варианте Террафлекс, на всех фонах возделывания. В среднем за годы исследований прибавка составляет от 0,12 до 0,30%, в зависимости от варианта и фазы роста и развития. Полученные результаты показывают, что содержание калия в листьях и стеблях озимой пшеницы было максимальным в фазы всходов, кущения и выхода в трубку, что подтверждает наибольшую потребность калия растениями в период их интенсивного роста. В среднем за годы исследований увеличение от используемых факторов составило от 0,01 до 0,04% - на фоне без удобрений, от 0,02 до 0,05% - на фоне с NPK, от 0,06 до 0,09% - на фоне с NPK+S, по сравнению с контролем. Под действием регуляторов роста и минеральных удобрений увеличивается содержание серы в репродуктивных органах. Максимальная прибавка отмечается в вариантах Террафлекс и Цецеце на всех фонах опыта, что составляет от 0,04 до 0,09%.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik.ugsha.ru/contentse/1-16-isaychev.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.1(33)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>