<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X19256">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">PECULIARITIES OF AGE-RELATED CHANGES OF ZINC CONTENT IN HEIFERS</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ОСОБЕННОСТИ ВОЗРАСТНЫХ ИЗМЕНЕНИЙ СОДЕРЖАНИЯ ЦИНКА У ТЕЛОК</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Аndreyev  A.I.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Меnkova  A.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Agricultural institute of Mordovian state university named after N.P.Ogarev</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Bryansk state agricultural academy</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2016-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Cows</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Zinc</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">stomach</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">intestines</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">chyme</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1939</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8517</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7422</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3924</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_9852</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>4 tables, 11 ref. DOI: 10.18286/1816-4501-2016-2-109-112</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">We have experimentally studied concentration of zinc and its content in walls and chyme of divisions of stomach and bowel of 6-12 months old heifers with haylage type of feeding. Hay, haylage and barley bran were included in composition of basic diets. Elements malnutrition was compensated by calcium and phosphorus additives, sodium chloride, and a mixture of salts of microelements. Control slaughter of animals was performed at 6, 9 and 12 months (3 heads of every age). Concentration of zinc in the studied samples was determined on atomic absorption spectrophotometer. Conducted studies show that the highest concentration was observed in abomasum walls (17,35-23,10 mg/kg) and honeycomb (15,47-17,38 mg/kg) and the least it was in walls of small intestine (9,73-11,40 mg/kg). Increasingly it increased up to 12 months of age in walls of abomasum and small intestine of heifers. The analysis of zinc accumulation in walls of digestive tract suggests that its largest part is concentrated in the walls of rumen (of 28,9-32,1 per cent) and small intestine (22,5-28,1 %).  The zinc was deposited more in the walls of rumen, honeycomb, bible-bag, and abomasum during the period from 9 to 12 months, and in small and large intestine the impletion was steadier. With age the zinc content in all stomach divisions increased practically evenly (by 1.6-2.4 times), in intestine – by 1.5-1.6 times of the initial value (Р</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Экспериментально была изучена концентрация цинка и его содержание в стенках и химусе отделов желудка и кишечника телок 6-12 месячного возраста при сенажном типе кормления. В состав основных рационов включали сено, сенаж и ячменную дерть. Дефицит элементов питания восполняли фосфорно-кальциевыми добавками, поваренной солью, а также смесью солей микроэлементов. Контрольный убой животных проводили в 6, 9 и 12 месяцев (по 3 головы каждого возраста). Концентрацию цинка в исследуемых образцах определяли на атомно-адсорбционном спектрофотометре. Проведенные исследования показывают, что более высокая концентрация отмечалась в стенках сычуга (17,35-23,10 мг/кг) и сетки (15,47-17,38 мг/кг) и наименьшей она была в стенках тонкого отдела кишечника (9,73-11,40 мг/кг). В большей степени она повышалась к 12-месячному возрасту в стенках сычуга и тонкого кишечника телок. Проведенный анализ накопления цинка в стенках пищеварительного тракта свидетельствует о том, что наибольшая его часть сосредоточена в стенках рубца (28,9-32,1 %) и тонкого кишечника (22,5-28,1 %).  В стенках рубца, сетки, книжки и сычуга цинк больше всего депонировался в период от 9 до 12 месяцев, а в тонком и толстом кишечнике наполнение было более равномерным. С возрастом содержание цинка во всех отделах желудка повышалось практически одинаково (в 1,6-2,4 раза), в кишечнике – в 1,5-1,6 раза от первоначального (Р</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik.ugsha.ru/contentse/2-16-Andreyev.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.2(34)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>