<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X13124">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">NEED FOR HIGHLY PRODUCTIVE DEEP GESTATING SOWS IN EXCHANGE ENERGY</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ПОТРЕБНОСТЬ ВЫСОКОПРОДУКТИВНЫХ ГЛУБОКОСУПОРОСНЫХ СВИНОМАТОК В ОБМЕННОЙ ЭНЕРГИИ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Маtyayev V.I.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Аndin I.S.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Agricultural institute of Mordovian state university named after N.P.Ogarev</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L02</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Sows</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Energy value</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">compound feeds</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Animal feeding</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7271</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_10613</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1796</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_429</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">In the article, the authors set the goal of obtaining highly productive deep gestating sows 13-14 live pigs weighing not less than 1,35 kg. As the object of research, highly productive deep gestating sows OJSC Agrofirma "Octyabrskaya", the third farrowing, in the amount of 10, body weight 290,2 kg were taken. The number of fetuses in the womb were determined using ultrasound. The fodder of own production was used in the feeding of gestating sows, 1 kg of dry matter contained: 13,55 MJ of metabolizable energy, 165,9 g of crude protein, 26,5 g of crude fat, 104 grams of crude fiber, 9,29 g of calcium, 7,77 g of phosphorus and 16,3 mg of carotene. For optimal process of pregnancy from hunting to farrowing 4-phase feeding regime was applied. Monitoring body condition of sows led through the measurement of backfat thickness using ultrasound M. longissimus dorsi at the front of the head of the last rib 6,5 cm lateral to the midline of the back. Backfat thickness in experimental sows during insemination was 23,1±0,27 cm, after farrowing – 25,2±0,30, weaning piglets — 21,9±0,26 cm. The need for highly productive deep pregnant sows in the last third of pregnancy (live weight 290,2 kg, 14 piglets) was determined taking into account the maintenance of life (31 MJ), the increase in body weight of 30 kg (4,5 MJ/day), foetus growth (7 MJ). Total daily requirement of highly productive deep gestating sows should be at the level of 42,5 MJ of metabolizable energy. To fill the deficit of metabolizable energy, sunflower oil 199 g/b/day was administered in the diet of sows. Gas chromatographic analysis of blood lipids of sows shows that feeding them with vegetable fat contributes to significantly change the fatty acid spectrum, the ratio of unsaturated and saturated fatty acids (1.07:1). The results of farrowing highly productive deep gestating sows confirmed the correct application of the recommended designs, the weight of piglets at farrowing amounted 1367 g, against 1266 g in the control (commercial diet). Thus, the diets of high yielding deep gestating sows must be controlled according to the content of the exchange energy, the lack of which to be bridged through the introduction of vegetable oil.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">В приведенной статье авторы поставили цель получения от высокопродуктивных глубокосупоросных свиноматок 13-14 живых поросят с массой не менее 1,35 кг. В качестве объекта исследований были взяты высокопродуктивные глубокосупоросные свиноматки ОАО Агрофирма «Октябрьская», третьим опоросом, в количестве 10 голов, живой массой 290,2 кг. Количество плодов в утробе матери устанавливали с помощью УЗИ. В кормлении супоросных свиноматок применяли комбикорм собственного производства, в 1 кг сухого вещества которого содержалось: 13,55 МДж обменной энергии, 165,9 г сырого протеина, 26,5 г сырого жира, 104 г сырой клетчатки, 9,29 г кальция, 7,77 г фосфора и 16,3 мг каротина. Для обеспечения оптимального процесса беременности от охоты и до опороса применяли 4 фазный режим кормления. Контроль за состоянием упитанности свиноматок вели посредствам измерения толщины шпика при помощи ультразвука на М. longissimus dorsi у передней головки последнего ребра в 6,5 см латеральнее срединной линии спины. Толщина шпика у подопытных свиноматок при осеменении равнялась 23,1±0,27 см, после опороса – 25,2±0,30, отъеме поросят – 21,9±0,26 см. Потребность высокопродуктивных глубокосупоросных свиноматок в последнюю треть беременности (живая масса 290,2 кг, 14 поросят) определяли с учетом поддержания жизни (31 МДж), прироста массы тела 30 кг (4,5 МДж/сут.), роста плодов (7 МДж). Итого суточная потребность высокопродуктивных глубокосупоросных свиноматок должна быть на уровне 42,5 Мдж обменной энергии. Для восполнения дефицита обменной энергии в рацион свиноматок вводили подсолнечное масло 199 г/гол./сут. Газохроматографический анализ липидов крови свиноматок показывает, что скармливание им растительного жира способствует достоверному изменению жирнокислотного спектра, соотношению ненасыщенных и насыщенных жирных кислот (1,07:1).
Результаты опороса высокопродуктивных глубокосупоросных свиноматок подтвердили правильность применения рекомендуемых разработок, масса поросят при опоросе составила 1367 г, против 1266 г в контроле (хозяйственный рацион). Таким образом, рационы высокопродуктивных глубокосупоросных свиноматок необходимо контролировать по содержанию обменной энергии, недостаток которой восполнять за счет введения растительного жира.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik.ugsha.ru/contentse/3-15-Matyayev.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.3(31)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>