<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X12828">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">SUBSTANTIATION OF TECHNOLOGIES OF GROWING REPLACEMENT GILTS WITH THE USE OF DRUG ROSTMIK</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ОБОСНОВАНИЕ ТЕХНОЛОГИИИ ВЫРАЩИВАНИЯ РЕМОНТНЫХ СВИНОК С ИСПОЛЬЗОВАНИЕМ ПРЕПАРАТА РОСТМИК</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Кulmakova N.I.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Leontyev L.B.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>FSBEI HPE RSAU – МSAA К.А. Тimiryazev</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">gilts</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Metabolism</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">reproductive performance</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Viability</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Multiple births</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_11152</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4769</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6510</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8210</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4985</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>3 tables, 12 ref.</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The aim of this work was the rationale for inclusion of the drug Rostmik in the technology of growing replacement gilts in the conditions of the Chuvash Republic. 	The work is performed on the basis of FSUE EF «Privolzhskoye» Chuvash state agricultural Academy. Replacement gilts of large white breed, the average live weight from 81,40±0,66 to 82,26±0,47 kg have been the subject of research.  By results of work it is established that the introduction of the drug Rostmik, consisting of malt sprouts and poly salts of micro elements, in the dose of 300 g in 60 days before insemination, to the technology of growing replacement gilts, promotes activation of protein, vitamin, mineral metabolism, optimization of acid-base balance, increase the functional activity of factors of nonspecific resistance. All this allows them more productive use of nutrients. As a result, they grow  intensively and develop, which is manifested in a larger by 22,7% average and by 7,2% absolute increase in live weight, the increased fertility from first insemination by 11,6% with decreasing flow of sperm on one fruitful insemination  by 0,2 dose,  high by 17,0% multiparity and by 5,2% safety of piglets compared to replacement piglets who are on a normal economic diet.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Целью работы явилась обоснование включения в технологию выращивания ремонтных свинок препарата Ростмик в условиях Чувашской Республики. Работа выполнена на базе ФГУП УОХ «Приволжское» Чувашской государственной сельскохозяйственной академии. Объектом исследований явились ремонтные свинки крупной белой породы, средней живой массой от 81,40±0,66 до 82,26±0,47 кг. 
По итогам работы установлено, что введение в технологию выращивания ремонтных свинок препарата Ростмик, включающий в свой состав солодовые ростки и полисоли микроэлементов, в дозе 300 г за 60 суток до осеменения, способствует активации белкового, витаминного, минерального обмена, оптимизации кислотно-щелочного равновесия, повышению функциональной активности факторов неспецифической резистентности. Все это позволяет им продуктивнее использовать питательные вещества рациона. Вследствие этого они интенсивней растут и развиваются, что проявляется в большем на 22,7% среднесуточном и на 7,2% абсолютном приросте живой массы, повышением оплодотворяемости от первого осеменения на 11,6% при понижении расхода спермы на одно плодотворное осеменение на 0,2 дозы, высокой на 17,0% многоплодностью и на 5,2% сохранностью поросят по сравнению с ремонтными свинками, находящимися на обычном хозяйственном рационе.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik.ugsha.ru/contentse/2-15-%D0%9Aulmakova.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.2(30)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>