<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X12869">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">INFLUENCE OF KINSHIP ON HOLSTEIN BREED ON PRODUCTIVE LONGEVITY AND LIFETIME MILK PRODUCTIVITY OF BLACK-MOTLEY COWS</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ВЛИЯНИЕ КРОВНОСТИ ПО ГОЛШТИНСКОЙ ПОРОДЕ НА ПРОДУКТИВНОЕ ДОЛГОЛЕТИЕ И ПОЖИЗНЕННУЮ МОЛОЧНУЮ ПРОДУКТИВНОСТЬ ЧЁРНО-ПЁСТРЫХ КОРОВ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Rudenko  O.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Еremin  S.P.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Nizhny Novgorod research Institute of agriculture</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Nizhny Novgorod State Agricultural Academy</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Cows</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Animal genetics</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en" />
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Milk performance</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1939</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_49986</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_24276</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The study was carried out in the breeding farms of Nizhny Novgorod region. The aim of this work was to study the effect of genetic factors, including the Holstein breed kinship, on productive longevity of dairy cows. Purebred black pied cows have the highest life expectancy that they lived more than 5 lactations, had a maximum lifetime milk yield 24124 kg of milk, the best results for the yield of milk on day 1 of life (8.7 kg) and the ratio of milking days to dry (1,28). With increasing kinship the duration of the productive use of animals has decreased dramatically and reached 2,49 lactations in cows with Holstein breed kinship of more than 88%. A similar situation was observed in terms of lifetime milk yield. Thus, the lowest lifetime milk yield (14115 kg) was obtained from cows with high kinship (75-87%), these animals were given per 1 day of life 7 kg of milk, per 1 day of lactation - 19.1 kg. The force of the impact of factor "proportion of kinship" to study the signs was established: lifetime – 8,92%, lifetime milk yield – 3,70%, milk yield during the first lactation - 4.03%, the highest milk yield for a lactation – 2,91%, milk yield per 1 day of lactation – 8,91%. The highest milk yield for first and higher lactation from cows that have kinship 38-50% by improving breed, with an average life expectancy 3,36 lactations and lifetime milk yield 18286 kg of milk. These options are most favorable for increasing the duration of use of cows and obtain maximum lifetime productivity.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Исследования проводили в племенных хозяйствах Нижегородской области. Целью работы явилось изучение влияния генетических факторов, в том числе кровности по голштинской породе,  на продуктивное долголетие молочных коров. Наибольшей продолжительностью жизни отличались чистопородные чёрно-пёстрые коровы, они жили в среднем более 5 лактаций, имели максимальный пожизненный удой 24124 кг молока, лучшие показатели по удою на 1 день жизни (8,7 кг) и соотношение дойных дней к недойным (1,28). С увеличением кровности длительность продуктивного использования животных резко уменьшилась и составила 2,49 лактации у коров с кровностью по голштинской породе более 88%. Аналогичная ситуация наблюдалась и по показателю пожизненного удоя. Так,  наименьший пожизненный удой (14115 кг) получен от коров с высокой кровностью (75-87%), эти животные дали в расчёте на 1 день жизни 7 кг молока, в расчёте на 1 день лактации – 19,1 кг. Установлена сила влияния фактора «доля кровности» на изучаемые признаки: продолжительность жизни – 8,92%, пожизненный удой – 3,70%, удой за первую лактацию – 4,03%, удой за наивысшую лактацию – 2,91%, удой на 1 день лактации – 8,91%. Наибольший удой за первую и наивысшую лактации получен от коров, имеющих кровность 38-50% по улучшающей породе, при средней продолжительности жизни 3,36 лактации и пожизненном удое 18286 кг молока. Эти параметры наиболее благоприятны для увеличения продолжительности использования коров и получения от них максимальной пожизненной продуктивности.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik.ugsha.ru/contentse/2-15-Rudenko.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.2(30)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>