<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X13489">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">EFFECT OF ANTI-FRICTION ADDITIVES IN OIL ON A TEMPERATURE IN THE TRIBO UNIT</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ВЛИЯНИЕ АНТИФРИКЦИОННЫХ ПРИСАДОК В МАСЛЕ  НА ТЕМПЕРАТУРУ В ТРИБОУЗЛЕ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Glushchenko Аndrey А.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Zamaldinov Маrаt М.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Salakhutdinov Ilmas R.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">N20</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">machinery industry</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Temperature</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">lubricants</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">wear</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4497</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7657</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_25737</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_24914</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">While in operation, the temperature rise in tribo unit contributes to the creation of conditions for the transition from the unsaturated contact to the saturated and the occurrence of burrs and grappling of rubbing surfaces. The moment of transition is characterized by the so-called critical transition point. Working conditions of tribo unit to the critical point are characterized by a low wear and a long service life. When working in conditions of temperatures above the critical, increased wear of the rubbing surfaces of tribute, scuffing, seizure and wedging is observed. To reduce the temperature of tribo unit it is proposed to use in the lubricating oil copper-containing additive MOF having higher thermal conductivity. With the same thickness of the lubricating layer in tribo unit, it will reduce the diffusivity of the oil cover, and therefore shows the thermal conductivity of the elements of tribo unit. As a result of the conducted researches it is established that the introduction of anti-friction additives in regular oil will raise the value of critical point of transition from unsaturated contact to saturated in tribo unit. And improving critical point of transition will reduce the temperature in tribo unit during ordinary operation, and thus reduce the intensity of  the wear of friction surfaces.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">В процессе эксплуатации, повышение температуры в трибоузле, способствует созданию условия перехода от ненасыщенного контакта к насыщенному и возникновению задиров и схватываний трущихся поверхностей. Момент перехода характеризуется так называемой критической точкой перехода. Условия работы трибоузла до критической точки характеризуются низким износом и длительным ресурсом работы. При работе в условиях температур выше критической наблюдается повышенный износ трущихся поверхностей трибоузла, задиры, схватывания и заклинивание. Для снижения температуры трибоузла предложено использовать в смазочном масле медьсодержащую присадку МОФ, обладающей более высокой теплопроводностью. При одинаковой толщине смазочного слоя в трибоузле, это позволит снизить температуропроводность масляной пленки, и, соответственно приведенную теплопроводность элементов трибоузла. В результате проведенных исследований установлено, что введение в штатное масло антифрикционных присадок позволит поднять величину критической точки перехода ненасыщенного контакта в насыщенный в трибоузле. А повышение критической точки перехода позволит снизить температуру в трибоузле при рядовой эксплуатации, и тем самым, снизить интенсивность износа поверхностей трения.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik.ugsha.ru/contentse/2-15-Glushchenko.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.2(30)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>