<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X17301">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">INFLUENCE OF NEOPLASIC LESIONS OF MAMMARY GLAND ON HEMOSTASIS INNER PATH OF FEMALES DOGS</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ВЛИЯНИЕ НЕОПЛАЗИЙНЫХ ПОРАЖЕНИЙ МОЛОЧНОЙ ЖЕЛЕЗЫ НА ВНУТРЕННИЙ ПУТЬ ГЕМОСТАЗА У СУК</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Rublenko M.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Bely D.D.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Bila Tserkva national agrarian university</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Dnipropetrovsk state agrarian and economic university</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2016-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L70</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L73</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">dogs</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Mammary glands</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en" />
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Coagulation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">neoplasms</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2352</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4562</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1691</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5122</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Study of activated partial thromboplastin time duration (APTT) is optimal for the evaluation of internal path and general cascade of blood clotting system, which is the most sensitive index of coagulation and allows to evaluate its initial stage – the formation of thromboplastin. Taking into account that direct anticoagulants (heparin) affect factors of internal path of hemostasis, APTT is acknowledged as the optimal test for monitoring the effectiveness of anticoagulation therapy. Taking into account the importance of APTT in the evaluation of hemostasis status disorders, as well as insufficient knowledge of the problem of its correction for tumorigenic, we have conducted studies of this indicator in females dogs with mammary gland tumors. It was established that 	neoplasmic process is accompanied by statistically significant changes of this indicator in all patients. Moreover, if in case of malignant lesions of mammary gland prolongation and the shortening of the APTT was detected in the same number of cases (50/50 %), so in case of benign process most of the animals revealed a shortening of blood clot formation time (73,68 %). In case of malignant tumors the disorder of coagulation internal path was more pronounced: prolongation of the APTT values exceeded the 150 % threshold in 50 % of dogs. In case of benign tumors such changes were observed in 26,32 % of female dogs. The obtained results indicate the disturbance of equilibrium of coagulation and fibrinolytic mechanisms in patients with tumoral lesions of mammary gland, and also confirm the diagnostic value of this test.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Для оценки внутреннего пути и общего каскада системы сворачивания крови оптимальным является исследование продолжительности активированного частичного тромбопластинового времени (АЧТВ), которое является наиболее чувствительным показателем коагуляции и позволяет оценить её начальную стадию – образование тромбопластина. Учитывая, что прямые антикоагулянты (гепарин) воздействую на факторы внутреннего пути гемостаза, АЧТВ признан оптимальным тестом контроля эффективности антикоагуляционной терапии. Принимая во внимание значимость АЧТВ в оценке нарушений гемостазиологического статуса, а также недостаточную изученность проблемы его коррекции при новообразованиях, были проведены исследования данного показателя у сук с опухолями молочной железы. При этом установлено, что неоплазийный процесс сопровождается статистически достоверными изменениями указанного показателя у всех пациентов. Причём, если в случае злокачественного поражения молочной железы удлинение и укорочение АЧТВ регистрировали в одинаковом количестве случаев (50/50 %), то при доброкачественном процессе у большинства животных выявляли уменьшение времени образования кровяного сгустка (73,68 %). При злокачественных новообразованиях нарушения внутреннего пути коагуляции были более выражены: увеличение значений АЧТВ превышало 150 % барьер у 50 % собак. При доброкачественных опухолях подобные изменения констатировали у 26,32 % сук.Полученные результаты свидетельствуют о нарушении равновесия коагуляционных и фибринолитических механизмов у пациентов с опухолевыми поражениями молочной железы, а также подтверждают диагностическую ценность данного теста.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik.ugsha.ru/contentse/1-16-rublenko.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.1(33)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>