<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X17635">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">THE INFLUENCE OF STRAW ON FERTILE CHARACTERISTICS OF SOIL AND BIOLOGICAL YIELD CAPACITY OF BARLEY ON THE LEACHED CHERNOZEM IN THE CENTRAL BLACK EARTH REGION.</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ВЛИЯНИЕ СОЛОМЫ НА ПОКАЗАТЕЛИ ПЛОДОРОДИЯ И БИОЛОГИЧЕСКИЙ УРОЖАЙ ЯЧМЕНЯ НА ЧЕРНОЗЕМЕ ВЫЩЕЛОЧЕННОМ В УСЛОВИЯХ ЦЧР</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Lukin Alexey L.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Mareva Olga B.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Selavkin Sergey N.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Voronezh State Agrarian University named after Emperor Peter I</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F62</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Hordeum</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">straw</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">microorganisms</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">enzyme activity</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">soil fertility</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Chernozems</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3660</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7441</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4807</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2604</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7170</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1533</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>4 tables, 9 ref.</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Monitoring of the fertile characteristics of soil is a relevant aspect in modern agricultural technologies. A particular interest is taken into evaluating effect of straw processed with microorganisms and used as fertilizer.  To collect practical data, in 2012-2014 a microplot experiment was conducted on the territory of the Botanical Garden of Voronezh Agricultural University. The aim of the experiment was to study biological activity of leached chernozom (black earth). In the autumn the straw combined with Baikal AM1 (300 litres/ha) was ploughed up in a fallow plot. It has been found that annual use of straw straw increases the organic amount of soil by 1,3 times.  Its maximum is observed when both straw and seeds are combined with Baikal AМ1. All the variants demonstrate the significant increase in urease, while catalase activity varied only slightly. The variants with straw processed with microorganisms show the increase in phosphotase and invertase. Analysis of the total bacteria amount grown in SАА and МPА reveals the transformation of soil organic. The lowest figure is found when straw is processed with Baikal AМ1, while the highest figure (2,8 as much) is found in the ground plot. The plots where plain straw was used produced 514 productive stems, but in cases where straw was processed with bacteria we found 540-560stems. Thus, it is found that in case of growing barley, the organic maximum is achieved when using Baikal AM1 for processing both seeds and straw. The variants with straw and bacteria show increase in enzyme activity. The balance of autochthonous and zymogenous microbiota gradually decreases further from the control variant. When seeds and straw was processed with Baikal AM1, there is increase in the amount of grains, capacity of spikes and therefore the yield capacity.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Актуальной проблемой современных агротехнологий остается контроль уровня плодородия почвы. Оценка влияния органического удобрения в виде соломы, обработанной микроорганизмами, на численность и активность почвенной микрофлоры представляет интерес. В 2012-2014гг заложен микроделяночный опыт на территории Ботанического сада ВГАУ по изучению элементов биологической активности чернозема выщелоченного. В качестве фона (контроля) использовалась почва обработанная по типу пара, обработка соломы микроорганизмами препарата Байкал ЭМ 1 из расчета 300 л/га рабочего раствора проводилась осенью. Ежегодное внесение соломы повысило содержание органического вещества в целом в 1,3 раза. Во всех вариантах наблюдалась высокая активность уреазы, а активность каталазы незначительно варьировала. Повышение активности фосфатазы и инвертазы отмечено на вариантах при внесении соломы обработанной микроорганизмами. По соотношению общей численности микроорганизмов растущих на питательных средах (КАА:МПА) можно судить о процессах трансформации органического вещества почвы. Наименьшее значение этого соотношения отмечено при обработке соломы препаратом Байкал ЭМ 1, а наибольшее значение (в 2,8 раза) получено на варианте под паром. На вариантах с внесением соломы сформировалось 514 продуктивных стеблей, а при использовании микроорганизмов (варианты 2 и 3) - 540 и 560 шт. соответственно. Таким образом, установлено, что при выращивании ячменя максимальное значение показателя органического вещества достигается на варианте с использованием препарата Байкал ЭМ 1 при совместной обработке соломы и семян. На варианте применения соломы и микроорганизмов выявлено увеличение ферментативной активности. Соотношение групп зимогенной и автохтоной микробиоты уменьшается постепенно от контрольного варианта. Обработка семян и соломы препаратом Байкал ЭМ 1 способствовала увеличению озерненности, повышению продуктивности колосьев и в результате этого увеличению урожайности.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik.ugsha.ru/contentse/4-15-Lukin.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.4(32)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>