<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X12767">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">DEPENDENCE OF DYNAMICS OF MICROELEMENTS IN PLANTS OF SPRING WHEAT FROM THE PRE-SOWING TREATMENT OF SEEDS BY GROWTH REGULATORS</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ЗАВИСИМОСТЬ ДИНАМИКИ МАКРОЭЛЕМЕНТОВ В РАСТЕНИЯХ ЯРОВОЙ ПШЕНИЦЫ ОТ ПРЕДПОСЕВНОЙ ОБРАБОТКИ СЕМЯН РЕГУЛЯТОРАМИ РОСТА</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Isaychev V.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Andreev N.N.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Kaspirovsky A.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2013-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F61</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Triticum aestivum</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">plant growth stimulants</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">mineral supplements</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Crop yield</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en" />
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7951</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_27096</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_12599</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_10176</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>15 ref.</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The influence of different growth regulators on the dynamics of macro-elements (nitrogen, phosphorus, and potassium) in crops of spring wheat is studied. The studies have shown that at the presowing seed treatment by growth regulators there are positive changes in the dynamics of the main elements of the nutrition of bodies of spring wheat. The analysis of the dynamics of nitrogen, phosphorus and potassium in the leaves, stems, and ears of corn shows that the maximum number of specified elements in vegetative organs is observed in the initial phases of the growth of plants, gradually decreasing as maturation. Simultaneously with this, there is an increase in the amount of nitrogen, phosphorus and potassium in the reproductive organs. This is due to stimulation by growth regulators of metabolic and physiological processes in plants. The positive influence of growth regulators on the provision of plant nutrition elements leads to the increase of the crop yield of spring wheat.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Изучено влияние различных регуляторов роста на динамику макроэлементов (азот, фосфор, калий) в растениях яровой пшеницы. Исследования показали, что при предпосевной обработке семян регуляторами роста происходят положительные изменения в динамике основных элементов питания в органах яровой пшеницы. Анализ динамики содержания азота, фосфора и калия в листьях, стеблях и колосьях показывает, что максимальное количество указанных элементов в вегетативных органах наблюдается в начальные фазы роста растений, постепенно снижаясь по мере созревания. Одновременно с этим происходит увеличение количества азота, фосфора и калия в репродуктивных органах. Это объясняется стимуляцией регуляторами роста метаболических и физиологических процессов в растениях. Положительное влияние регуляторов роста на обеспечение растений элементами питания в конечном итоге сказывается на увеличении урожайности яровой пшеницы.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.1(21)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>