<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="CO2016000056">
    <dc:title xml:lang="es">Eficacia de los extractos hidroalcohólicos de dos plantas sobre garrapatas adultas Rhipicephalus (Boophilus) microplus</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="es">
      <dcterms:alternative>Efficacy of hydroalcoholic extracts of two plants on adult ticks Rhipicephalus (Boophilus) microplus</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Pulido Suárez Néstor Julián</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Cruz Carrillo Anastasia</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2013-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">H10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en" />
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Biological control agents</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Plant extracts</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Entomology</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1327912764943</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_920</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8166</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2588</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>1 fig. 28 ref.</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="es">Se determinó la eficacia del extracto natural de Verbena officinalis L. y de Ruta graveolens L. en el control in vitro de la garrapata adulta Rhipicephalus (Boophilus) microplus. El extracto de cada planta se obtuvo mediante la técnica de maceración. Para las pruebas, se  utilizaron garrapatas adultas de dos tamaños (pequeñas y medianas), que fueron expuestas a los extractos de cada planta, utilizando la técnica de inmersión de garrapatas adultas. A las 24, 48, 72 y 96 h de exposición, se realizó la lectura de mortalidad, donde se tomó como mínimo eficaz una mortalidad de 60%. Las pruebas iniciales se realizaron con extractos puros y cuando éstos mostraban eficacia se procedía a realizar diluciones crecientes, hasta encontrar la concentración mínima eficaz. Las pruebas fueron realizadas en clima frío. El extracto de R. graveolens (ruda) mostró efectividad en garrapata pequeña y mediana, sólo con el extracto puro</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">V. officinalis (verbena negra) mostró eficacia sobre garrapata pequeña y mediana en la dilución 5:10. V. officinalis mostró mayor eficacia y se observó que los mejores resultados se obtuvieron con las mayores concentraciones. Palabras claves: control biológico, fitoterapia, Ruta 
graveolens, Verbena officinalis.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">The efficacy of the natural extract of Verbena officinalis L. and Ruta graveolens L. in vitro monitoring of adult tick Rhipicephalus (Boophilus) microplus was established. The extract of each plant was obtained by maceration. For testing two sizes (small and medium) of adult ticks were exposed to extracts of each plant, by immersion technique. At 24, 48, 72 and 96 h of exposure, mortality was recorded taken as 60% mortality as the effective minimum. Initial tests were conducted with pure extracts, and if efficacy detected, increased dilutions were made to establish the minimum efficiency. Tests were conducted in cool climates conditions. The extract of R. graveolens (rue), showed effectiveness in small and medium tick only with the pure extract</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">V. officinalis (common vervain) was effective on small and medium-tick in dilution 5:10. V. officinalis showed greater efficacy and found that the best results were obtained at higher concentrations. Key words: Biological control, phytotherapy, Ruta graveolens, Verbena officinalis.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.corpoica.org.co/SitioWeb/Archivos/Revista/Articulo9_REVISTACORPOICAVol14No1-2013.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">es</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Revista CORPOICA : Ciencia y Tecnología Agropecuaria</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">01228706</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.14/n.1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>