<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="SK2016006872">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Effect of delayed tending on development of beech (Fagus sylvatica L.) pole stage stand</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Štefančík Igor</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>National Forest Centre, Zvolen, Slovak Republic</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Czech University of Life Sciences Prague, Kamýcká 129,  165 21 Prague 6 – Suchdol, Czech Republic</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2013-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Production</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">stand structure</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6200</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_34911</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The paper deals with assessment of the long-term experiment (45 years of investigation) in beech (Fagus sylvatica L.) stand with delayed tending started at stand age of 60 years. The research was performed on four partial plots by different methods of their management: (i) plot with heavy thinning from below (C degree according to the German forest research institutes from 1902), (ii) plot with the free crown thinning (thinning interval of 5 years), (iii) plot with the free crown thinning (thinning interval of 10 years) and (iv) control plot (with no thinning). From qualitative point of view, the best results according to the number of target (crop) trees were found on plots tended by the free crown thinning (thinning interval of 5 years), and the worst on plots with heavy thinning from below and/or plot with no tending (control plot). Consequently, the results showed lower number of target (crop) trees in comparison with our assumption and/or the model developed for beech stands in the past. On the other hand, from quantitative point of view, the best results were achieved on plot tended by heavy thinning from below, followed by the plot with the free crown thinning (thinning interval of 5 years).</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.savzv.sk/editorial-activity/contents/</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>FOLIA OECOLOGICA</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1336-5266</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.40/n.2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>