<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="SK2016006552">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">A comparative analysis of image processing softwares to indirect estimation of leaf area index in forest ecosystems</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Pastorella Fabio</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Paletto Alessandro</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Forest Monitoring and Planning Research Unit (CRA-MPF) - Consiglio per la Ricerca e la sperimentazione in Agricoltura, Villazzano di Trento, Italy</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2013-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">canopy</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">photography</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Leaf area index</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1262</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5808</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_35196</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The leaf area of vegetation can be expressed in terms of leaf area index (LAI). This index depends on species composition, developmental stage, prevailing site conditions, seasonality and management practices. LAI is an important ecological parameter because vegetation-atmosphere processes of the canopy are controlled by the foliage. It can be estimated with hemispherical photographs using some commercial and free softwares. The choice of the software and the settings of parameters are two fundamental aspects to obtain suitable data. The paper focuses on the comparative analysis of the LAI data obtained with three image processing softwares (Spot Light Intercept Model, Gap Light Analyzer and WinScanopy) in a case study in Italy. The data were analyzed in a qualitative and quantitative way. The Wilcoxon signed rank test showed statistically significant differences among the three softwares. WinScanopy provides lower LAI values than the other two softwares. The same non-parametric test distinguishing per forest type and forest age showed statistically significant differences among softwares in three forest types (silver fir, Norway spruce and beech forests) and in the young stands. Instead, no statistically significant differences were found in the mature stands.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.savzv.sk/editorial-activity/contents/</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>FOLIA OECOLOGICA</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1336-5266</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.40/n.2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>