<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="SK2016011137">
    <dc:title xml:lang="sk">Overenie technológie variabilnej aplikácie dusíka s využitím informácie o poraste a produkčnej zóne pozemku v poloprevádzkových podmienkach</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>Field evaluation of variable application of nitrogen using the information on crop in combination with information on yield potential zone of the field</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Galambošová Jana</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Ingeli Martin</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Rataj Vladimír</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Slovak University of Agriculture, Nitra, Slovak Republic</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">P01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Soil</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">precision agriculture</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Nitrogen</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">sustainability</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7156</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_92363</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5192</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33560</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang=" ">Nitrogen is one of the most important factors influencing crop yield. Technical and technological aspects of nitrogen fertiliser application receive much attention nowadays. Nowadays, nitrogen application is based on non-contact crop sensing using the satellite, aerial as well as ground- based platforms of remote sensing. Due to availability and low investment costs, ground based remote sensing sensors installed at machinery are the most used. Sensors use mostly the information on spectral reflectance, which are correlated with important crop parameters as e.g. leaf area index, areal Nitrogen, chlorophyll content etc. Latest scientific results show, that when applying nitrogen, other factors which reflect the variability of the field should be considered. The paper reports results of a strip-based field experiment conducted at a commercial farm, where the technology of nitrogen application using the sensor ISARIA was assessed. The strips fertilised based on sensor recommendation were altered with uniform application, where doses were recommended based on farmer's best practice. The sensor determined the application dose based on information from crop sensing as well as yield potential of the particular part of the field. Results showed that when using the sensor, nitrogen doses higher of 49.32 kg.ha N were applied compared to uniform application, however, this was reflected by yield increase by 1.25 t.ha, When considering the revenues increase and costs associated, the economic benefit was calculated as 150.68 €.ha.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.19/n.2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>