<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="SK2016010675">
    <dc:title xml:lang="sk">Vplyv minerálnej výživy a kyseliny 5-aminolevulovej na úrodu a kvalitu dyne červenej (Citullus lanatus Thumb., Mansf.)</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>Effect of mineral nutrition and 5 - aminolevulinic acid acid on yield and quality of watermelons (Citrullus lanatus Thumn.</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="">
      <dcterms:alternative>Mans.)</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Varga Ladislav</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Ložek Otto</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Slamka Pavol</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Ducsay Ladislav</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Slovenská poľnohospodárska univerzita, Nitra</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:publisher>
      <ags:publisherPlace>Nitra</ags:publisherPlace>
    </dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F04</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Fertilization</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Yields</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Quality</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">watermelons</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2863</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8488</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6400</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_15277</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang=" ">The small ground-plot experiment with the watermelon with the varieties of Lady F1 , Madera F1 and Bonta F1 was established in the locality of Kráľová nad Váhom situated in the southern part of The Danube lowland and in the locality of Želiezovce situated in the south-east part of The Danube lowland. The soil in both localities was medium heavy sandy-loamy black soiI with neutral soil reaction. During the vegetation period there were 5 sprayings with Pentakeep V, G and S realised on the 7 variants of nutrition in these terms: first - 10 days after out planting of transplants, second - before the beginning of blossoming of watermelon, third - after blossoming, fourth- by fruits setting, fifth-after the first harvest of the yield of watermelon fruits. Foliar applied fertilizers from the series of Pentakeep were used in the concentrations of 0.02%, 0.05%, 0.1% and 0.2% in the dosage of water 500 l.ha, 1,000 l.ha and 2,500.ha. The objective of the experiment was to quantify the efficiency of the 5-aminolevulinic acid together with the mineral nutrition in the fertilizers of the serie s "Pentakeep V, S and G" on the yield of watermelon and to find out the influence of the Pentakeep V, S, and G fertilizers on the content of nitrates and vitamin C in the fruits of watermelon, to evaluate the fertilization efficiency of the used fertilizers from the economic aspect. Based on our results and observations can be stated, that the foliar application of Pentakeep V in the concentrations of 0.02%, 0.05% and 0.1% during the monitored trial years from 2006 to 2008 statistically high significantly increased the average yield of the fruits of watermelon by 19.1% to 21.1%, which means the increase of the fruits yield of watermelons by 8.99 t.ha up to 9.93 t.ha in comparison to the control treatment. The most marked increase of the average yield of the watermelon fruits was achieved by the foliar application of Pentakeep V in the concentration of 0.05% in the spray dose l,OOOI.ha-l with statistically high significantly increased average yield of watermelon fruits by 9.93 t.ha" which represents in the relative expression in percentage 21.1% increase in comparison to the control treatment. By the evaluation of the 5-aminolevulinic acid influence in the Pentakeep V fertilizer on the content of nitrates in the fruits of watermelon it can be stated, that the foliar application of Pentakeep V on the all observed varieties was demonstrated in statistically high significant reduction of the nitrates content in the fruits of watermelon from 18.4% to 36.1%. The foliar application of Pentakeep V in the concentration of 0.02% in the spray dose 2,500 I.ha-l resulted in the biggest reduction of (statistically high significantly) the content of nitrates in the fruits of watermelon by 63.2 mg.kg it means by 36.1 % in comparison to the control treatment. Favourable stimulating effect of the foliar application of Pentakeep V was manifested also on the increase of the vitamin C content in the fruits of watermelon. From the view of the vitamin C content in the fruits we noticed in the treatment with the Pentakeep V application in concentration of 0.05% the most significant increase of vitamin C content level in the fruits of watermelon, the increase amounted 39.0%. By the application of Pentakeep V in the 0.05% concentration applied in the fluid spraying dose 1,000 l.ha on the plants of watermelons in the treatment 2 the coefficient of the economic efficiency (KEE) has reached the highest value 6.6 and parallel the highest profit increase was achieved from hectare 1,854.1 €. Based on during two years gained results from the examination of the foliar application efficiency of the separate fertilizers Pentakeep V, Pentakeep S and Pentakeep G with the content of 5 aminolevulinic acid on the model crop of watermelon it can be stated, that by the application of Pentakeep S in the 0.1 % concentration in the fluid spraying dose 500 l.ha (during the vegetation were applied 5 sprayings), from all observed treatments we noticed the most massive increase statistically high significantly of the average yield of watermelon fruits by 17.10 t.ha which represents in the relative expression in percentage 36.8% increase in comparison to the control treatment, and tbe biggest coefficient of the economic efficiency (KEE) was achieved 7.9 and the highest profit increase from hectare 2,837.5 € was achieved. The influence of the application of Pentakeep V in the concentrations of 0.1%, 0.05% and 0.02% statistically high significantly reduced the average content of nitrates in the fruits of watermelons by 41.3 mg.kg up to 66.3 mg.kg which represents in the relative expression in percentage by 26% to 41.8% decrease in comparison to the control treatment. The foliar application of Pentakeep S and G reflected in reverse statistically high significant increase of the content of nitrates in the fruits of watermelon in comparison
to the control treatment. The most notable increase of the vitamin C content in the fruits of watermelon by 36.7% was achieved by using 0.05% concentration of Pentakeep V in spraying dose of 1,000 l.ha.
Key words: watermelon, 5 aminolevulinic acid, yield, nitrates, vitamin C, Pentakeep</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN">978-80-552-1158-9</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Book</dc:type>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>