<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="SK2016011139">
    <dc:title xml:lang="sk">Úroda a zloženie semena hrachu siateho v závislosti od podmienok pestovania</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>Yield and composition of pea seeds in dependence on growing condition</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Candráková Eva</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Panáková Zuzana</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Slovak University of Agriculture, Nitra, Slovak Republic</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Peas</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Yields</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Production</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_13177</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8488</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6200</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Field polyfactorial experiment with common pea, variety Audit was conducted in warm climate area in years 2011, 2012 and 2013. The altitude of the locality is 175 m. There was studied the impact of factors on the yield and quality of seeds pea. The soil cultivation methods O1 - conventional (plowing to a depth of 0.24 my, O2 - reduced (plowing to a depth of 0,15 m), O3 - minimalization (loosening the soil to a depth of 0.12 m). Variants of fertilization (H1 - control treatment without fertilization, H2 - inorganic fertilizers (P and K), H3 - inorganic fertilizers with plowing of forecrop residues of preceding crop (wheat). Temperature and water condition in the individual years were different. The significantly highest yield of pea seeds was reached in 2011 (3.41 t.ha) and the lowest yield was in 2012 (1.77 t.ha), Alike, low yield was also in 2013 (1.90 t.ha). Ti/lage treated for the yield of pea seeds was statistically significant in favor of the conventional method (2.44 t.ha] with a minimum difference with the minimization method (2.42 t.ha}. Aplication of the fertilizers with crop residues influenced the yield of pea seeds high significantly (2.53 t.ha). Statistically significant difference, compared to the control tretament (2.08 t.ha), was only when the inorganic ferti/izers were used of (2.47 t.ha). The content protein and starch in pea seeds was influenced by the terms of years and variants of fertilization. The highest content protein in pea seeds was in 2012 (28.14%) and the lowest content protein was in 2011 (20.64%). Between content protein and starch was found to be highly dependent indirect correlation (r= -0.59++).</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Agrochémia</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1335-2415</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.19/n.2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>