<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016P11311">
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">ГЕНОТИПИЧЕСКИЕ ФАКТОРЫ, ВЛИЯЮЩИЕ НА ХАРАКТЕР ОНТОГЕНЕЗА  ТЕЛОК ЧЕРНО-ПЕСТРОЙ ПОРОДЫ</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>GENOTYPIC FACTORS INFLUENCING THE NATURE OF THE ONTOGENY  OF BLACK-MOTLEY BREED HEIFERS</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Baymishev  H.B.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Grigoriev  B.C.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Yakimenko  L.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Baymishev  M.H.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Animal genetics</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">breeding</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_49986</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_49902</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>Key words: genotype, growth, development, precocity, fertility, childbirth, parturition</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">В статье приведены данные об интенсивности роста и развития телок в раннем постнатальном онтогенезе в зависимости от породы и линейной принадлежности. На основании сравнительной оценки динамики изменения живой массы и воспроизводительных качеств телок с разной линейной принадлежностью черно-пестрой, голштинской пород установлено, что в условиях интенсивной технологии производства молока, животные голштинской породы линии Монтвик Чифтэйн превосходят по интенсивности роста и репродуктивным показателям своих сверстниц черно-пестрой породы и телочек линии Рефлекшен Соверинг по голштинской породе.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Data on the growth intensity and development of heifers in early postnatal ontogenesis period, depending on the breed and the linear facilities are presented in the article. Based on the comparative evaluation of dynamics of live weight changes and reproductive qualities of heifers with different linear affiliation of black-motley, Holstein breed it is established that in the conditions of intensive technology of milk production, animals of Holstein breed of Montvik Chifteyn line surpass the growth rate and exceed on reproductive performance in comparison with their peer heifers of black-motley breed and heifers from Reflekshen Sovering line of Holstein breed.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://media.wix.com/ugd/3e7d27_c17f1fe3d60b428e9faf26082c2e7dd6.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Success of Modern Science and Education</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2412-9631</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.6/n.№1, 2015</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>