<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016P11841">
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">ОСОБЕННОСТИ ФОРМИРОВАНИЯ ИННОВАЦИОННЫХ СТРАТЕГИЙ РАЗВИТИЯ АГРОПРОМЫШЛЕННОГО КОМПЛЕКСА</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>FEATURES OF FORMATION OF INNOVATIVE STRATEGIES OF AGRICULTURE SECTOR</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Godina  O.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Maksimenko  L.S.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Marakhovskaya  G.S.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">E14</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Policies</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6062</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>Key words: innovative development of agricultural sector, innovation potential, assessment of readiness for in-novative changes, innovative strategy of agribusiness development, strategic issues, management mechanism of innovative development of agriculture</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">В статье раскрыты особенности процесса формирования благоприятных  условий развития инновационной системы в АПК, проблемный характер инновационных процессов в экономике аграрного сектора,  доказана необходимость выбора стратегии инновационного развития АПК региона исходя из оценки степени готовности к инновационным изменениям, что позволило обосновать порядок формирования инновационных стратегий  развития АПК региона в зависимости от уровня инновационного потенциала его субъектов.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The article reveals peculiarities of the formation process of favorable conditions for the development of innovative systems in the agricultural sector. The problematic nature of innovation processes in the economy of the agricultural sector is considered in the article. The necessity of choosing the strategy of innovative development of agribusiness in the region based on the assessment of readiness for innovative changes is proved here. That allowed justifying the order of formation of innovative development strategies of agribusiness in the region depending on the level of innovative potential of its subjects.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://media.wix.com/ugd/3e7d27_1660bd039ef74b5e8074835a507147b0.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Success of Modern Science and Education</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2412-9631</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.9/n.№2, 2015</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>