<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016P11809">
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">СИСТЕМА ЗАЩИТЫ КАРТОФЕЛЯ ПРЕПАРАТАМИ ЗАО «БАЙЕР»  В РЕПРОДУКЦИОННОМ СЕМЕНОВОДСТВЕ СОРТА ГАЛА</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>THE SYSTEM OF POTATO PROTECTION BY USING PRODUCTS OF THE CLOSED JOINT STOCK COMPANY “BAYER” IN REPRODUCTION SEED FARMING OF GALA BREED</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Churakov  A.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Stupnitskiy  D.N.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F03</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">seed production</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6937</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>Key words: potato, methods of plants protecting, seed farming, weeds</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Картофель является важной сельскохозяйственной культурой, позволяющей при соответствующем уровне агротехники получать высокую урожайность. Однако интенсивное развитие заболеваний и конкуренция с сорными растениями приводят к значительному недобору урожаев. В настоящее время на рынке имеется большое количество пестицидов, разрешённых к применению, однако отсутствие обоснованной системы применения препаратов зачастую снижает их эффективность. С целью производственной проверки системы защиты картофеля ЗАО «Байер» на полях Красноярского ГАУ был заложен производственный опыт. В борьбе с сорняками (Avena fatua, Echinochloa crusgalli, Setaria viridis и glauca, Capsella bursa-pastoris, Cannabis ruderalis) эффективность до 95 % показал гербицид Зенкор Ультра в сочетании с последующим окучиванием. При выстраивании системы защиты от возбудителей грибных и бактериальных болезней, переносчиков вирусов эффективно использовать: при посадке «Престиж». По вегетирующим растениям: первая обработка «Сектин Феномен» + «Биская», вторая – «Инфинито» + «Биская», третья – «Пеннкоцеб». При отсутствии в технологии возделывания картофеля защиты от фитофтороза поражение листьев растения составляло более 50%. В варианте с применением фунгицидов проявление признаков заболевания сократилось в два и более раза. Обеспечивает дозревание клубней комбинированный способ удаления ботвы, включающий скашивание и последующее опрыскивание десикантом «Реглон». Применение полной схемы защиты картофеля позволило получить товарную урожайность 27,8 т/га при средней массе товарного клубня 95 г. В контрольном варианте (без применения гербицида) товарная урожайность достоверно ниже и составила 21,8 т/га, масса клубня снизилась на 10 г.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Potato is an important agricultural crop, which allows obtaining high crop-production power in relevant level of agro technology. However the intensive development of diseases, competition with weeds leads to shortage in bearing. Nowadays there is variety of pesticides, that are allowed to use, but the lack of a scientifically grounded system of the usage of those products leads to their efficiency decreasing. Aiming to production testing of a system of potato protection, the close corporation “Bayer” has carried out a production experiment on the KrasSAU fields. Herbicide Zenkor Ultra followed by earthing up showed the efficiency up to 95 % to eliminate weeds (Avena fatua, Echinochloa crusgalli, Setaria viridis и glauca, Capsella bursa-pastoris, Cannabis ruderalis). Usage of “Prestige” while planting time is efficient for building a system of protection from mycogenous and bacteriosis agents and transmitters. “Sektin-Fenomen” + “Biskaya” are used to make the first treatment</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">“Infinito” + “Biskaya” are used to make the second treatment</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">“Penkotseb” is used to make the third treatment during vegetation period. If there is absence of protection from late blight of potato in its handle technology, the affection of the leaves of the plant was more than 50%. Using the fungicides reduced the signs of the disease two or more times. The combined method of removing halm, including slanting and applying desiccant “Reglon”, provides after ripening of the tubers. Using the full scheme of potato protection allowed obtaining 27.8 t/ha, the average weight of tuber was 95 gr. The productivity without usage of herbicide was lower: 21.8 t/ha, the average weight of tuber lowered 10 gr.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://media.wix.com/ugd/3e7d27_1660bd039ef74b5e8074835a507147b0.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Success of Modern Science and Education</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2412-9631</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.6/n.№2, 2015</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>