<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016P11805">
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">ВЛИЯНИЕ УСЛОВИЙ ПОСЕВА И ПРЕДПОСЕВНОЙ ОБРАБОТКИ СЕМЯН СОРГО ПРЕПАРАТАМИ НА РАСПРОСТРАНЕННОСТЬ И РАЗВИТИЕ АЛЬТЕРНАРИОЗА В ЛЕСОСТЕПИ САМАРСКОЙ ОБЛАСТИ</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>INFLUENCE OF CONDITIONS OF CROPS AND PRESEEDING PROCESSING OF SEEDS OF THE SORGHUM BY PREPARATIONS ON PREVALENCE AND ALTERNARIOZ DEVELOPMENT IN THE FOREST-STEPPE OF THE SAMARA REGION</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Matvienko  E.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Syrkina  L.F.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Antimonov  A.K.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Antimonova  O.N.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">cultivation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2018</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>Key words: sorghum, crops conditions, prevalence, grades</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Следует отметить, что оптимальные условия для развития альтернариоза на листьях сорго складываются при повышенном количестве осадков в июне, августе и сентябре в сочетании с жарким и засушливым июлем, что и наблюдалось в 2011 г. Посев семян с поливом почвы способствовал повышению устойчивости растений к альтернариозу особенно у сахарного сорго, в меньшей степени у зернового сорго сорта Премьера. Для повышения устойчивости сорго к альтернариозу рекомендуются предпосевная обра-ботка семян системным препаратом инсектофунгицидом Престиж и биопрепаратом Фитоспорин, посев се-мян во влажную почву.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">It should be noted that optimum conditions for development of an alternarioz on leaves of sorghum are summarised at the raised amount of precipitation in June, August and September in combination with hot and droughty July, as was observed in 2011. Crops of seeds with watering of the soil contributed to the increase of plants resistance to an alternarioz especially at sugar sorghum, in lesser degree at grain sorghum of “Premiera” varietiy. For increase of sorghum resistance to an alternarioz it is recommended to organize the preseeding processing of seeds by a system preparation insektofungitsidy Prestige and by a biological product Fitosporin and to crop seeds to the damp soil.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://media.wix.com/ugd/3e7d27_1660bd039ef74b5e8074835a507147b0.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Success of Modern Science and Education</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2412-9631</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.4/n.№2, 2015</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>