<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016P11142">
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">РАСЧЕТЫ ПРОЦЕССОВ СУШКИ ДУБОВЫХ КЛЕПОК В ОРОШАЕМЫХ  ШТАБЕЛЯХ ПРИ СОЗРЕВАНИИ</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>CALCULATION PROCESSES OF OAK STAVES DRYING IN IRRIGATED STACKS  WHEN MATURING</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Panahov T.M.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">Q02</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">food processing</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Preservation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_37969</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6171</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>Key words: drying time, irrigation, stave, moisture, density</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Климат Азербайджана не позволяет проводить сушку-созревание дубовой клепки без предварительного увлажнения или орошения. Исследования показали, что сушка клепок поверхностных слоев древесины составила 22% в течение 8 часов. Также была определена динамика сушки дубовых клепок с различным анатомическим строением и физическими свойствами древесины, в частности плотностью и пористостью. В результате установлено, что сушка клепок до 22%, необходимая для развития грибов-пионеров, проходит ориентировочно за период орошение – за 8 часов и сушки – 8 часов для одних суток.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The Azerbaijan Climate prevents the drying-ripening of oak staves without pre-wetting or irrigation. Researches show that staves drying of the surface layers of wood were equal to 22% for 8 hours. It was also determined the dynamics of oak staves drying with different anatomical structure and physical properties of wood, in particular with index of density and porosity. The results showed that the staves drying to 22% which is necessary for the mushrooms-pioneers development is extended approximately over the periods of irrigation and drying (8 hours, respectively) within one day.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://media.wix.com/ugd/3e7d27_c17f1fe3d60b428e9faf26082c2e7dd6.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Success of Modern Science and Education</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2412-9631</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.4/n.№1, 2015</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>