<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016P11836">
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">АНАЛИЗ ПРОИЗВОДСТВА СЕЛЬСКОХОЗЯЙСТВЕННОЙ ПРОДУКЦИИ В ЕАЭС И ПЕРСПЕКТИВЫ ЕГО РАЗВИТИЯ</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>ANALYSIS OF AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTION IN THE EURASIAN ECONOMIC UNION AND PROSPECTS OF ITS DEVELOPMENT</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Kovaleva V.D.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">E16</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">production economics</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_26808</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>Key words: Eurasian Economic Union, the integration processes, coordination, agricultural production, prod-ucts, controlling instrumentation, accounting system, strategic development</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">В статье представлены результаты анализа производства сельскохозяйственной продукции Евразийского экономического союза,  раскрыты основные аспекты координации интеграционных процессов его развития, основанные на инструментарии контроллинга. Предложена  методология государственного регулирования стратегии развития сельскохозяйственного производства, основанная на совершенствовании бухгалтерского учета в соответствии с МСФО.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The article presents the results of the analysis of agricultural production of the Eurasian economic Union, explains the main aspects of coordination of integration processes of its development, based on controlling instrumentation. The methodology of the state regulation strategy for the development of agricultural production based on improvement of accounting system in accordance with IFRS is proposed.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://media.wix.com/ugd/3e7d27_1660bd039ef74b5e8074835a507147b0.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Success of Modern Science and Education</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2412-9631</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.5/n.№2, 2015</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>