<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016D03385">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">ASSESSMENT OF IMPREGNATING ABILITY OF SPERMATOZOA AND HERMAPHRODITISM CASE OF A MARSH FROG (PELOPHYLAX RIDIBUNDUS, PALLAS, 1771) IN THE CONDITIONS OF ANTHROPOGENOUSLY CHANGED LANDSCAPES</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ОЦЕНКА ОПЛОДОТВОРЯЮЩЕЙ СПОСОБНОСТИ СПЕРМАТОЗОИДОВ И СЛУЧАЙ ГЕРМАФРОДИТИЗМА У ОЗЕРНОЙ ЛЯГУШКИ (PELOPHYLAX RIDIBUNDUS</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="">
      <dcterms:alternative>PALLAS</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="">
      <dcterms:alternative>1771) В УСЛОВИЯХ АНТРОПОГЕННО-ИЗМЕНЕННЫХ ЛАНДШАФТОВ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Baytimirova Ekaterina</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Vershinin Vladimir</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Institute of Plant and Animal Ecology, Ural Branch of the Russian Academy of Sciences</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L53</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Spermatozoa</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7287</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The effect of endocrine disruptors lead to sexual development deviations and to the appearance of intersexual individuals. The increase of the number of intersexual frogs became one of the results of hormone disruptors influence on amphibians. At the same time fact about the presence of oocytes in the issues of testis is prevailing in literature. No doubt that the connections between intersexuality and fertility of sexually mature frogs needs more investigation. One of the main indicators of impregnating ability of spermatozoa is the head size. Sexually mature marsh frog males (Pelophylax ridibundus), caught in three habitats with different level of anthropogenous loading were investigated in this work. Spermatozoa heads area measurement is carried out both on the smear preparations, and on histologic preparations of a seed plant by means of the ImageJ program. A microscopic research concerning the presence of oocytes at seed plants’ tissue was carried out on serial cuts of animal seed plants. The abnormal spermatozoa quantity does not exceed 7%. The minimum head area is noted around the hermaphroditic individual capture place. The spermatozoa heads area of the hermaphrodite is smaller than the one of normal males. Research of the oocytes presence in seed plant tissue showed its’ existence only in tissue of the hermaphrodite seed plant. It is possible to refer the spermatozoa head size of a marsh frog to parameters rather sensitive to adverse effects unlike the quantity of spermatozoa. And one of probable causes of a marsh frog hermaphroditic individual emergence in the area of Yekaterinburg city, is the pollution of a spawning reservoir by the easily oxidized organic substances with hormon properties.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Воздействие эндокринных деструкторов может приводить к отклонениям полового развития и появлению интерсексуальных особей. Одним из результатов действия гормональных деструкторов на амфибий стало увеличение встречаемости интерсексуальных особей среди лягушек. При этом в литературе преобладают данные о присутствии ооцитов в ткани семенников животных. Установление связи между интерсексуальностью и плодовитостью половозрелых лягушек, несомненно, нуждается в дополнительных исследованиях. Одним из основных показателей оплодотворяющей способности сперматозоидов является размер головки. В данной работе исследовались половозрелые самцы озерной лягушки (Pelophylax ridibundus), отловленные в трех местообитаниях с разным уровнем антропогенной нагрузки. На мазковых и гистологических препаратах семенника было проведено измерение площадей головок сперматозоидов с помощью программы ImageJ. На серийных срезах семенников животных проведено микроскопическое исследование относительно присутствия ооцитов в ткани семенников. Показано, что количество аномальных сперматозоидов у животных не превышает 7%. Наименьшая площадь головок отмечена в районе поимки гермафродитной особи. Площади головок сперматозоидов гермафродита меньше по сравнению с нормальными самцами. Исследование относительно присутствия в ткани семенников ооцитов, показало их наличие только в ткани семенника гермафродита. По-видимому, размер головок сперматозоидов у озерной лягушки, можно отнести к достаточно чувствительным к неблагоприятному воздействию параметрам в отличие от количества сперматозоидов. Одной из вероятных причин появления гермафродитной особи озерной лягушки на территории города Екатеринбурга, является загрязнение нерестового водоема органическими веществами, обладающими гормоноподобными свойствами.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://dx.doi.org/10.12731/wsd-2014-10-2</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">en</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>В мире научных открытий</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2072-0831</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.10</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>