<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016D03447">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">INDUCTION OF SYSTEMIC ACQUIRED RESISTANCE OF PLANTS BY EXOMETABOLITES OF CAUSAL AGENT OF POTATO RING ROT</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ИНДУКЦИЯ СИСТЕМНОЙ ПРИОБРЕТЕННОЙ УСТОЙЧИВОСТИ РАСТЕНИЙ ЭКЗОМЕТАБОЛИТАМИ ВОЗБУДИТЕЛЯ КОЛЬЦЕВОЙ ГНИЛИ КАРТОФЕЛЯ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Omelichkina Yulia</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Boyarkina Svetlana</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Shafikova T.N.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Siberian Institute of Plants Physiologies and Biochemistry</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F62</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">effectors</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Clavibacter michiganensis</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">allergic reactions</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_27506</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33331</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3763</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Development of plant defense to the influence of the pathogen is determined by the rapid recognition. It depends on the presence of specific receptors in plants. Recognition of molecular patterns of microbial cell surface by plant receptors, which are localized in the plant cell membrane, triggers basic non-specific immunity</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">recognition of pathogen effectors by plant receptors, which are localized inside the plant cell, triggers specific immunity. Specific immunity involves the development of hypersensitive response, systemic acquired resistance and immune memory of the plant. The study of patterns and effectors as inductors of plant defenses responses is current issue to the search of biogenic activators long-term resistance of plants to a wide range of pathogens.
Clavibacter michiganensis subsp. sepedonicus (Cms) is the phytopathogenic bacterium, that causes the plant systemic disease - "ring rot of potatoes", which is one of the most common and harmful bacterial diseases. Previously it was shown that the causal agent of potato ring rot induces development of hypersensitivity reaction and systemic acquired resistance in non-host tobacco plants. In the present study it is established that the exometabolites of this pathogen (cell free culture filtrate and heat-treated bacterial suspension) also cause the development of hypersensitivity and system sustainability. The obtained results allow to assume that thermostable effector molecules, that have the ability to induce local and systemic protective response plants, are present in the composition of exometabolites of this phytopatogene.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">Развитие защитных реакций растения на воздействие патогена определяется быстрым и адекватным его распознаванием, которое зависит от наличия у растения специфических рецепторов. При распознавании мембранными рецепторами растения консервативных микробных молекулярных паттернов активируется базовый неспецифический иммунитет</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">при распознавании цитоплазматическими рецепторами эффекторных молекул патогена запускается специфический иммунитет. Последний включает развитие реакции сверхчувствительности, системной устойчивости и иммунной памяти растения. Изучение паттернов и эффекторов в качестве индукторов защитных ответов растении актуально для поиска биогенных активаторов долговременной устойчивости растений к широкому кругу патогенов. 
Clavibacter michigaпeпsis subsp. sepedoпicus (Cms) – бактериальный фито-патоген, который вызывает у растения-хозяина системное заболевание – «коль-цевую гниль картофеля», являющееся одним из наиболее распространенных и вредоносных бактериозов. Ранее было выявлено, что бактерии Cms индуцируют развитие реакции сверхчувствительности и системной приобретенной устойчивости у растения-нехозяина табака. В настоящей работе установлено, что экзо-метаболиты патогена – фильтрат, лишенный бактериальных клеток и термически инактивированная суспензия бактерий также вызывают развитие реакции сверхчувствительности и системной устойчивости. Полученные результаты позволяют полагать, что в составе экзометаболитов данного фитопатогена присутствуют термостабильные эффекторные молекулы, которые обладают способностью индуцировать локальный и системный защитный ответ растения.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://dx.doi.org/10.12731/wsd-2014-10-12</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">en</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>В мире научных открытий</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2072-0831</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.10</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>