<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="CO2016000039">
    <dc:title xml:lang="es">Influencia del virus de la tristeza de los cítricos (CTV) en el comportamiento de la lima ácida Tahití (Citrus latifolia Tanaka) injertada sobre seis patrones en el piedemonte llanero de Colombia (1997 – 2008)</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>Citrus tristeza virus (CTV) influence on the behavior of Tahiti lime (Citrus latifolia Tanaka) grafted on six rootstocks in the plain piedmont of Colombia (1997-2008)</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Chaparro Zambrano Hans Nicolás</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Velásquez R. Heberth Augusto</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2013-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">H10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Plant diseases</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">plant pathology</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">fungus control (diseases)</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Plant viruses</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5962</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5974</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3147</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5985</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>6 figs.</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="es">La lima ácida Tahití, Citrus latifolia Tanaka (Rutaceae), es susceptible al daño del virus de la tristeza de los cítricos (CTV), lo que disminuye la rentabilidad del cultivo. En la terraza alta del piedemonte de Meta, Colombia, se evaluó la influencia del virus sobre el comportamiento de la lima ácida Tahití en seis patrones: Carrizo, Sunki × English, Sunki × Jacobson, Pomeroy, Rubidoux y Kryder 15-3. El diseño experimental utilizado fue completamente al azar tomando cada árbol como unidad experimental</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">se utilizó comparación de medias y estadística inferencial para: altura de la planta, diámetro y altura de la copa, volumen de la copa, producción y severidad del virus de la tristeza. La mayor producción acumulada por árbol (kg/árbol) la obtuvo Sunki × English</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">todos  los patrones presentaron una altura homogénea, excepto Carrizo con menor tamaño y volumen de copa. La mayor producción de frutos acumulada durante ocho  cosechas se obtuvo con Sunki × English seguido por  Rubidoux y Carrizo. La mayor eficiencia productiva promedia se obtuvo con Sunki × Jacobson. La produc- ción y el crecimiento morfológico decayeron en la séptima cosecha (2007) en todos los patrones, ocasionado por la infección de una mezcla de aislados de virus de la tristeza de los cítricos tipo Madeira y tipo B128 que ocasionan acanalamiento del tallo</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">tipo B31 que produce acanalamiento moderado</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">y aislamientos B7 y VT. Palabras claves: control de enfermedades de plantas, híbridos de cítricos, longevidad de plantas, rendimiento, trópico bajo.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">Tahiti lime, Citrus latifolia Tanaka (Rutaceae), is susceptible to Citrus Tristeza Virus (CTV), and if affected, decreases the profitability of the crop. In the well-drained high terrace of the Meta piedmont, the influence of the virus attack was evaluated on the performance of Tahiti lime grafted on six rootstocks (Carrizo</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">Sunki × English</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">Sunki × Jacobson</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">Pomeroy</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">Rubidoux, y Kryder 15-3) on a completely randomized experiment design taking each tree as an experimental unit. A comparison of means and inferential statistic were used for: plant height, height and canopy diameter</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">canopy volume, yield and severity of CTV. All rootstocks showed homogenous height. Carrizo was the exception with less size and canopy volume. The highest accumulated fruit yield (Kg/tree) was obtained by Sunki x English, followed by Rubidoux and the lowest yield was obtained by Carrizo. The highest yield efficiency of average canopy volume was obtained with Sunki x Jacobson. The Tahiti lime yield and morphological development fell in the seventh year (2007) in all rootstocks, due to an infection caused by a mix of isolates of CTV type Madeira and type B128, isolates which cause stem channeling: type B31 which causes moderate stem channeling and B7 and VT isolate. Key words: plant disease control, citrus hybrids, plant longevity, yield, tropic low lands</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.corpoica.org.co/SitioWeb/Archivos/Revista/Articulo4_REVISTACORPOICAVol14No1-2013.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">es</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Revista CORPOICA : Ciencia y Tecnología Agropecuaria</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">01228706</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.14/n.2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>