<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="CO2016000067">
    <dc:title xml:lang="es">Capital social y capital financiero en la adopción de tecnologías ganaderas en zonas rurales altoandinas de Colombia</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>Social and financial capital in cattle technology adoption for high elevation Andean rural areas in Colombia</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Forero Camacho César A</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Rojas Carvajal Guillermo H.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Argüelles Cárdenas orge H.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2013-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">E13</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Cattle</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Human resources</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">economic analysis</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1391</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3684</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2469</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>4 figs., 3 tabs.34 ref.</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Technology adoption has been discussed as an alternative to strengthen rural development and solving the problems of food production in the world. However, is a decision influenced by multiple factors, which promote or not its implementation. The objective of this investigation was to establish which aspects of social and financial capital influence the adoption of technologies in rural areas where farmers practice the dual-purpose cattle production system. Methodologically, a mixed model that integrates a quantitative and qualitative approach and tools to obtain information: surveys, semi-structured interviews and focus groups, were used in a small farmers’ community in Bogotá, Colombia. The rate of technology adoption was determined by estimating weighted indices for the following subdomains: conservation, feeding, agroforestry, milking, reproduction, and health. We performed weighted indices for the components of social capital (level training, community organization, community trust, institutional trust and reciprocity) and financial capital (savings and income). Hierarchical clustering of data using multiple correspondence analyses allowed the identification of three groups of producers according to their level of adoption: innovators, early adopters and skeptics. Linear regression models established the components of social capital and financial capital with greater significance or influence on the adoption of livestock technologies. The level of training, reciprocity and community organization from the social capital, and the planning index from the financial capital are the factors that have more influence in the adoption. Key words: technology adoption, social capital, financial capital, cattle rising.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="es">La adopción tecnológica se ha planteado como una alternativa de fortalecimiento del desarrollo rural y de solución a los problemas de producción de alimentos en el mundo</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang=" ">sin embargo, es una decisión enmarcada por múltiples factores que favorecen o no su implementación. El objetivo de esta investigación fue conocer cuáles aspectos del capital social y del capital financiero influyen en la adopción de tecnolo gías en zonas rurales, donde productores campesinos desarrollan el sistema productivo ganadero de doble propósito. Se utilizó un modelo metodológico mixto que integra el enfoque cuantitativo y cualitativo y herramientas para la obtención de información: encuestas, entrevistas semiestructuradas y grupos focales, en una comunidad de pequeños productores de Bogotá, Colombia. Se determinó la tasa de adopción tecnológica a través de índices de ponderación estimados para las subdimensiones: conservación, alimen tación, agrosilvopastoriles, ordeño, reproducción y sanidad. Se realizaron índices de ponderación para los componentes del capital social (nivel de capacitación, organización comunitaria, confianza comunitaria, confianza institucional y reciprocidad) y del capital financiero (ahorros e ingresos). Se realizó un análisis de correspondencia múltiple que estableció tres grupos de productores denominados según el nivel de adopción: innovadores, tempranos y escépticos. Luego, con modelos de regresión lineal múltiple se establecieron los componentes del capital social y capital financiero con mayor significancia o influencia sobre la adopción de tecnologías ganaderas. Los factores que más influyen sobre la adopción son la capacitación, la reciprocidad y la organización comunitaria (capital social) y el índice de planificación (capital financiero). Palabras claves: adopción tecnológica, capital social, capital financiero, ganadería.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.corpoica.org.co/SitioWeb/Archivos/Revista/RevCorpoicaVol14-2cap03.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">es</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Revista CORPOICA : Ciencia y Tecnología Agropecuaria</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">01228706</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.14/n.2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>