<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X12002">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Influence of zeolite containing marl on the intensity of nitrogen, carbohydrate and lipid  metabolism in the body highly productive cows</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Влияние цеолитсодержащего мергеля на интенсивность азотистого</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="">
      <dcterms:alternative>углеводного и липидного обмена в организме высокопродуктивных коров</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Lyubin N.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Loginov G.P.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Аkhmetova V.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Каzan SAVM maned after N.E. Bauman</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L02</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Cows</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Feed additives</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Supplementary feeding</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">zeolites</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">protein feeds</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1939</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2827</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7522</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_15928</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_13616</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>3 tables,13 ref</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">We studied parameters of nitrogen, carbohydrate and lipid metabolism in blood and liver of highly productive cows. The research was carried out on cows of Holstein breed, which were divided into three groups. The first received basic household diet (BD), the second – BD + 2 %, the third – BD + 4 % of siliceous marl from the ration of dry matter. The results of the study showed an increase in the level of total protein in serum of cows of experimental groups, while reducing the content of urea in their blood. Feeding marl contributed to the increase (within limits) of glucose concentration in blood serum of cows of the 2nd and 3rd groups, as well as increased levels of volatile fatty acids (including acetic acid), cholesterol and phospholipids in the serum of their blood compared with the control. Biochemical examination of the liver tissue of the experimental animals also showed increased metabolism of proteins, carbohydrates and lipids in their body under the influence of marl. The use of natural mineral supplements - siliceous marl for highly productive cows increases the intensity of nitrogen, carbohydrate and lipid metabolism in their body. At the same time the periods of (1 phase of lactation and dry) production cycle should be viewed as critical and to take all measures for the optimization of mineral nutrition of cows.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Изучали показатели азотистого, углеводного и липидного обмена в крови и печени высокопродуктивных коров. Исследования проводились на коровах голштинской породы, которые были разделены на три группы. Первая получала основной хозяйственный рацион (ОР), вторая – ОР + 2 %, третья – ОР + 4 % кремнеземистого мергеля от сухого вещества рациона. Результаты исследования выявили увеличение уровня общего белка в сыворотке крови коров опытных групп, при одновременном снижении содержания мочевины в их крови. Скармливание мергеля способствовало  повышению (в пределах нормы) концентрации глюкозы в сыворотке крови коров 2-й и 3-й групп, а также увеличением уровня летучих жирных кислот (в т.ч. уксусной кислоты), содержания холестерина и фосфолипидов в сыворотке их крови по сравнению с контролем. Биохимическое исследование ткани печени подопытных животных также свидетельствовало об усилении обмена белков, углеводов и липидов в их организме под влиянием мергеля. Применение природной минеральной добавки - кремнеземистого мергеля  для высокопродуктивных коров повышает интенсивность азотистого, углеводного и липидного обмена в их организме. При этом периоды (1 фаза лактации и сухостойный) производственного цикла следует рассматривать как критические и принимать все меры для оптимизации минерального питания коров.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik.ugsha.ru/contentse/2-15-Lyubin.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.2(30)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>