<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016X11408">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">SUBSTANTIATION OF THE IMPACT OF AIR PARAMETERS ON THE ENERGY CONSUMPTION IN THE CONTACT TYPE GRAIN DRYERS</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>К ОБОСНОВАНИЮ ВЛИЯНИЯ ПАРАМЕТРОВ ВОЗДУХА НА ЭНЕРГОЗАТРАТЫ В ЗЕРНОСУШИЛКАХ КОНТАКТНОГО ТИПА</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Kurdyumov V.I.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Pavlushin A.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Karpenko G.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">N01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">farm equipment</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">machinery industry</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">technical properties</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">DRYERS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">drying</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_25753</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4497</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2572</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2401</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2402</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">When developing grain dryers contact type, the physical laws and physical-chemical ratios, which are subject to processes of thermal influence on the grain, and general research methods of developed mechanization and their calculations are taken into account. The process of grain drying is non-stationary and, in some cases, reversible process occurring mainly with variable (decreasing) speed, and therefore the calculation of the kinetics of this process is very difficult. The result of the calculation should be determined by the duration of heat exposure (exposure time), which under the given bandwidth UTOZ and sensitive indicators of the process determines the dimensions of the thermal camera (space, which directly processes the thermal effects on grain). In some cases practical interest is the solution of the inverse problem, i.e., calculation of optimal operating parameters, which provides the desired bandwidth of UTOZ and relevant technological requirements. The purpose of the research: to identify the impact of parameters of air while grain drying in installations of contact type on the total specific energy consumption. The theoretical patterns reflect the basic characteristics of the process of contact drying of grain in the proposed units. These dependencies can be used for optimization of parameters of air while grain drying in installations of contact type, as well as for the calculation of the other indicators of contact heat exchange process. Operation of developed mechanization of the process of drying grain at the optimum air parameters will allow to achieve high efficiency of the process.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">При разработке зерносушилок контактного типа учитывают физические законы и физико-химические соотношения, которым подчиняются технологические процессы теплового воздействия на зерно, а также общие методы проведения исследований разрабатываемых средств механизации и их расчётов. Процессы сушки зерна нестационарный и, в ряде случаев, обратимый процесс, протекающий в основном с переменной (убывающей) скоростью, и поэтому расчёт кинетики этого процесса представляет значительные трудности. В результате расчёта должна быть определена продолжительность теплового воздействия (экспозиция), которая при заданных пропускной способности УТОЗ и режимных показателях процесса определяет габариты тепловой камеры (пространства, в котором непосредственно происходят процессы теплового воздействия на зерно). В ряде случаев практический интерес представляет также решение обратной задачи, т. е. расчётное определение оптимальных режимных параметров, обеспечивающих заданную пропускную способность УТОЗ и соответствующие технологические требования. Цель проводимых исследований: выявление влияния параметров воздуха при сушке зерна в установках контактного типа на суммарные удельные энергозатраты. Полученные теоретические закономерности отражают основные характерные черты процесса контактной сушки зерна имеющего место в предложенных установках. Эти зависимости можно использовать при оптимизации параметров воздуха при сушке зерна в установках контактного типа, а также для расчёта других показателей процесса контактного теплообмена. Эксплуатация разработанных средств механизации процесса сушки зерна при оптимальных параметрах воздуха позволит достичь высокой энергоэффективности процесса.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Ulyanovsk State Agricultural Academy</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1816-4501</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.1(29)</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>