<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A11525">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">ESTIMATION OF VOLUME OF WOOD PULP WATER LOGGING IN THE RESERVOIR OF BOGUCHANSKAYA HYDROELECTRIC POWER STATION</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ОЦЕНКА ОБЪЕМА ЗАТОПЛЕНИЯ ДРЕВЕСНОЙ МАССЫ В ВОДОХРАНИЛИЩЕ БОГУЧАНСКОЙ ГЭС</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>KORPACHEV Vasily</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>PEREZHILIN Aleksandr</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>ANDRIYAS Andrey</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Siberian State Technological University</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2013-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">M40</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">water storage</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en" />
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8327</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Water-related environmental problems have not only general, but also individual properties: long term and distant consequences, cumulative effect, “self-expanding” of direct effect zones, etc. From this perspective reservoirs of large Hydroelectric Power Stations represent a powerful source of impact. Particularity of creation of Hydroelectric Power Stations in Siberia is that their reservoirs are generated by flooding of large territories of water-collecting areas, including wooded territories with large amount of trees and shrubs. During feasibility study of reservoir creation, an important stage is determination of planned volume of flooding of wood pulp, taking into account technical and economic indicators and environmental requirements. The aim of this work is estimation of flooding volume of wood in the reservoir of the Boguchanskaya hydroelectric power station (BoHPS). The BoHPS reservoir is located in central and southern taiga of south-west of the Central Siberian Plateau in the Lower Angara River Basin (57 – 60° North Latitude and 98 – 103° East Longitude). If normal water-surface elevation is 208.0 m BES (Baltic Elevation System), the total, the length along main channel is 375 km. Rate of replacement is 1.95 (50 % of flow duration). geometric reservoir volume is 58,2. Water surface area is 2,326 km2. The commercial timber logging and deforestation is necessary over the whole flooded territory of the BoHPS reservoir with the above mentioned basic characteristics. In addition, nonfulfillment of any measures must be reasoned with forecast calculations, confirming that their effect on the quality of water in the reservoir will be within statutory requirements. Appropriate forecast analysis was performed by the Members of the V.N.Sukachev Institute of Forest of the RAS Siberian branch and Institute for water and environmental problems of Far-Eastern Division of the Russian Academy of Science (FED RAS). It follows from the analysis that the contribution of trees and shrubs into the total volume of contaminants is not high, and if flooded even 12 mln. m3 wood pulp it will not greatly affect the quality of water. Therefore the flooding volume of trees and shrubs in the BoHPS reservoir is determined for five most probable options of work performance. The most favorable option in relation to flooding volume of wood is the fifth considered option, which supposes complete deforestation and clearing of felled areas. But also in this case more than 5 mln. m3 for this is that the first commercial timber logging was conducted more than 20 years ago, and now young growth and middle-aged crop constitutes 50 % of the total planted area, most of which is not merchantable wood. In any case of cleaning of the reservoir floor from forest vegetation, the volume of wood will not exceed the maximum level, which disturbs safety criterion. Meanwhile it is not enough to consider water related issues only in terms of quality of water and aquatic ecosystems, for this reason, the essential line of research is definition of regularities and estimation of the effect of water bodies changes impact on interactive ecosystems. This calls for coordination of research of many specialized scientific research institutes and environmental non-Government organizations, as well as significant financial contributions of territory will be flooded. The reason</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Произведен расчет и представлена оценка прогнозных объемов затопления (оставления) древесной массы в ложе водохранилища Богучанской ГЭС для наиболее вероятных сценариев подготовки ложа для наполнения.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://ojs.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/93/79</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.17/n.1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>