<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A03103">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">CHEMICAL PROCESSES OCCURRING IN CHIPBOARDS UNDER HOT PRESSING (BASED ON FURFUROLACETONE MONOMER FA)</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ХИМИЧЕСКИЕ ПРОЦЕССЫ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="">
      <dcterms:alternative>ПРОТЕКАЮЩИЕ ПРИ ГОРЯЧЕМ ПРЕССОВАНИИ В СТРУКТУРЕ ДРЕВЕСНО-СТРУЖЕЧНЫХ ПЛИТ НА ОСНОВЕ ФУРФУРОЛАЦЕТОНОВОГО МОНОМЕРА ФА</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>KONONOV Georgy</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>FEDOTOV Alexander</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>UGRYUMOV Sergey</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Moscow State Forest University</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Kostroma State University of Technology</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2013-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Polymerization</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Wood products</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Cellulose</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_25200</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_16203</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1423</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Alternative binding materials such as furan oligomers (for example, furfural-acetone monomer FA) can be used for improvement of operational properties of wood boards. Furan oligomers are of better water-resistance and durability in the hardened state. Use of furan resins in production of wood boards with improved physical and mechanical properties, as well as description of the chemical processes, occurring in boards structuring, are of high interest. The purpose of the work is to research and analyse the processes which occur in furan oligomer structuring (on example of furfural-acetone monomer FA) and study its interaction with the components of wood in particle boards structure. Tasks to be solved: stage analysis of chemical reactions taking place during the curing of furan oligomer, study of chemical processes during the interaction of wood particles with furfuralacetone monomer FA. Chemical process of furfural-acetone monomer FA curing and its interaction with the components of wood is developed on the base of well-known theoretical propositions of high molecular chemistry. It is known that two main components of monomer FA (mono- and difurfurilidenacetone) are structuring autonomously in three stages. Chemical process of structuring goes on ethylene double bond (reactions of polymerization) and in a carbonyl group (polycondensation reaction) at the first stage. Oligomerization on ethylene double bond and on carbonyl group continues at the second stage. At the third stage of the curing, resin is not in melt and soluble condition which is a characteristic feature of spatial polymers. From the chemical point of view, reaction of polymerization flows on double bonds of furan ring at this stage. Difurfurilidenacetone is also curing in three stages. Reaction of polymerization flows due to exhaustion of unsaturated bonds of aliphatic chain at the first stage. The process of polymerization in double bonds of aliphatic groups with increasing of molecular weight of macromolecules continues at the second stage. Polymerization of difurfurilidenacetone occurs on double bonds of furan ring with formation of unmelted and insoluble polymer at the third stage. Distributing among the particles of wood filler, furan oligomer improves water resistance of boards due to blocking of free hydroxyl groups of cellulose. This kind of lock is achieved by means of formation of a dense hydrogen bond networks between heterocyclic oxygens of monofurfurilidenacetone and hydrogens of unrelated hydroxyl groups of cellulose. Heterocyclic oxygen of monofurfurilidenacetone has a high electronegativity due to the presence of four unpaired electrons and displacement of p-electron density of two adjacent multiples of C-C bonds. Therefore, a partial negative charge appears on it and a partial positive charge appears on hydrogen of unrelated hydroxyl group of cellulose. Thus, the conditions for formation of hydrogen bonds, which block penetration of moisture into wood boards are created. Water resistance and durability are improved. The process of chemical interaction of components of wood with the components of binder due to formation of dense hydrogen-bond networks between unrelated hydroxyl groups of cellulose and oxygens of furan rings is developed. Improvement of physical and mechanical properties of boards achieved by blocking of free hydroxyl groups of cellulose by means of binding material is revealed.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Рассмотрены химические процессы структурирования фурфуролацетонового мономера ФА, применяемого в производстве древесностружечных плит, и его взаимодействия с компонентами древесины. На основе известных теорий определены химические реакции автономного структурирования двух основных компонентов мономера ФА – моно- и дифурфурилиденацетона с образованием пространственного полимера. Приведены химические процессы, отражающие адгезионное взаимодействие фуранового олигомера с компонентами древесины.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://ojs.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/122/124</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.19/n.3</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>