<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A11366">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">ON THE OCCASION OF THE CENTENARY OF BIRTH OF ALEXANDER KONSTANTINOVICH DENISOV (5 December 1913 – 22 January 1991)</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>К 100-ЛЕТИЮ АЛЕКСАНДРА КОНСТАНТИНОВИЧА ДЕНИСОВА (5 декабря 1913 года – 22 января 1991 года)</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>DENISOV Sergey</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Volga State University of Technology</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2013-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">forestry</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3055</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">On the 5th of December 2013 Alexander Konstantinovich Denisov (prominent forester, Doc-tor of Agricultural Sciences, Professor, participant of the Great Patriotic War) could be 100 years. A.K.Denisov made a great contribution to the study of floodplain Oak forests growing in the North of the European part of Russia. Many of his works concern the problems of genesis of floodplain Oak forest, ecological and biological peculiarities of English Oak (Quercus robur L.) in floodplains (northern bound of its areal). A.K.Denisov offered a detailed analysis of post glacial dynamics of northern Oak growth in a number of his papers. Biological and ecological peculiarities of Oaks allowing to form native floodplain forests were elaborated for the first time. A typology of floodplain forests of southern taiga (European territory) was also elaborated. A problem of water-protective role of forests and floodplain Oak forests and forestry management in riverain forests in particular takes a significant place in his researches and publications. A.K.Denisov also revealed the reasons of frost cleft appearance at the Oak stems (frost clefts sharply reduce marketability of Oak stands) and offered silvicultural measures for prevention of this phenomenon. Most papers of А.К.Denisov are still of current importance.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Значительный вклад А. К. Денисов сделал в изучение пойменных дубовых лесов Севера европейской части России. В работах учёного впервые были раскрыты биологические и экологические свойства дуба, позволяющие ему формировать коренные пойменные леса, им разработана типология пойменных лесов южной европейской тайги. Значительная часть работ А. К. Денисова является актуальной и в настоящее время.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://ojs.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/127/116</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.20/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>