<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A17150">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">SIMULATION MODEL FOR DYNAMICS ESTIMATION OF SCOTS PINE BIOMASS</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ИМИТАЦИОННАЯ МОДЕЛЬ ДИНАМИКИ ФИТОМАССЫ ДЕРЕВЬЕВ СОСНЫ ОБЫКНОВЕННОЙ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>STARTSEV Aleksey</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Nizhny Novgorod State Academy of Agriculture</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2016-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">forestry</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3055</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The paper is aimed at the development of a simulation model for estimation of Scots Pine growth. The model features nine phase variables: stem mass (volume), biomass of branches, needles, tender and thick roots, bark, gross annual photosynthesis, carbohydrate reserve and increment. The growth rate of a woody plant depends on the total amount of carbohydrates synthesized by the tree throughout the vegetation period. This value is based on the level of soil fertility and humidity, density of the wood stand, tree position in the canopy which defines the level of crown shading. Individual characteristics of the growth rate arising as a result of hereditary properties are taken into consideration. These include height growth rate, biomass increment rate, etc. Conclusion. The model developed allows calculating biometric indicators and biomass of certain tree components aged from 2 to 120-150 years. Model verification was carried out using the data from 48 cut down pine trees aged from 37 to 145 years. The determination coefficient (R2) amounted 0.849 for stems, 0.714 for needles and 0.72 for branches. The model is well adaptable for other tree species.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Разработана имитационная модель роста деревьев сосны обыкновенной. Модель имеет девять фазовых переменных: масса (объём) ствола, фитомасса ветвей, хвои, тонких, толстых корней, коры, валовый годичный фотосинтез, фонд запасных углеводов и высота. Скорость роста дерева зависит от общего количества углеводов, синтезируемых растением в течение вегетационного периода. Разработанная модель позволяет вычислять биометрические показатели и фитомассу отдельных компонентов деревьев в возрасте от двух до 120–150 лет.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://journals.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/349/352</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.29/n.1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>