<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A17143">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">AGE STRUCTURE OF PINUS SYLVESTRIS L. COENOPOPULATIONS IN MIDDLE-AGED PINE FORESTS IN THE KOLA PENINSULA</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ВОЗРАСТНАЯ СТРУКТУРА ЦЕНОПОПУЛЯЦИЙ СОСНЫ В ПОСТПИРОГЕННЫХ СЕВЕРОТАЁЖНЫХ ЛЕСАХ КОЛЬСКОГО ПОЛУОСТРОВА</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>GORSHKOV Vadim</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>STAVROVA Natalia</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>VOLKOVA Elena</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Komarov Botanical Institute of the Russian Academy of Sciences</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2016-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">forestry</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3055</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The aim of the study was to assess the diversity of age structure of Pinus sylvestris L. coenopopulations in northern taiga Scots pine forests and woodlands of the Kola Peninsula with fire age of ~80–90. Objects. The research was carried out on 11 permanent sample plots (PSP) of the size 0.10-0.15 ha. Four types of Scots pine communities were analyzed: pine woodlands of lichen site type (Subpinetum cladinosum) (3 PSP), pine forests of lichen site type (Pinetum cladinosum) (3 PSP), pine forests of lichen-green moss site type (Pinetum cladinoso-hylocomiosum) (3 PSP) and pine forests of green moss site type (Pinetum hylocomiosum) (2 PSP). Methods. The age of Scots pine individual trees was determined by analyzing cores and cross-sections which were taken at the base of the trunk. Results. Three main forms of age distribution of Scots pine coenopopulations were distinguished оn the basis of skew and kurtosis magnitudes in the studied communities having wide range of stand basal area (6 to 29 m2/ha) and stand density (300 to 3000 ind./ha): positively asymmetrical (A), negative asymmetrical (B) and symmetrical bimodal (D). The age range of individuals in all coenopopulations was identified as narrow ( 25 m2/ha) and forest litter thickness greater than 5 cm were found to have Scots pine age distribution of the form B.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Исследовано разнообразие вариантов возрастной структуры ценопопуляций Pinus sylvestris L. в северотаёжных лишайниковых, лишайниково-зеленомошных и зеленомошных лесах, сформировавшихся после пожаров давностью 78–87 лет на территории Кольского полуострова. Установлено, что для изученных ценопопуляций сосны, имеющих широкий диапазон полноты (от 6 до 29 м2·га-1) и густоты (от 300 до 3000 экз./га) древостоев, характерны три основных формы возрастных распределений: положительно асимметричная, бимодальная и отрицательно асимметричная. На основе дискриминантного анализа выявлены параметры-предикторы (соотношение покрытий мхов и лишайников в напочвенном покрове, покрытие лишайников р. Cladina, густота и сумма площадей сечений древостоя, толщина лесной подстилки), позволяющие прогнозировать характер возрастной структуры ценопопуляций сосны обыкновенной в северотаёжных лесах начальных стадий постпирогенных сукцессий (~70–100 лет после пожара).</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://journals.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/347/350</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.29/n.1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>