<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A01535">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">EXPERIMENTAL DETERMINATION OF MAXIMUM DENSITY, OPTIMUM HUMIDITY AND SUBSIDENCE OF FOREST SOILS</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ЭКСПЕРИМЕНТАЛЬНОЕ ОПРЕДЕЛЕНИЕ МАКСИМАЛЬНОЙ ПЛОТНОСТИ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="">
      <dcterms:alternative>ОПТИМАЛЬНОЙ ВЛАЖНОСТИ И ОСАДКИ ЛЕСНОЙ ПОЧВЫ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>LISOV Vladimir</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>YAZOV Vladimir</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Saint-Petersburg State Forestry Engineering University named after S.М. Кirov</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2013-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">subsidence</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">soil compaction</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_14650</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7163</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">One of the main ways to increase efficiency of harvesting machines is to provide the tractors designed to run in specific operating conditions. The main factors affecting the performance in specific environmental and production conditions are manoeuvrability of tractor and work capacity of skid trails. In the course of development of harvest sites with low bearing capacity, necessity  of stump-to-roadside equipment is rather urgent.
The aim of this study is to determine physical and mechanical properties of forest soil affecting rutting, and to get relationship for forest soil for repeated loads and soil moisture.
The study targeted to calculate maximum density, optimum moisture and subsidence of  forest soil was conducted in November 2012 in laboratory conditions, as described in ISO 22733-2002.
10 soil samples from the cutting area were chosen for the tests. The samples were located in block 95 of the Morozov military forestry in Leningrad region.
To determine the maximum density and optimum moisture of forest soil, a compaction stand-ard instrument was used.
Based on the experimental results:
1. Maximum density (ρmax) and optimum moisture content (Wopt) of soil were defined. These values comprise:  ρmax= 1,35 g/cm3, Wоpt = 10 %.
2. The graphs of changes of subsidence   depending on the period of ramming were  made.
3. Reliability of experimental data was found with the use of Fisher's exact test and Cochran's test. Estimated value of the Fisher criterion for six runs is 0,076 – 0,124, of Cochran's test  –  0,12–0,22. In calculating of these criteria the 0,05 significance level was used. Thus, the calculation results are reliable with 95 % confidence.
Based on the experimental data the following conclusions were made:
1. After thirty blows of rammer, soil ceases to thicken.
2. At  an optimum moisture of soil, subsidence is maximal because the soil is exposed to the maximum compaction.
3. The experimental data are described by a logarithmic function. The magnitude-square is close to unity, indicating a good convergence of the logarithmic model with the obtained during the experimental research data.
4. The obtained dependences make it possible to predict the final density of soil with high probability, and consequently, to manage the process of forest soil compaction to achieve its optimal values in terms of further natural reforestation.
Scientific and practical significance of the results is to obtain additional evidence on the physical and mechanical properties of forest soils as bearing surfaces for forest machines.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Движение лесных машин по волокам сопровождается процессом накопления деформаций, в результате чего растёт глубина колеи. В результате  экспериментов получены зависимости осадки лесной почвы от количества повторных нагрузок и влажности почвы. Полученные зависимости могут быть использованы для повышения проходимости лесных машин и снижения экологического ущерба при их работе в лесу.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://ojs.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/114/100</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.20/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>