<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A04859">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">MICOBIOTA STRUCTURE IN RECREATIONAL FORESTS OF MARI EL REPUBLIC</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>СТРУКТУРА МИКОБИОТЫ В РЕКРЕАЦИОННЫХ ЛЕСАХ РЕСПУБЛИКИ МАРИЙ ЭЛ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>GAVRITSKOVA Natalia</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Volga State University of Technology</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F50</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Fungi</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Recreation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3145</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6477</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Introduction. Taking into account high importance of fungi in functioning of biogeocoenosis, the problems of micobiota inventory and revealing of peculiarities of anthropogenic changes of species diversity and structure of macromycetes are the most vital tasks of fungology. The goal of the paper is to reveal influence of recreation on species composition and on the structure of fungus- macromycetes. The objects of the research are forest communities of the Republic of Mari El with different nature and extent of recreational activity. Field methods of registration of fungus- macromycetes, geobotanical methods of assessment of species diversity and structure of macromycetes are used in the researches. Results. A detailed study of fungus-macromycetes in Mari El Republic forests (different types of forest management) was carried out</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">species composition was studied and the analysis of taxonomic and ecologo-trophic structure of the revealed macromycetes was carried out</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">complex influence of recreational loads on fungus-macromycetes of forest communities was investigated. The types of basidiomicota were revealed, reaction of the macromycetes to anthropogenic interference serve as an index of intensification of recreational impact (synanthropes are among them), showing activity in the man-disturbed plant communities and sensible species, vanishing in case of intensification of recreational load.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">Приведены результаты детального изучения грибов-макромицетов на лесных территориях Республики Марий Эл с различными видами рекреационного лесопользования</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">изучен видовой состав и проведён анализ таксономической и эколого-трофической структуры выявленных макромицетов</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">изучено комплексное влияние рекреационных нагрузок на грибы-макромицеты в лесных фитоценозах. Выделены виды ксилотрофных макромицетов, реакция которых на антропогенное вмешательство служит показателем усиления рекреационного воздействия, среди них синантропные виды, проявляющие активность в антропогеннонарушенных фитоценозах, и чувствительные виды, исчезающие при усилении рекреационной нагрузки.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://ojs.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/62/39</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.23/n.3</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>