<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A08324">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">INFLUENCE OF AERIAL INCOME OF ELEMENTS ON THEIR CIRCULATION IN FOREST ECOSYSTEMS</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ВЛИЯНИЕ АЭРАЛЬНОГО ПОСТУПЛЕНИЯ ВЕЩЕСТВ НА ИХ КРУГОВОРОТ В ЛЕСНЫХ ЭКОСИСТЕМАХ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>DEMAKOV Yuriy</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>ISAEV Alexander</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Volga State University of Technology</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>State Natural Reserve «Bolshaya Kokshaga»</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K70</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">forestry</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">chemical composition</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Cotton</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Precipitation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3055</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1794</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1926</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6161</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Results of the analysis of many source of literature in assessment of aerial income of elements in forest ecosystems and their transformation by the shelter are offered. It was shown that precipitation merges with geobiocoenosis when coming in contact with the shelter, supplying water and many nutrients which are necessary for all living beings. Penetrating the shelter, composition of precipitation changes to the great extent as precipitation does not only washes off the dust out from the leaves and becomes saturated with the metabolism products of differetnt plants and other living beings. It also leaches out a number of chemical elements from living cells, actively influencing on the biological cycle of the elements. An extent of precipitation chemical composition transformation, taking place both in summer and in winter, depends on precipitation frequency and intensity as well as the species of trees, phase of their seasonal development and conditions of growing. Results of experience in assessment of dispersion of dust emissions of cilica brick factory using textile bandages and influence of exometabolites of trees, which are precipitation solved, on cotton fibres (cellulose) decay in different biotopes were described. It was determined that a major change of an original ash content took place in all the tissue samples (in the area of dust emissions of Mari cilica brick factory, content of ash and many ash constituents has significantly increased</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">in the nearby territory, content of calcium, strontium and cuprum has, on the contrary, significantly decreased.). Most part of the elements was washed out from the tissues in the birch groves and pine forests, growing in nutrient-poor sandy soils. There was low intensity of washing out of calcium and strontium in an inundable biotope. Conclusion: trees regulate the process of mineral nutrition and biological cycle in forest ecosystems by themselves, excreting from the surface of leaves, branches and a stem all the necessary exometabolites. Composition and concentration of exometabolites depend on the species of trees and environment condition.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang=" ">Приведены результаты анализа литературных источников по оценке аэрального поступления веществ в лесные экосистемы и их трансформации пологом древостоя. Показано, что атмосферные осадки с момента своего соприкосновения с пологом леса включаются в состав биогеоценоза. Проходя сквозь полог леса, они существенным образом изменяют свой состав, не только смывая с листьев осевшую пыль, но и насыщаясь продуктами метаболизма растений и других организмов. Описаны результаты опытов по оценке рассеивания пылевых выбросов завода силикатного кирпича с использованием тканевых повязок и влияния экзометаболитов деревьев, растворённых атмосферными осадками, на разложение хлопчатобумажной ткани в различных биотопах. Сделан вывод о том, что деревья сами регулируют процесс своего минерального питания и биологический круговорот веществ в лесных экосистемах, выделяя через поверхность листвы, ветвей и ствола необходимые экзометаболиты, состав и концентрация которых зависят как от вида древесного растения, так и от условий среды.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://ojs.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/87/62</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.25/n.1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>