<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A01531">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">OPTIMUM TECHNOLOGIES OF ARTIFICIAL REGENERATION OF BLACK ALDER PLANTINGS IN FLOODPLAINS OF RUSSIAN STEPPE ZONE</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ОПТИМАЛЬНЫЕ ТЕХНОЛОГИИ ИСКУССТВЕННОГО ВОССТАНОВЛЕНИЯ НАСАЖДЕНИЙ ОЛЬХИ ЧЁРНОЙ В ПОЙМАХ РЕК СТЕПНОЙ ЗОНЫ РОССИИ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>TURCHINA Tatiana</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Federal Budgetary Institution Russian Research Institute for Silviculture and Mechanization «South-European FRES»</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2013-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Alnus glutinosa</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">artificial regeneration</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_23885</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_641</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Black Alder plantings in floodplains of the steppe zone take 10–85 % of the wooded lands. Forest stands of vegetative origin predominate. The analysis and generalisation of regional experience of Black Alder cultivation will allow to make amendments into current regulatory and procedural documents as possibility of artificial regeneration of the species is not provided in the documents.
The purpose of the research was to ground optimal processing methods  for development the areas of forest plantations. 
Influence of processing methods (ways of soil preparation, a way and a method of planta-tions establishment, terms of establishment, mixture scheme) on growth, productivity, structure of one-age plantings was defined with the use of means of mathematical statistics.
While analyzing various variants of land preparation, ploughing of soil, no leading techno-logical operation which defines better survival ability, safety of plantations and their biometric indicators was revealed. 
Forest plantations of Black Alder were created by means of sowing and planting of one- and two-year seedlings. In accordance with the results of the research, better survival ability in sowing was found: for the moment of technical reception of forest plantations it is 27 % better than in the case of planting.
In the case of uniform method of establishment, location of planting point in topography micro increase (bottom and furrow slice) has a great impact on tree growth in diameter: for sow-ing – it is negative, for planting – it is positive.
Comparison of growth course of the plantations established by means of  sowing and planting of one-year seedlings, shows advantage of the plants developing from seeds. Distinctions in growth of the plantations established by sowing and planting of two-year seedlings were not revealed.
In comparison of plantations types, mono stands have advantage over the mixed stands. Tree species-associates have a negative impact on the growth of Alder even despite similarity of ecological requirements.
Researches have revealed authentic negative influence of undergrowth density of  box-elder (Acer negundo L.) (in quantity from 1500 pieces / hectare and more) and presence in plantations of tree species–predecessor on average diameter of Black Alder.
 Results of the research have shown that limiting parameters defining success and quality of plantations is their composition and initial density.
With the use of the results of the research, a technological scheme of plantations develop-ment was developed. In the scheme ways of land preparation and ploughing of soil are differenti-ated depending on the area category. The integrated parameters are: 
- type of forest plantations - mono, composition 10 Black Alder</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">- density of planting – 4,4–4,7 thousand piece / hectare</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">- planting material – seeds, 2-year-old seedlings</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">- location of a planting place in microrelief - bottom furrow (sowing), microincrease (planting)</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">- scheme of planting (sowing) – 3,0х0,75-0,7 m</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">- spatial orientation of lines - across a current of high flood.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">Проанализирован опыт создания лесных культур ольхи чёрной в степ-ной зоне России. Изучено влияние технологических приёмов на рост и продуктивность искусственно созданных черноольшаников. Для разных категорий лесокультурных площадей предложены технологии создания лесных культур.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://ojs.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/112/98</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.20/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>