<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A04837">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">GENETIC STRUCTURE OF SEED ORCHADS AND NATURAL STANDS OF PINUS SYLVESTRIS IN THE MIDDLE VOLGA REGION</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ГЕНЕТИЧЕСКАЯ СТРУКТУРА ЛЕСОСЕМЕННЫХ ПЛАНТАЦИЙ И НАСАЖДЕНИЙ СОСНЫ ОБЫКНОВЕННОЙ В СРЕДНЕМ ПОВОЛЖЬЕ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>KRIVOROTOVA Tatiana</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>SHEIKINA Olga</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Volga State University of Technology</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F30</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Pinus sylvestris</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Seed</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">genetic code</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5912</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6927</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3215</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Genetic diversity is one of the factors providing sustainable development of forest ecosystems. Therefore, reproduction of genetic variation in the course of breeding programs implementation and artificial reforestation is an important problem. The goal of this research is to study and compare genetic structure of seed orchads, created to supply seeds for artificial reforestation, and the natural stands serving as an alternative source of seed. The seed orchards and the stands originating from the Republic of Mari El, Chuvash Republic and Penza oblast were studied in this research. Estimation of the level of genetic variation and differentiation was carried out with the use of ISSR – DNA fragments. Six ISSR primers for performance of polymerase change reaction (PCR) were used, it made it possible to amplify 215 DNA fragments. The results show that the level of genetic diversity in seed orchards compares well with the level of genetic diversity detected in natural stand from the same regions.  For example, a share of polymorphic loci in the seed orchards varied from 81.4 to 91.2 %, at that time in the stands it was from 77.2 to 88.8 %. According to Nei, genetic diversity was from 0.12 to 0.278 in the seed orchards and from 0.207 to 0.238 in the stands. Measure of diversity part between populations (Gst=0.127) and size of gene flow (Nm=3.45) indicate low isolation of Pinus sylvestris in the studied regions of Middle Volga Region which is quite normal for propagation of this species.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Проведены сравнительные исследования генетической структуры лесосеменных плантаций и насаждений сосны обыкновенной на основе анализа ISSR-фрагментов ДНК. Установлено, что лесосеменные плантации имеют уровень генетической изменчивости не ниже чем сформированные в природе насаждения. Изученные лесосеменные плантации и насаждения не отличаются большой генетической дифференциацией, и основная доля генетической изменчивости находится внутри изученных групп деревьев (87,3 %).</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://ojs.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/46/24</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.21/n.1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>