<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A11548">
    <dc:title xml:lang=" ">IMPACT OF INDUSTRIAL ENVIRONMENT ON VITALITY AND TANNIN CONTENT IN THE LEAVES OF WOODY PLANTS (NABEREZHNYE CHELNYCASE STUDY)</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ВЛИЯНИЕ ТЕХНОГЕННОЙ СРЕДЫ НА ЖИЗНЕННОЕ СОСТОЯНИЕ И СОДЕРЖАНИЕ ТАНИНОВ (НА ПРИМЕРЕ ГОРОДА НАБЕРЕЖНЫЕ ЧЕЛНЫ) В ЛИСТЬЯХ ДРЕВЕСНЫХ РАСТЕНИЙ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>BUHARINA Irina</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>KUZMIN Peter</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Udmurt State University</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Branch of Kazan (Volga) Federal University</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2013-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F40</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">plant ecology</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5963</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The growth rate of industry and a growing number of vehicles results in loss of vitality of wood plants. Various metabolites, such as, vitamins, ferments, pigments, hormones, phenol compounds, are involved in adaptive reactions of plants to the conditions of technogenic stress. Phenol compounds in plants perform protective functions. Phenol compounds, in particular tannins play an important role in formation of adaptive reactions of woody plants in polluted environment. The aim of this work is to explore the features of dynamics of tannin content in leaves of woody plants as part of antioxidant protective system in plantations with different level of technogenic impact, and to define vitality of woody plants in different functional zones of Naberezhnye Chelny, to determine defects of woody plants, growing in different plantation types, to analyze the dynamics of tannin content in leaves of woody plants. The research is aimed at AcernegundoL., AcerplatanoidesL., Tiliacordata Mill., Populusbal samifera L. The species under study grow in the city within different environmental plantations: along highways and sanitary protection zones of industrial enterprises, which are the main contamination sources of the city. The territories of Chelninskiy and Elabuzhskiy forest districts are chosen as areas of conventional control, and the area of the city park Grenada is chosen for alien species. The content of condensed tannins in leaves of woody plants was tested three times during the period of vegetation (in June, July, August), using Leventhal method modified by Kursanov. The analysis of soils and plant species was conducted in Ecology and Plant Physiology laboratory of Biology Faculty of the branch of Kazan (Volga Region) Federal University. The analysis revealed that soils in plantations of sanitary protection zones of industrial enterprises were characterized by subacid and faintly alkaline reaction, average to high content of organic compounds, nitrate nitrogen concentration on the level of 247–300 mg/kg and ammonium nitrogen concentration on the level of 6.1–15.6 mg/kg. The soils in plantations along highways had: faintly alkaline reaction</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">organic compounds at low concentrations</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">medium to low ammonium nitrogen, nitrate nitrogen and labile phosphorus concentration</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">high to very high concentration of exchange potassium. The city plantations of different ecological types are characterized by loss of vitality, it is caused by severe damage of limbs and necrosis of leaves, by reduction in leaf area index. Woody plants in plantations with higher anthropogenic impact have different defects such as, frost cracks, inbarks (opened and closed), barrel curvature, mechanical defects, side drought, decurrent branching, dead branches in krone, marginal leaf necrosis, all these defects are the consequence of intensive man-caused impact. The content of condensed tannins in leaves of the wood plat species under study is constantly increasing during the whole vegetation season and reaches its maximum in August. Notably, the concentration of this metabolite in leaves of the studied species (except for Populus balsamifera L.), growing in plantations of sanitary protection zones of industrial enterprises and along highways, was significantly reduced in comparison with the level of tannin content in conventional control zone.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">Выявлено воздействие техногенной среды на жизненное состояние и формирование патологий у изучаемых видов растений. Изучена динамика содержания танинов в листьях древесных растений, произрастающих в насаждениях различных функциональных зон города. Показано участие данного метаболита в формировании приспособительных реакций древесных растений к условиям техногенной среды.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://ojs.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/96/82</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.17/n.1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>