<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A01542">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">STANDS DYNAMICS IN FLOODPLAIN FORESTS OF «BOLSHAYA KOKSHAGA» RESERVE</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ДИНАМИКА ДРЕВОСТОЕВ В ПОЙМЕННЫХ ЛЕСАХ ЗАПОВЕДНИКА «БОЛЬШАЯ КОКШАГА»</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>ISAEV Alexander</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>DEMAKOV Yuriy</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>State Natural Reserve «Bolshaya Kokshaga»</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Volga State University of Technology</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2013-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">composition</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Productivity</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">dynamics</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_331025</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6210</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_330860</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The dynamics data (1995-2010 years) of composition and productivity of complex-mixed stands are offered. The data were obtained due to regular control at the three permanent sample sites, located in the central zone of the floodplain of the Bolshaya Kokshaga. Dependance between current trees increment and their original size were estimated. Tendencies for trees mortality were revealed.
It was determined that number of trees and total basal area of their stems has increased for  15 years. The scale of current mortality of trees fluctuated from year to year, sometimes it was 23 pcs./ha. Mean diameter of trees was varying in different species</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">it depended on stems increment, addition of young trees and mortality of some trees. The size of current increment of different spe-cies was measured in very large bounds. Aspen had the biggest increment, Elm had the least increment. Trees increment in diameter had a faint dependence on their original diameter.  Dependence of basal increment on their original diameter was rather tight. Trees increment was not stable in the course of time: some trees had constant increment or otherwise, sometimes change of increment (in the both directions) was observed.
A clear tendency for consolidation of former positions of Lime at all the sampling areas was traced. A tendency for losing positions of other species, Oak in particular, was found. Existence of Oak population in the future is proplematic.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">Приведены данные по динамике состава и производительности сложных смешанных древостоев за период с 1995 по 2010 гг., полученные путём регулярных учётов на трёх постоянных пробных площадях, заложенных в центральной части поймы реки Большая Кокшага. Оценена зависимость между текущим приростом деревьев и их исходным размером. Выявлены тенденции процесса накопления древесного отпада.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://ojs.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/116/102</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.20/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>