<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A17153">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">TECHNOLOGICAL IMPROVEMENTS IN USING CONTROL LINES IN FIGHTING FOREST FIRES IN AREAL APPLICATION ZONES</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>СОВЕРШЕНСТВОВАНИЕ ТЕХНОЛОГИЙ СОЗДАНИЯ ЗАГРАДИТЕЛЬНЫХ И ОПОРНЫХ ПОЛОС ПРИ ТУШЕНИИ ЛЕСНЫХ ПОЖАРОВ В ЗОНАХ ЛЕСОАВИАЦИОННЫХ РАБОТ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>ERITSOV Andrey</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>GUSEV Vitaly</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Saint Petersburg Forestry Research Institute</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2016-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K70</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">forestry</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3055</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Introduction. The problem of forest fires going out of control and damaging housing units and whole settlements due to rapid flame propagation has become vitally important in Russia. The goal of the current research is to analyze the aerial firefighting techniques including creation of control lines with the use of helicopters for forest fire management. We also attempted to determine the optimal parameters of concentration of fire-extinguishing compositions and flight modes during aerial operations. For the purpose of this research we set the following sub-goals: the analysis of aviation technologies used in aerial firefighting</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">and the characteristics of certain helibuckets tested onsite and used for ceating control lines. The approaches applied in the research were experimentally tested onsite with new improved equipment, as well as new foams and wetting agents. Results and conclusions. The paper analyses the water dropping helicopter units, comparatively presents their technical characteristics as well as field results. Based on the results of the experiments carried out we argue that the use of helibuckets equipped with foam shooting systems significantly increases the efficiency of helicopter use in extinguishing forest fires. The efficiency of advanced new helicopter techniques and technologies applied in fighting forest fires was scientifically proved in the paper and can be applicable particularly to remote areas. A list of recommendations concerning the use of new helicopter technologies for prevention and suppression of forest fires was developed.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">Рассмотрены актуальные вопросы борьбы с лесными пожарами, проблемы перехода пожаров на сопредельные территории, обоснована необходимость развития современных авиационных технологий тушения лесных пожаров. Представлен опыт совершенствования авиационных технологий создания опорных и заградительных полос для тушения пожаров в удалённых районах. Отмечены преимущества применения вертолётной техники в сравнении с самолётами-танкерами, обоснована необходимость применения вертолётных водосливных устройств ВСУ-5А с системой дозированной подачи смачивателя СДП-1 и ВВСУ УКТП «Пурга». Установлено, что использование вертолётных водосливных устройств с системой дозированной подачи смачивателя и пенообразователя существенно повышает эффективность применения вертолётов на тушении лесных пожаров. Представлены технические характеристики вертолётных водосливных устройств, сравнительные результаты их испытаний, а также рекомендации по их применению.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://journals.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/350/353</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.29/n.1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>