<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A10426">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">HIGH TEMPERATURES INFLUENCE ON WOODY PLANTS CONDITION AND THEIR PATHOGENS IN PROTECTIVE STANDS OF LOWER VOLGA REGION</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ВЛИЯНИЕ ВЫСОКИХ ТЕМПЕРАТУР НА СОСТОЯНИЕ ДРЕВЕСНЫХ РАСТЕНИЙ И ИХ ПАТОГЕНОВ В ЗАЩИТНЫХ НАСАЖДЕНИЯХ НИЖНЕГО ПОВОЛЖЬЯ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>SKURATOV Ilya</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>KRUKOVA Elena</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Russian Research Agroforestry Institute</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K70</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">diseases</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">plants</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_49879</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5993</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The studies were carried out in 2014 (dry year) in protective stands of different purpose and design, and in the greeneries of the Volgograd region. The analysis for thermal stability of woody plants is carried out on the basis of the analysis of the range of structural changes for the crowns of trees. It was determined that various tree species, used to establish protective forest stands, considerably differed from each other on drought resistance and thermal influence. European white birch, European wild apple, wild pear tree, Siberian pea shrub, and Common horse chestnut were the species to have suffered from the drought in 2014 most of all. Black locust, Norway maple, and Canadian maple are the species of mean stability to high temperatures. Siberian elm, Black poplar, English oak (pyramidical), European ash, and Green ash were found to be the most thermally stable species. Thus, it is desirable to plant them establishing the protective stands on the south-eastern part of Russia. Thermal injuries of woody plants in the stands provoke weakening of the trees and noncontagious diseases occurrence. Carcinous and vascular malformations are considered to be the most dangerous. In hot summers, number of powdery mildew, infectious mottling, and rots decreases.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Приведены результаты исследований влияния экстремально высокой температуры воздуха, отмечавшейся летом 2014 года, на состояние древесных растений в защитных лесных насаждениях и посадках урбоэкосистем Волгоградской области. Установлено, что наиболее термически повреждѐнными оказались берѐза повислая, яблоня лесная, груша лесная, карагана древовидная, а особенно каштан конский. Среднюю степень устойчивости имеют робиния лжеакация и ряд видов клѐна. Наиболее устойчивы к термическим повреждениям вяз приземистый, тополь чѐрный, дуб черешчатый, ясени ланцетный и обыкновенный. Степень устойчивости к высоким температурам сопряжена с толерантностью деревьев к инфекционным болезням.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://ojs.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/75/52</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.26/n.2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>