<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A11519">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">CONSUMPTION AND REMOVAL OF ASH CONSTITUENTS FROM WOODEN PLANTS IN THE INUNDATED BIOTOPE</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ПОТРЕБЛЕНИЕ И ВЫНОС ДРЕВЕСНЫМИ РАСТЕНИЯМИ ЗОЛЬНЫХ ЭЛЕМЕНТОВ В ПОЙМЕННОМ БИОТОПЕ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>DEMAKOV Yuriy</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>ISAEV Alexander</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>SHVETSOV Andrey</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Volga State University of Technology</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>State Natural Reserve «Bolshaya Kokshaga»</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2013-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K70</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">plants</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Fraxinus</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5993</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3086</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Data on ash composition of wood of 13 various tree types growing in short-term flooding biotope are provided. It has been concluded that the contents of calcium forming the basis of the cell wall is the highest in all tree types. Then follows kalium. Iron, manganese, strontium and zinc are one order less in the wood. Ni, Pb, Co and Cd are at the end of the range. The amount of elements under study found in ashes constitutes roughly 49.3 %, varing from 39.4 % for black alder to 54.8 % for English oak. The content of ash and ash constituents in different types of trees varies significantly. Based on the coefficient of variation the elements are ranged as follows: Fe&gt; Cd&gt; Co&gt; Pb&gt; K&gt; Zn&gt; Mn&gt; Ca&gt; Ni&gt; Sr&gt; Cu&gt; Cr. Tree species significantly differ from each other depending on the efficiency of nutrients consumption. Rough-bark poplar requires more mineral substances to produce 1 kg timber. European white elm features a little lower value. These two tree species consume most calcium and potassium. Siberian larch is the one that uses soil potential most effectively with the contents of ash 7.4 times less than poplar‘s. When carrying out clear cutting procedures most of the ash elements are removed from the forest. It is especailly true for calcium and kalium. This lack of mineral elements has to be replenished for sustainability of biogeocenosis. The gross annual consumption of major mineral elements has been conducted as well as their total accummulation in the stem wood and removal beyond biogeocenosis when clear cutting accurs.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Приведены данные по зольному составу древесины 13 различных пород деревьев, произрастающих в краткопойменном биотопе. Проведен расчет валового годичного потребления насаждениями основных минеральных веществ, их общего накопления в стволовой древесине и выноса за пределы биогеоценоза при рубке леса.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://ojs.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/92/78</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.17/n.1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>