<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A03099">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">WINDFALLS AND WINDBREAKS IN PINE FORESTS OF THE NORTHEASTERN UKRAINE</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ВЕТРОВАЛЫ И БУРЕЛОМЫ В СОСНОВЫХ ЛЕСАХ НА СЕВЕРО-ВОСТОКЕ УКРАИНЫ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>MESHKOVA Valentina</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>TOVSTUKHA Alexander</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>PIVOVAR Tatiana</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Ukrainian Research Institute of Forestry &amp;amp</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Forest Melioration named after G.M. Vysotskiy</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Forest and Hunting Management (Ukraine, Sumy)</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2013-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K70</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Pine forests</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Stand density</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Wind damage</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_25260</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_35781</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8392</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">In the Northeast of the Ukraine the share of sanitary felled stands to the total area of sanitary fellings increased from 0.2 % in 2000 to 50 – 60 % in 2012. Possibilities of prediction of the threat of wind damage and planning of sanitary measures are limited because of lack of data absence concerning probable distribution of windbreaks and windfalls in pine forests depending on forest site conditions, structure and condition of the stands. The aim of this research was to determine peculiarities of structure of wind-damaged pine stands in the Northeast of the Ukraine in comparison with non-wind-damaged pine stands. Researches were carried out in 2006 – 2013 in Sumy region, there are two types of natural zones (Forest zone (Polesye) and Forest-Steppe zone) in it. In accordance with the results of stands inspection and with the use of forest inventory data, some databases were formed. The databases make it possible to analyze wind-damaged and non-wind damaged stands separately. The detailed study of trees classification according to the type of wind damage (windbreak, windfall, trees with broken top, bent trees) as well as assessment of taxation indices were carried out at the sample plots in two State Forest Enterprises – SE «Akhtyrka Forest Enterprise» (Left-bank ForestSteppe, the southern part of Sumy region) and SE «Shostka Forest Enterprise» (East Polesye, the northern part of Sumy region). Comparison of distribution of wind-damaged and non-wind-damaged stands in different forest site conditions as well as in accordance with stand origin, its age, and a share of Pine trees in the stand composition was carried out. It was proved, that there were more damages in forests located in less rich and less moist forest site conditions where a share of Pines is less than 8 units. Stand distribution by its origin did not differ in the wind-damaged and non-wind-damaged plots. Age range of natural and artificial stands of wind-damaged plots was lower, than age range in non-wind damaged plots. The youngest stands were the least damaged trees by wind. Differences between H/D ratio for wind-damaged and non-wind-damaged plots of both natural and artificial stands were almost the same for the groups of trees organized in accordance with the age of trees, their density, forest site conditions and productivity (bonitet). The obtained data prove that H/D ratio cannot be the criterion of wind tolerance for pine stands in the studying region. There was no serious difference of the H/G ratio in wind-damaged and non-winddamaged trees of the same age and bonitet that is forest reaction to wind loading did not depend on the given ratio. Distribution of pine trees by the types of wind damage depending on stand density as well as distribution of plots by stand density was analyzed for non-wind-damaged stands, wind-damaged stands for the first time, stands damaged by the wind in two years after selective sanitary felling and wind-damaged stands in the foci of root rot. Windbreak predominated in the plots with relative stand density &gt; 0.8, windfall increased with decrease of stand density. Windfall predominated over the windbreak in the foci of rot root and in the plots where selective sanitary felling was carried out in previous two years.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Исследованы особенности структуры сосновых древостоев в насаждениях, поврежденных ветром, на северо-востоке Украины. Проведено сравнение распределения поврежденных и не поврежденных ветром насаждений по типу лесорастительных условий, происхождению, доле сосны в составе, возрасту. Рассмотрено распределение деревьев сосны по типам повреждения ветром в зависимости от полноты насаждений, а также распределение участков по полноте в насаждениях: не поврежденных ветром</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">поврежденных ветром впервые</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">поврежденных ветром через два года после проведения выборочных рубок и поврежденных ветром в очагах корневой губки.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://ojs.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/121/123</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.19/n.3</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>