<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A08308">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">A WAY TO STUDY THE PROCESS OF AGEING OF ORGANIC CONCRETE AT HIGH TEMPERATURE</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ПРЕДЛОЖЕНИЕ К ИЗУЧЕНИЮ ПРОЦЕССОВ СТАРЕНИЯ ОРГАНИЧЕСКИХ БЕТОНОВ ПРИ ВОЗДЕЙСТВИИ ВЫСОКИХ ТЕМПЕРАТУР</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Salikhov Mukhammet</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Ilivanov Viktor</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Malyanova Lidiya</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Volga State University of Technology</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Concrete</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">aging</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1804</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_192</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Introduction. Ageing of engineering structures made of organic concrete (bitumen is one of the basic elements) is the reason of durability decrease of the structures. However, there are no standard methods to study and to assess the durability of such organic concrete. Authors analyzed advantages and disadvantages of the using methods of study. Major deficiencies of well-known methods of study of ageing of organic concrete are time of work, labor intensity, influence on assessment of scaling factor, necessity to have special equipment which is expensive and not taking into account all the changes of concrete. The goal of the research is to elaborate a new methods, which is simple, independence from scale factor and possibile to use in the experiments of standard equipment in existing laboratories. Results. The offered methods of assessment is based on the results study of laboratory sample of organic concretes by well-known standard methods using standard instruments of existing construction technology laboratory. Assessment of extent of artificial ageing of organic concretes at high temperatures is offered to carry out by means of new dimensionless parameter - coefficient and intensity of ageing. Five stages of experimental work and five stages of analytical actions in comparative assessment of ageing of organic concretes at high temperatures of any composition are given. Conclusion. This methods allows to follow the dynamics of ageing of organic concrete and bitumen by treating them at high temperatures, the methods is implemented at the standard equipment to study bitumen and organic concrete.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Дан краткий анализ причин старения органических бетонов и известных методик их изучения в лабораторных условиях. Предложена новая методика оценки процесса старения органических бетонов во времени при высоких температурах в лабораторных условиях при помощи безразмерных критериев, отличающаяся простотой и возможностью использования для проведения экспериментов стандартного оборудования.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://ojs.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/86/73</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.25/n.1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>