<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A13359">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">INFLUENCE OF SOIL POLLUTION (HEAVY METALS) ON THE LICHEN PINE FOREST SOIL COVER IN CONDITIONS OF FIELD EXPERIMENT</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ВОЗДЕЙСТВИЕ ПОЧВЕННОГО ЗАГРЯЗНЕНИЯ ТЯЖЁЛЫМИ МЕТАЛЛАМИ НА НАПОЧВЕННЫЙ ПОКРОВ СОСНЯКА ЛИШАЙНИКОВО-ЗЕЛЕНОМОШНОГО В УСЛОВИЯХ ПОЛЕВОГО ЭКСПЕРИМЕНТА</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>LYANGUZOVA Irina</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>GORSHKOV Vadim</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>BAKKAL Irina</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>BONDARENKO Margarita</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Komarov Botanical Institute of the Russian Academy of Sciences</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K70</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">forestry</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3055</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The results of a long-term field experiment of the polymetallic dust influence, vented by  «Severonikel» (Моnchegorsk, Kola Peninsula), on the condition and species composition of soil cover in  lichen pine forest as well as migration of Ni, Cu, Co out from the polluted soil into the dominant herbs and lichens were reflected. In case of hand application of the  polymetallic dust  on the surface of snow cover in  lichen pine forest,  spatially heterogeneous pollution of the upper organic horizon with manmade compounds of heavy metals (total concentration of acid-soluble  forms of which varies within 32,7 – 737 mg/kg) was observed. The grass-shrub layer of lichen pine forest is sustainable to soil pollution with Ni, Cu and Co  within the index of manmade load 2,0–45,5 of relative units (no  strong changes of projective cover and species diversity as well as no correlation  of the studied parameters with the level of soil pollution with heavy metals prove the idea). Lichenous-moss carpet is very sensitive to the polymetallic dust application, causing the change in species composition and  lowering of projective cover. Soil pollution with heavy metals leads to 1,3–3-times increase of the total composition of Ni, Cu, Co in the assimilatory body of redbilberry (Vaccinium vitis-idaea) and moss (Pleurozium schreberi), as well as living parts of lichen thallus Cladina stellaris, which is significantly lower than toxic boundary and is not fatal for living. Decrease of projective cover in lower layers of lichen pine forest, the muscoid Pleurozium schreberi and the lichens of Cladina family as well as increase of Cladonia family is the evidence of slowing down of the process of soil cover recovery under the influence of biogeocenose pollution with heavy metals in  the course of  postpyrogenic succession.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">В условиях полевого эксперимента по влиянию полиметаллической пыли, выбрасываемой в атмосферу комбинатом «Североникель» (г. Мончегорск, Кольский полуостров), на компоненты лесных экосистем северной тайги было исследовано состояние и видовое разнообразие нижних ярусов лишайниково-зеленомошного соснового леса (давность последнего пожара 80 лет), а также изучена миграция Ni, Cu, Co из загрязнённой почвы в надземные части доминирующих видов растений и лишайников. Установлено, что видовое разнообразие травяно-кустарничкового и мохово-лишайникового ярусов не изменяется в интервале индекса техногенной нагрузки 2,0–45,5 отн. ед. Однако параметры напочвенного по-крова в большей или меньшей степени изменены под воздействием тяжёлых металлов, а его послепожарное восстановление заторможено.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://ojs.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/286/290</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.27/n.3</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>