<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A03358">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">ADVANCE AND TASKS OF FOREST PROTECTION IN THE UKRAINE</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ДОСТИЖЕНИЯ И ЗАДАЧИ ЗАЩИТЫ ЛЕСА В УКРАИНЕ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>MESHKOVA Valentina</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Ukrainian Research Institute of Forestry &amp;amp</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Forest Melioration named after G.N. Vysotskiy</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K70</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">forest protection</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Plant diseases</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_28075</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5962</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The main researches on forest protection in the territory of the Ukraine were carried out in oak (Quercus robur) and pine (Pinus sylvestris) stands which were the most common to the territory. In recent years high attention was paid to the organisms, which damage ash (Fraxinus excelsior) in connection with worsening of condition of its stands. It was shown that Ukrainian forests were the most weakened in the eastern and southern regions. This situation is explained by deficit of precipitation and higher continentality of climate (it is unfavorable for forest growth, but favorable for development of outbreaks of harmful insects). The purpose of this research was to offer the advances of Ukrainian researchers – forest protectors in solution of scientific and applied tasks as well as to define the perspective tasks in this field of investigation. The base of this review are the scientific publications of researchers on the issues of forest protection in the Ukraine for the last five years. Lists of harmful insects for oak and pine stands were specified, methods of calculation and prediction of such insects were improved, dates of forest protective and sanitary measures were adjusted. A score system of stand attractiveness for the most spread needle and foliage chewing insects was developed and tested. The system gives the possibility to predict the threat of crown damage in separate forest plots using forest inventory data, to draw the maps of threat, to evaluate the potential area of damaged stands and its changes after changes of age, density and species composition of the forest. Coefficients for prediction of mortality of trees after outbreak of pine sawflies were calculated for certain forest site conditions taking into account the level of defoliation and initial sanitary condition of trees. The algorithm for prediction of colonization of trees by stem pests in pine stands, weakened by different actions, taking into account the frequency of colonization by stem pests, the trees of different cate-gories of sanitary condition and distribution of trees by categories of sanitary condition, was suggested. Methodical approaches to determination of species composition of ophiostomoid fungi, related with bark beetles, as well as supporting the Koch's postulates on possibility of vectoring of these fungi by bark beetles were adjusted. Adventitious insects (including leaf-miners, Leptoglossus occidentalis bug) and fungi (pathogens of ash dieback and Dothistroma needle blight) were recorded in the East of the Ukraine. It was shown that in the nearest future it would be necessary to adjust the peculiarities of biology, development and spread of harmful forest organisms in different forest site conditions and different regions of the Ukraine as well as to evaluate relations between population density of harmful organisms and the level of stand dam-age taking into account the initial stand condition, intensity and duration of natural and anthropogenic actions. It is important to pay more attention to researches of peculiarities of biology and spread of forest diseases and their interaction with vectoring insects. In-depth study of the problems on protection of plant material in green houses and nurseries, unclosed forest plantations, objects of breeding, seed plantations, ornamental stands of settlements from harmful organisms (adventitious insects are included) is planned.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://ojs.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/49/27</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.22/n.2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>