<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A04887">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">ORGANIZATION OF FISH MIGRATION CYCLE WITHIN FISH-PROTECTIVE CONSTRUCTION OF HYDROELECTRIC COMPLEX</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ОРГАНИЗАЦИЯ МИГРАЦИОННОГО ЦИКЛА РЫБ В СОСТАВЕ РЫБООХРАННОГО КОМПЛЕКСА ГИДРОУЗЛА</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>VVEDENSKIY Оleg</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Volga State University of Technology</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">M01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">fish</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Migration</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_15903</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4822</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Introduction. Water engineering on the rivers and inland water reservoirs almost completely disturbs the conditions for fish migration. Spawing migration against the flow is stopped by the dams, which leads to termination of natural reproduction and downstream migration is resulted in fish kill in the turbines of hydro-electric power stations and water reservoirs. Besides, feeding migration is also reduced, nonmigratory fish form 2 schools instead of one – one school is formed higher the dam, another one – lower the dam. The goal of the research is to elaborate the activities to organize fish migration cycle in fish-protective constructions of hydroelectric complexes. The following task was set for it: significantly improve the efficiency of work of fish passing constructions and fish-directing devices, assuring downstream, spawing and other types of migration through the hydroelectric complexes regardless of the pressure on the dam of hydroelectric complexes. It is possible to find the solution of the task at hand in further improvement of the construction of classical fish-ways (they should be more simple in construction and similar to the natural conditions of fish habitat as high as possible). The applied for these purposes technology (usage of hydraulic jets) will let to modernize the constructions of the classical fish-ways both to efficiently pass the fish in spawning season through the dams of hydroelectric complexes and to perform high-productive downstream migration. The offered engineering solutions. Hydraulic jets make it possible to correct cross current in the fish-passing outlets of the fish-passing construction. In this case there is a possibility both to improve the efficiency of functioning of fish-passing constructions in the period of spawing migration  and to use the fish-ways at the high-head water development and to apply the data of fish-passing construction in conditions of these hydroelectric complexes for return of fish and young fish. Besides, hydraulic jets make it possible to direct and redirect migrant fish and young fish in the desirable place of the reservoir, saving naturalness of habitat. Experimental researches. Possibility to use of the offered mathematical model and engineering solutions in practice to restore fish migration cycle in the regulated rivers was experimentally conducted on the example of the laboratory model (scale). In course of carrying out of the laboratory researches, Froude similarity criterion was chosen as the basic criteria of hydrodynamic similarity. Conclusion. The offered engineering solutions and technologies in organization of fish migration cycle, including fish-protective constructions of hydroelectric complex, make it possible to get closer to solution of the key problems to renew natural reproduction of many kinds of fishes in the regulated rivers. The offering engineering solutions and technologies, supplementing and enhancing fish-protective constructions, improve their efficiency. The described in the paper technology will allow to use the fish passing constructions on the hydraulic jets to assure spawing and down stream migration which is very economically sound. Distinctive features of the offered element of this construction is flexibility of control of the constructions and compliance of them with ecological requirements.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Анализируется проблема разрушения миграционного цикла рыб, вызванная гидротехническим строительством. Предложен комплекс мероприятий по организации миграционного цикла рыб в составе рыбоохранного комплекса гидроузла. Выработаны технические решения по повышению эффективности работы рыбопропускных сооружений и рыбонаправляющих устройств с целью обеспечения покатных, нерестовых и других миграций через гидроузлы вне зависимости от величины напора на плотину гидроузла. Представлено математическое обоснование предлагаемых технических решений. Приведены результаты экспериментальных исследований.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://ojs.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/71/48</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.24/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>