<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A17156">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">PATTERNS OF GROWTH AND FORMATION OF SCOTS PINE SPECIES FOR THE PURPOSE OF QUARRY RECULTIVATION</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ОСОБЕННОСТИ РОСТА И ФОРМИРОВАНИЯ КУЛЬТУР СОСНЫ ОБЫКНОВЕННОЙ ПРИ РЕКУЛЬТИВАЦИИ КАРЬЕРОВ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>NUREEVA Tatiana</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>KUKLINA Nadezhda</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>CHEFRANOVA Maria</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>MUKHORTOV Dmitry</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Volga State University of Technology</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2016-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">forestry</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3055</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">The topic addressed in the paper is urgent in terms of improving the quality and productivity of plantations particularly on the recultivated lands damaged by unfavorable conditions. In terms of restoration of disturbed lands, the type of forest species plays a very important role. The use of planted seedlings on the disturbed areas is not properly studied so far as evidenced by the relatively small number of publications on this topic. The goal of this research was to identify the growth patterns of Scots pine seedlings with closed root system and study the prospects of their application on the quarry undergoing forest reclamation. The research was carried out on the experimental plot with plantations of Scots pine aged 12, on quarries due for reclamation. The researchmethods were aimed at studying the impact of applied approaches on the status and growth of planted pine seedlings and were determined by such factors as viability, safety, status, height, increment, stem diameter, the diameter of the crown and other qualitative and quantitative parameters in accordance with the G.K. Nezabudkin’s method. The analysis of the growth of pine with the use of seedlings with closed root system and in-the-row spaces varying from 0.35 to 1.5 m between the plants, allowed concluding that growth was intensified for seedlings which were spaced 0.8-1.0 m. The viability of 12-year-old Scots pine species in all cases exceeded 67 %, and the highest growth rate was recorded for the seedlings with 1.0 m in-the-row spacing, due to the achievement of favorable conditions for growth and development, including lack of competition with herbaceous vegetation on the early stages of growth. In terms of their key indicators the quarry plantations of Scots pine were similar with those obtained on clearings and when in-therow spacing varied between 0.65 and 1.5 m., the growth increment of pine trees on the experimental quarry plot was higher which indicates their resistance to limiting factors.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Проведён анализ состояния 12-летних культур сосны на участках рекультивации песчаного карьера, отмечены основные проблемы, связанные с лесной рекультивацией. Установлено, что условия карьеров благоприятны для произрастания сосны обыкновенной. Вы- явлены особенности роста несомкнувшихся культур сосны обыкновенной в условиях песчаного карьера. Обоснована необходимость усовершенствования технологии создания лесных культур для повышения биоразнообразия и устойчивости будущих насаждений при лесной рекультивации.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://journals.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/351/354</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.29/n.1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>