<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A13345">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">INFORMATION CONTENT OF MORPHOMETRIC PARAMETERS OF TREES, ACORNS AND LEAVES OF ENGLISH OAK (QUERCUS ROBUR L.) IN PROVENANCE TRIAL PLANTATIONS</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ИНФОРМАТИВНОСТЬ МОРФОМЕТРИЧЕСКИХ ПАРАМЕТРОВ ДЕРЕВЬЕВ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="">
      <dcterms:alternative>ЖЕЛУДЕЙ И ЛИСТЬЕВ ДУБА ЧЕРЕШЧАТОГО (QUERCUS ROBUR L.) В ГЕОГРАФИЧЕСКИХ КУЛЬТУРАХ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>DEMAKOV Yuriy</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>KRASNOV Vitaliy</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>KIRILLOV Sergey</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>SMYSHLYAEVA Мargarita</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>ANTROPOVA Аnna</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Volga State University of Technology</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">forestry</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3055</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Provenance trial plantations of English oak (Quercus robur L.), established in 1976 in the Republic of Mari El ( area -  9,9 ha out from 22 of its climatypes) were chosen to be the object of the research. In 2014 variability and information significance of large number of morphometric parameters of trees, acorns and leaves were estimated. Clustering of climatypes and morphomet-ric parameters were carried out. Results. According to the carried out research, all the parame-ters of oak climatypes condition are strictly divided into three groups by coefficient of variation, and information content. Fructification level (V = 74,5 %) and the length of a stem from the ground to the top of a tree (V = 59,2 %) change most of all. Height and diameter of trees as well as the size of acorns and leaves (V = 6,7–15,0 %) do not almost change. Coefficient of variation of other parameters varies within 21 – 39 %. It was determined that the starting geographic conditions of the climatypes in the change of  morphometric parameters of trees, acorns and leaves, which poorly correlate with each other in the established plantations, play no serious role. Chance noise-factors are the major source for variation of parameters value. It was concluded that it was important to take into account both the habit of trees, and abundance of fruiting, and mass of acorns when selecting the best climatypes of oak  in order to establish  seed plantations. To select the best trees of English oak in productivity,  it is obligatory to establish the experimental plantations in all the regions. The seedlings for the plantations should be grown out from the acorns, gathered in various cenopopulations of English oak. It is desirable to preserve the provenance trial plantations of English oak in the Republic of Mari El to carry out genetic and selection research and to obtain the seed material with the aim to establish a new testing ground.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Оценена изменчивость и информативная значимость морфологических параметров деревьев, желудей и листьев дуба черешчатого (Quercus robur L.) в 38-летних географических культурах, созданных в Республике Марий Эл из 22 его климатипов. Проведена кластеризация климатипов и морфометрических параметров. Показано, что наиболее значительно изменяются у климатипов балл плодоношения и высота до начала кроны. Слабее же всего варьируют высота и диаметр деревьев, а также размеры желудей и листьев. Роль исходных географических условий климатипов в изменении значений морфометрических параметров их деревьев, желудей и листьев, которые слабо коррелируют между собой, в созданных культурах практически не проявилась. Основным источником вариации значений параметров являются случайные факторы-шумы. Сделан вывод о том, что при отборе лучших климатипов дуба для создания лесосеменных плантаций нужно учитывать не только габитус деревьев, но также обилие плодоношения и массу желудей.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://ojs.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/281/286</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.27/n.3</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>