<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A03106">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">WALL-MOUNTED HYDRAULIC MANIPULATOR WORK CYCLE TIME</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ПРОДОЛЖИТЕЛЬНОСТЬ РАБОЧЕГО ЦИКЛА НАВЕСНОГО ГИДРОМАНИПУЛЯТОРА</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>SMIRNOV Мikhail</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>BAKULINA Irina</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Volga State University of Technology</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2013-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">J10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Tree felling equipment</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_25742</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Nowadays there are no standards on loading time of timber with the help of wall-mounted hydraulic manipulator depending on the size of timber and other important indicators. The purpose of the work is to ground standards of loading and unloading cycle time of assortment with the help of wall-mounted hydraulic manipulator. The problems on definition of factors which influence on loading and unloading cycle time of log assortment were being solved. Mathematical models of calculation of loading and unloading cycle time of log assortment were elaborated. In order to solve the set tasks the methods of the theory of experiment planning and mathematical statistics were used. Multivariable work measurement under the wall-mounted hydraulic manipulator were carried out on the basis of a full factorial plan 23 composition. A relative duration of individual operations in the work cycle of wall-mounted hydraulic manipulator is determined. Duration of commutative operations is defined by the distance of shifting in horizontal and vertical planes. Grab period and the period of assortment placing depend on the number of log assortment which is grabbed at the same time. Dependences of loading-unloading works on four parameters (distance of shifting in horizontal plane, piling height of timber product, assortment diameter and useful scheduled load of long haul truck) are expressed with the multinominal of the degree II. Horizontal component is the most important constituent in load shifting. The less piling height of timber product, the more height in load shifting in vertical plane and period of loading and unloading operations. The regression dependences of working cycle of wall-mounted hydraulic manipulator in loading and unloading of assortments on the number of grabbed assortments, distance of load shifting in horizontal plane and piling height of timber product were obtained. Loading cycle time of assortments varies within 0.8–1.34 minutes depending on their size and distance of load shifting. Unloading cycle time is less that loading cycle time in 1.1–1.6 times. The obtained regression dependences of work cycle time of wall-mounted hydraulic manipulator during loading and uploading of assortment make it possible to standardize work of logging truck-and-trailer units.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Приведены результаты производственных экспериментальных исследований. Получены регрессионные зависимости продолжительности рабочего цикла навесного гидравлического манипулятора, позволяющие нормировать работу лесовозных автопоездов с навесным погрузочным устройством на погрузке и выгрузке сортиментов.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://ojs.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/123/125</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.19/n.3</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>