<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A01450">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">PROBLEMS OF WOOD RAW MATERIAL OBTAINING AT THE VACANT AGRICULTURAL LANDS</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ПРОБЛЕМЫ ПОЛУЧЕНИЯ ДРЕВЕСНОГО СЫРЬЯ НА НЕИСПОЛЬЗУЕМЫХ СЕЛЬСКОХОЗЯЙСТВЕННЫХ ЗЕМЛЯХ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>ZHIGUNOV Anatoliy</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>SHUTOV Igor</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Saint-Petersburg Forestry Research Institute</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Saint-Petersburg State Forestry Engineering University named after S.М. Кirov</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2013-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Agricultural landscape</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">legislation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">plantations</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Pine forests</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_37277</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4253</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5990</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_25260</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The main goal of the research is to ground possibility and expediency of use of the lands which are no more in agriculture in order to establish new forest plantations and to bring the abandoned lands back to economics. In accordance with the data provided by the scientists of Russian Academy of Agricultural Sciences, 30-40 mio/ha of farm fields are no more in agriculture today.
Scotch Pine and Norway Spruce are the two wood species which are chosen as basic wood species for cultivation at the abandoned lands for obtaining of wood. The species data are  aboriginal and sustainable to the local climatic conditions. With the use of the data, heavy yield of wood may be obtained. Besides, Pine and Spruce timber has always demand. Expediency and advantages of forest plantations development in the middle latitudes, including the territories of Russia, are proved. The basic principles of plantation enterprise organization which will let annually obtain wood for the needs of wood-using and food and pharmaceutical industries are offered. Legislative aspects which restrain establishment and development of forest plantations at the abandoned lands are considered and analyzed. 
Quick development of the branch directed to establishment of forest plantations intended for  obtaining of wood as  raw material and  fuel at the vacant lands of different assignment may help to solve many social and economic and ecological  problems: to stop  expansion of  the unused lands in the country, to turn vacant lands into income bearing lands, to create working places in the rural areas, to overcome deficit in wood of coniferous and other valuable species at the economically accessible territories.
In order to achieve the goal it is important to become aware (different levels: society, gov-ernment and parliament) of vital necessity to pass on to production of wood at the plantations, to decrease commercial load on natural forest, to make necessary amendments into  Civil, Land and Forest Codes  which will make it possible for the entrepreneurs to do income producing business  connected with plantations cultivation in Russia on a large scale.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Рассматриваются проблемы возвращения неиспользуемых сельскохозяйственных земель в хозяйственный оборот. Показана эффективность выращивания на таких землях лесных плантаций по производству древесного сырья. Раскрываются причины отставания плантационного лесовыращивания в России от других стран. Предлагаются меры по устранению препятствий на пути широкого использования плантационных технологий лесным бизнесом.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://ojs.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/110/96</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.20/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>