<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A11473">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">STUDY OF THE MODIFIED MACADAM-MASTIC ASPHALT CONCRETE LIFESPAN IN CORROSION MEDIUM</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ИССЛЕДОВАНИЕ ДОЛГОВЕЧНОСТИ МОДИФИЦИРОВАННОГО ЩЕБЕНОЧНО-МАСТИЧНОГО АСФАЛЬТОБЕТОНА ПРИ ДЕЙСТВИИ АГРЕССИВНОЙ СРЕДЫ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>ILIVANOV Viktor</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>SALIKHOV Mukhammet</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Volga State University of Technology</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2013-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">P30</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">environmental factors</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">road construction</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">corrosion</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2594</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_37272</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_24011</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Usage of the modifiers for improvement of asphalt concrete lifespan often leads to complication of work delivery technology and rise in price of road construction. At that, roads lifespan does not increase for certain. One of the possible ways of the problem solution is substitution of some part of the dispersed particles of macadam-mastic asphalt concrete with waste products of local soft aggregates. However in this case, over-expenditure of binding substance is observed. The target of the research is to reduce production costs of macadam-mastic asphalt concrete owing to reduction in requirement in asphalt binder, saving and improvement of its performance properties in comparison with classic compositions. According to the research results of Е.V. Vainshtein and surveillance over experimental part of motor road «Yoshkar-Ola – Kozmodemyansk – Cheboksary», covering of macadam-mastic asphalt concrete with sifting out of limestone crushing fully comply with the requirements, presenting to its performance characteristics. However, some rise of flow requirement of binding for preparation of macadam-mastic asphalt concrete mixture composition 7,5 % is observed. In order to reduce the flow requirement of binding, some mixtures of macadam-mastic asphalt concrete with sifting out of limestone crushing and addition of some chemical wastes were tested. Some achieved in the laboratory conditions results let us speak about performance improvement of the asphalt concrete with reduced to 5,8 % of binding construction bitumen 60/90. The considered in the article mixtures are as follows: mixture with reduced percentage of binding, but with waste additive</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">mixture with optimum percentage of binding. To calculate lifespan of the offered mixture of the modified macadam-mastic asphalt concrete the indicators which characterize strenuous conditions of road surface under the most possible reasons of its destruction are chosen: thermal tolerance under long-term load and high temperature</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">corrosion resistance under long-term heating of mixture</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">properties change under water saturation. As a result of the research of addition into macadam-mastic asphalt concrete with sifting out of limestone crushing of the modified additive, it was managed to improve its tolerance to corrosive medium ( water ) and improve its corrosion resistance under long heating, i.е. resistance to ageing. At that, aging processes of bitumen in the modified macadam-mastic asphalt concrete are less intensive than in the mixture of macadam-mastic asphalt concrete with sifting out of limestone crushing.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">Рассмотрены теоретические основы изменения прочности твердых тел при действии агрессивных сред на примере щебеночно-мастичных асфальтобетонов. Изучено влияние на долговечность модифицированного щебеночно-мастичного асфальтобетона с отсевами дробления известняков одновременного воздействия нагрузок и высоких температур. Показано, что предложенный щебеночно-мастичный асфальтобетон, по сравнению с щебеночно-мастичным асфальтобетоном классического состава, при длительном действии высоких температур подвержен процессам старения в меньшей степени. Методами длительного нагрева щебеночно-мастичной смеси и длительного водонасыщения щебеночно-мастичного асфальтобетона из нее установлена также более высокая коррозионная устойчивость предложенного состава.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://ojs.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/103/89</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.18/n.2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>