<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A03116">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">CHEBOKSARY HYDROELECTRIC POWER STATION RAISED WATER TABLE IMPACT ON FOREST PATHOLOGICAL CHARACTERISTICS OF STANDS</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ВЛИЯНИЕ ПОДТОПЛЕНИЯ ЧЕБОКСАРСКОГО ВОДОХРАНИЛИЩА НА ЛЕСОПАТОЛОГИЧЕСКИЕ ХАРАКТЕРИСТИКИ ДРЕВОСТОЕВ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>ALEKSEEV Ivan</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>ZAKHAROV Alexander</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>GUSEVA Oksana</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Volga State University of Technology</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Centre of Forest Protection in the Republic of Mari El</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2013-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K70</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Crop monitoring</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_37838</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The purpose of the research is to reveal the tendencies of changes of  sanitary characteristics of stands in order to  evaluate their resistance to raised water table and to give recommendations of more rational stands structure for different soil-hydrological conditions of subzones with raised water table due to reservoir of Cheboksary hydro-electric power station. A standardized methods of forest pathology monitoring which was developed by I.A. Alexeev is at the heart of the methods. It includes field-survey information collection en routes, differentiated approach to grading of trees condition, account and evaluation of faults in accordance with 10 reasons of their origin, mortality estimation in accordance with their origin, calculation of natural and normal mortality with an account of forestry influence. Calculation of level of biodiversity, effective phytomass, frustration and sustainability indices as well as evaluation of forecasting data in 23 characteristics  are carried out with the use of collected materials. For all the negative parameters which are taken into consideration, the evaluative scales are determined. This standardization allows to make equal evaluation of monitoring data of different authors in determination of statistic sanitary condition as well as its tendencies of change including adaptive processes and ecological characteristics. Coniferous trees are less adaptive to changes in humidity than broadleaved trees. A share of accidental mortality (windthrow and windbreak) dramatically increases because of intensification of wind conditions. A share of accidental mortality is up to 70 % of growing stock in forest outlier (5th subzone). Timber fungus (shelf fungus) causes Birch windbreak rise. The mean extension of shelf fungus is up to 11 meters in the forests with normal water table instead of 5–6 meters. Maple fungus and dryad's club saddle are not widely spread in the forests with normal water table but they lead to Lime windbreak rise. Change of ecological situation upon filling the Cheboksary reservoir affected both the species composition and deterioration of their sanitary condition. As a result of changes of hydrological conditions, a rather stable trees composition formed in 30 years. It is important to note that the composition differed from the original one. Lowering of annual mortality to the figures of natural thinning and rise in trunk section area at the 1.3 meters height of an ordinary growing tree to the section square of annually dead trees in 2.5 times and more are the most informative characteristics of adaptation of species to the new ground water level. Number of affected by deceases and pests trees grows with the increase of abiotic factor. Corticiaceae are less often met than Polyporaceae. Pests move from the lower part of trunk to the upper one. Woody species adaptation is slower than adaptation of forest live cover and fungal pests. The objects of impounding are out of focus of attention of foresters for more than 30 years. Particular attention should be paid to forest outliers which  are beyond the reach of sanitary interference. They became   the centers of forest pests, deceases and water reservoir pollution. Bluegreen algae density is much higher in the open part of ponds than in the waterlogged area. It is important to clean heavily waterlogged riparian forests and forest outliers from brushwood, dead-wood and to extract logs from water. The banks ought to be protected from abrasive processes either by means of construction of dams or by planting of hygrophilous species (e.g. Willows, Poplars, European or White Alders, Elms, etc.). At that, it is necessary to make more lowsloped stiff slopes and undertake protective measures from landslide in advance. In the 3 and 4th subzones, natural adaptation of tree species should be carried out by means of periodical selective sanitary felling. In the 1st and 2 subzones there should be made some measures on protection from root rot and trunk pests. Ages of protective maturity, felling of overmature forests and regeneration of more sustainable mixed forests at the fellings should be ascertained for water protection forests.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Приводятся результаты лесопатологического мониторинга лесов в зоне подтопления Чебоксарского водохранилища. Выявлено увеличение заболеваний абиотического порядка и случайного отпада деревьев в результате изменения ветрового режима и чрезмерного увлажнения почвы. Отмечено изменение видового состава дереворазрушающих грибов. Установлены наиболее характерные признаки адаптации пород к подтоплению.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://ojs.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/128/131</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.19/n.3</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>