<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A04885">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">THEIR ACCUMULATION OF TRITERPENE GLYCOSIDES IN THE GROWING CYCLE CELL SUSPENSION CULTURES POLYSCIAS FRUTICOSA</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ЗАКОНОМЕРНОСТИ НАКОПЛЕНИЯ ТРИТЕРПЕНОВЫХ ГЛИКОЗИДОВ В ЦИКЛЕ ВЫРАЩИВАНИЯ СУСПЕНЗИОННОЙ КУЛЬТУРЫ КЛЕТОК POLYSCIAS FRUTICOSA</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>KOCHKIN Dmitry</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>SUKHANOVA Еlena</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>NOSOV Alexander</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Moscow State University named after М. V. Lomonosov</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Institute of Plant Physiology named after К.А. Timiryazev</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F30</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Cell culture</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">In vitro culture</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">HPLC</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">NMR spectroscopy</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7178</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_24135</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_24469</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_24405</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Variation in the amounts and compositions of the individual polysciosides formed during a 21-day growth cycle of the cell-suspension culture of Polyscias fruticosa in flasks were determined by RP-HPLC-UV analysis. The plant cell culture was obtained from leaves of an adult plant and the present research has been led on the 154th subcultivation cycle of the suspension cell culture growth. Four polysciosides (oleanolic acid glycosides) were identified: ladiginoside A, polyscioside A, polyscioside E and glucopyranosyl-(1-2)-glucuronopyranosyl-3-oleanolic acid-28-glucopyranosyl ester. These glycosides were the same as in Polyscias filicifolia leaves, which had been isolated, determined by NMR method and used as standarts for the present research. The occurrence of all of them was shown during the whole subcultivation cycle. The major components were ladiginoside A and polyscioside E, their percentage during the subcultivation period amounted correspondingly up to 70% and 40%. An investigation of these glycosides dynamics during the cultivation cycle has been processed. The maximum content of the sum of glycosides (0,5% of the dry weight) was observed on the 14th day of subcultivation, at the end of the exponent stage of the cell culture growth. It is important to note that ladiginoside A is the most nonpolar glycoside among the determined ones, and while being a major glycoside with a rather stable occurrence during the cell culture cultivation is not common to be a major one for plants of Araliacea family. It should be noted that the research of isolated glycosides accumulation has been led for the first time.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Изучены закономерности накопления индивидуальных полисциозидов в цикле выращивания суспензионной культуры клеток Polyscias fruticosa при культивировании в колбах. Показано, что на протяжении цикла выращивания в биомассе культуры были представлены полисциазид А, Pol 3, полисциазид Е и ладигинозид А. При этом мажорными компонентами были полисциазид Е и ладигинозид А.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://ojs.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/70/47</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.24/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>