<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A11361">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">COMPOSITE PIPELINES ANALYSIS: ONE-LINEAR FINITE ELEMENT</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ПРЯМОЛИНЕЙНЫЙ КОНЕЧНЫЙ ЭЛЕМЕНТ ДЛЯ РАСЧЁТА КОМПОЗИТНЫХ ТРУБОПРОВОДОВ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>LOSKUTOV Yuriy</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Volga State University of Technology</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2013-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">pipes</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">polymers</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5925</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_32041</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The paper covers the areas of engineering and mechanics of composites and deals with the problem of pipelines strength. The purpose of the article is to describe a technique of design calculation of composite pipelines of hydro-mechanization. The first task is to prepare a finite element model of straining under the loading of straight pipeline sections by the continuous winding patterns. The second task is to obtain the formulas to calculate elasticity relations, coefficients of stiffness matrix and the vector of nodal forces. A one-dimensional straight finite element to perform the strength-and-stiffness analysis of thin-walled pipes/ slurry pipelines was introduced. Some methods of structural mechanics and finite element method were applied to study the plane stress of composite pipes. As a result, the formulas for calculation of the coefficients of the stiffness matrix and the vector of nodal forces were obtained. The effect of temperature and internal pressure from the point of view of its static loading was considered. The distribution of thermal and hydrodynamic effects by an equivalent system of concentrated nodal forces was also outlined. The analysis of the parameters of stress -strain state of the pipeline with flowing liquid was introduced. A comparison between two differing embodiment pipelines was made: one pipe had a single-layer steel structure, the other one had a multi-layer structure made by cross-laminated helical winding of the organoplastic Kevlar 49/PR-286 on the steel plug. This paper may be used in the works on hydro-mechanization for improving of floating routes/ in oil and gas pipelines.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Выполненные в данной работе исследования позволяют решить для трубопроводного гидротранспорта лесопромышленного комплекса задачу разработки и применения научно обоснованных методов проектирования композитных конструкций. Для анализа плоского напряжённого состояния трубопроводов использованы метод конечных элементов (МКЭ) и подходы строительной механики. Представлен прямолинейный стержневой конечный элемент. Получены расчётные соотношения для коэффициентов мат-рицы жёсткости и вектора узловых сил конечного элемента (КЭ) тонкостенного трубопровода, изготовленного из волокнистого композита. Рассмотрено двухкомпонентное статическое нагружение, включающее действие температуры и внутреннего давления. Учитывается слоистая структура материала и анизотропия термоупругих свойств. Расчётные соотношения и математическая модель могут быть полезны при проекти-ровании трубопроводов и пульпопроводов гидромеханизации, нефте- и газо-проводов.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://ojs.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/113/99</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.20/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>