<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016C07086">
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">Квота на выбросы и роль лесного сектора в национальных обязательствах Российской Федерации в новом климатическом соглашении</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>Emission allowances and the role of the forest sector in the national obligations of the Russian Federation in the new climate agreement</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Romanovskaya A.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Federici S</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Federal state budgetary institution “Institute of global climate and ecology of the Federal service for Hydrometeorology and environmental monitoring Russian Academy of Sciences”</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Food and agriculture organization of the United Nations</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K11</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K50</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K70</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Greenhouse gases</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">climatic change</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">emission reduction</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_34841</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_35367</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_331597</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">В России около 25% антропогенных выбросов парниковых газов от промышленных источников компенсируется поглощением в секторе землепользования, изменения зем- лепользования и лесного хозяйства – это должно быть учтено в национальных обязатель- ствах по новому климатическому соглашению. При ограничении потепления не более 2 °С квота на выбросы России на период после 2011 года составляет около 51,1 Гт СО2, что соответствует примерно 6,5% от глобальной остаточной величины выбросов. Расчеты квоты показали, что в течение своего исторического развития наша страна не «заняла» чужое пространство в атмосфере по эмиссиям парниковых газов. Чем раньше начнется снижение ежегодных выбросов, тем более плавно оно может происходить и в течение более долгого периода. Основное сокращение придется на период до 2050 г., и при опти- мистичном сценарии оно будет составлять не более 12% от уровня 1990 г. Включение по- глощения в лесных экосистемах в выполнение обязательств позволяет снизить темпы необходимого ежегодного сокращения выбросов примерно в 3 раза. В новом климатиче- ском соглашении целесообразно перейти на прогнозные базовые уровни баланса парни- ковых газов в лесных экосистемах, которые оценены равными 450, 344 и 238 Мт СО2 экв. в год для периодов 2021-2030, 2031-2040 и 2041-2050 гг. соответственно. Для возможности полного учета поглощения в лесах при выполнении национальных обязательств величи- на прогнозного базового уровня должна быть включена в установленные количества (т. е. выбросы от всех промышленных источников в базовом году).</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">In Russia about 25% of anthropogenic emissions of greenhouse gases from industrial sources is compensated by the sinks in the land use, land use change and forestry sector, and that should be reflected in the national commitments under the new climate agreement. To limit global warming to not more of 2 °C emission allowances of the Russian Federation for the period after 2011 is about to 51,1 Gt CO2. That is an equivalent to about 6,5% of the global allowed emissions. Our calculations of quota showed that in the course of its historical development, Russia has not “occupied” space in the atmosphere of other countries by its greenhouse gas emissions. If to start reduce annual emissions of greenhouse gases sooner than more smoothly and over a longer period it can happen. The main reduction will occur in the period up to 2050, and, under the optimistic scenario, the total reduction should not be more than 12% from the 1990 level. The inclusion of sinks in forest ecosystems in the obligations reduces the rate required annual emission reduction approximately in 3 times. In the new climate agreement, it is recommended to develop projected reference levels of the greenhouse gas balance in forest ecosystems. These reference levels correspond to 450, 344 and 238 Mt CO2 eq per year for periods 2021-2030, 2031-2040 and 2041- 2050 respectively. For a full accounting of the carbon sinks in the forests during the implementation of national commitments the projected reference level should be included in the assigned amounts (i.e., emissions from all industrial sources in the base year).</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://journal.spb-niilh.ru/pdf/1-2015/spbniilh-proceedings-1-2015-2-full.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">en</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Труды Санкт-Петербургского научно-исследовательского института лесного хозяйства</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2079-6080</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.10/n.1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>