<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016103012">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Improving of Barley Seedling Growth by Seed Priming Under Water Deficit Stress</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Jalilian Jalal</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Khalilzadeh Razieh</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Khanpaye Edris</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F60</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Pseudomonas</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6304</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Seed priming was used to reinforcement of barley seedling growth under water deficit stress in a greenhouse condition. Barley seeds were primed with humic acid, Pseudomonas Spp., Marmarin, distilled water (hydropriming) and none (as control) under four levels of water deficit stress (irrigation at 20 (I1), 40 (I2), 60 (I3) and 80% (I4) field capacity). Results indicated that all measured parameters were decreased with increasing the stress levels, except root length and root-shoot ratio. The highest value of root length (18.42 cm) and root-shoot ratio (2.84) was obtained in the I1 irrigation regime. However, I2, I3 and I4 irrigation regimes did not significantly affect on barley seedling traits, but I1 irrigation regime exhibited better growth. Seed priming with Pseudomonas affected root length, root and shoot dry weight, plant height and SPAD, significantly. Seed priming with Marmarin showed best results on SPAD. The maximum (0.37 g/plant) shoot dry weight was obtained from I2 irrigation regime with hydropriming treatment. Whereas, the lowest shoot dry weight (0.14 g/plant) was observed in I1 irrigation regimes in control condition. Hydropriming shows better response in root length, root and shoot and plant height and was equal with Pseudomonas, so it could be considered as a suitable substitute in organic agricultural systems.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.jspb.ru/issues/2014/N2/JSPB_2014_2_125-134.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">en</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Journal of Stress Physiology &amp;amp; Biochemistry</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1997-0838</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.10/n.2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>