<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016100344">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">AMIODARONE INDUCES THE SYNTHESIS OF HSPS IN  SACCHAROMYCES CEREVISIAEAND ARABIDOPSIS THALIANA  CELLS</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Pyatrikas D.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Fedoseeva I.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Varakina N.N.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Rusaleva T.M.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Stepanov A.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Rikhvanov E.G.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Borovskii G.B.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Voinikov V.K.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2012-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F60</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Mitochondria</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Heat shock</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4869</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_34015</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Many biotic and abiotic stresses cause an increase of cytosolic Ca
2+ level in cells. Calcium is one of the most important  second  messengers,  regulating  many  various  activities in  the  cell  and  was  known  to  affect expression of stress activated genes. Mild heat shock induces the expression of heat shock proteins (Hsps) which protect cell from drastic heat shock exposure. There are some literature data permitting to suggest that transient elevation of cytosolic Ca2+ level in plant cells is important for activation of Hsps expression. On the other hand mitochondria are known to regulate the intracellular calcium and reactive oxygen species signaling. It has been shown recently that mild heat shock induces hyperpolarization of inner mitochondrial membrane in plant and yeast cells and this event is critically important for activation of Hsps expression. To reveal  the  relationship  between  mitochondrial  activity,  intracellular  calcium  homeostasis  and  Hsps expression an antiarrhythmic drug amiodarone (AMD) have been used. AMD is known to cause transient increase  of  cytosolic  Ca2+  level  in  Saccharomyces  cerevisiae.  Obtained  results  have  showed  that  AMD treatment induced the synthesis of Hsp104p in S. cerevisiaecells and Hsp101p in A. thaliana  cell culture. Induction of Hsp104p synthesis leads to enhanced yeast capability to survive lethal heat shock exposure. Development  of  S.  cerevisiae thermotolerance  depended  significantly  on  the  presence  of  Hsp104p. Elevation of Hsp104p level in the result of AMD treatment was shown to be governed by activity of Msn2p and Msn4p transcription factors. Deletion of the  MSN2  and  MSN4 genes abrogated the AMD ability to induce Hsp104p synthesis. Mild heat shock and AMD treatment induced the hyperpolarization of the inner mitochondrial  membrane  in  yeast  and  Arabidopsis  cells  which  accompanied  by  HSP  synthesis  and development of thermotolerance. It was suggested that increase of cytosolic Ca2+ level after AMD treatment directly or indirectly causes the activation of mitochondrial activity which leads to hyperpolarization of the inner mitochondrial membrane and production of reactive oxygen species (ROS). Modulation of cellular Ca2+ and ROS signals by mitochondria is assumed to play a prominent role in activation of Hsps expression in east and plant cells</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.jspb.ru/issues/2012/N3/JSPB_2012_3_S35.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">en</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Journal of Stress Physiology &amp;amp; Biochemistry</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1997-0838</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.8/n.3</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>