<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="AL2016106232">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Temporal Variation of Water Quality in Thana Reservoir (Lushnja)</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>KOPALI ALBERT</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>DOKO ADRIAN</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>ROTA ELISON</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Department of Agro-environment and Ecology, Agricultural University of Tirana, Albania</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Water Quality</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_16061</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The implementation of sustainable farming systems requires and the completion of quantitative and qualitative water needs of plants. The main part of the water needed in agricultural systems is complemented by rainfall, but in conditions of their lack of need must to intervene with additional irrigation. Water used for irrigation on agricultural comes from sources with different backgrounds like rivers, streams, lakes and watersheds, and it represents very different qualities, especially as far as the level of salinity. In our country, the main part of irrigation water provided by the floodplain (over 600 reservoirs with capacity about 560 million water m3) that are to nourished which change their apparent qualitative composition. Their management requires, except of dynamic studies of sediment deposition, which is related to their longevity, also the study of their water quality, which is directly related to the quality of agricultural products. Providing quality water for irrigation, when the salinity level exceeds the levels permitted, with negative consequences on the quality of agricultural products, is the request of sustainable farming systems. Changing water quality in the time of various factors, their detection and analysis of water quality for irrigation reservoir Thana (Lushnja) have been the focus of this study.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">https://drive.google.com/a/ubt.edu.al/file/d/0B_i7_HlsPT6Hb3RYWkZWa3lvamM/view?usp=sharing</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Albanian Journal of Agricultural Sciences</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2218-2020</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.14/n.1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>