<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="AL2016102615">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Ensuring Improved Livelihood Opportunities for Resource-Poor Maize Farmers through the Dissemination of Striga Control Methods in Kwara State, Nigeria</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>OLORUNFEMI,  O.D.1</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>OGUNLADE,  I.1</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>FAKAYODE,  S. B.2</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>ADEKUNLE  O. A.1,3</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>1Department of Agricultural Extension and Rural Development, University of Ilorin, Ilorin, Nigeria.</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>2Department of Agricultural Economics and Extension, Federal University Oye-Ekiti, Nigeria.</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>3Department of Agricultural Economics and Extension, School of Agriculture, University of Cape Coast, Ghana</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">maize</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">poverty</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_12332</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6151</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">This paper examines the sources used by resource poor maize farmers in search of agricultural information on Striga control methods in Kwara State, Nigeria. A well structured interview schedule was used to elicit information using random sampling technique from one hundred and sixty (160) maize farmers in Edu and Patigi Local Government Areas which are highly endemic to Striga infestation in the State. Four sources of information were found effective in disseminating and diffusing Striga control methods in the area which include neighbours and friends, government agencies (ADP), agricultural extension agents and farmers groups. Logistic regression model of determinants of poverty revealed that characteristics of households that were more likely to be impoverished include small household size</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">low farm income, few years of farming experience and those whom Striga have been on their farms for long thereby having high yield loss to Striga. The study recommends an urgent need for extension agencies to intensify the use of the effective sources of information for disseminating Striga control methods to the farmers and it highlighted policies to improve the livelihoods of the resource-poor maize farmers in the Striga affected areas of Kwara State, Nigeria.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">https://docs.google.com/a/ubt.edu.al/viewer?a=v&amp;pid=sites&amp;srcid=dWJ0LmVkdS5hbHxyc3NifGd4OjY0YThkNDY1MjI4ZmE2NGI</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">en</dc:language>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">en</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Albanian Journal of Agricultural Sciences</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2218-2020</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.13/n.2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>