<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="AL2016109791">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">The Identification of Ecosystem Goods and Services Provided by Karavasta Lagoon</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>KOTO ROMINA</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>BANI AIDA</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>HAXHIALUSHI ROZANA</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>DAUTAJ ANJA</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Department of Agroenvironment nad Ecology, Agricultural University of Tirana, Tirana, Albania</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Department of Agroenvironment nad Ecology, Agricultural University of Tirana, Tirana, Albania</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Marketing-Tourism Department, Faculty of Economy, University of Tirana</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Institute of International Studies, Faculty of Social Sciences, Corvinus University of Budapest</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">services</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">assessment</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6989</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_330990</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The coastal system as the Karavasta lagoon provides a range of goods and services. The Karavasta Lagoon
(Ramsar site since 1996), is one of the most various mosaic of coastal habitats that extends in the central part of
the Albanian Adriatic coast. The aim of the study was the identifications of goods and services in Karavasta
lagoon. To identify, list and characterize the goods and services we have adopted the classification of ecosystem
services proposed by Millennium Ecosystem Assessment [14] that outlined four categories of ecosystem
services Provisioning, Regulating, Cultural, Supporting. According to the MEA, ecosystem services are seen as
‘the benefits ecosystems provide’’. To carry out our objectives we have used also a set of methodological tools
for data collections including: (i) Previous studies and literature (ii) Questionnaire in villages, household
around the lagoon and interview with tourist, visitor which use the lagoon. This methods help us to identify the
Ecosystem Services and to collect information about the goods and services in the lagoon. The study found out
that the goods and services of the lagoon are mainly utilized from the residents of the nearby villages such as
Mize, Zharnec, Kryekuq, Bedat, Xeng and Divjaka. It was noted that provisioning services with direct use are:
fishing (high level), medicinal plants, agriculture, mineral, wildlife (medium level) and provisioning services
with indirect use are: endemic plants (high level), water (medium level). Regulating services with direct use are:
recreation, education, cultural, historical and traditional services (high level) and regulating services with
indirect use are: flood and flow control (high level), hydrological regime, biological regulation (low level).
Supporting services with direct use are: supporting a range of biological diversity (high level), water transport
(low level) and supporting service with indirect use is: supporting a productive fishing environment (medium
level).</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">https://sites.google.com/a/ubt.edu.al/rssb/revista_2_2015_files/12_ROMINA%20KOTO%20pp%20162-168.pdf?attredirects=0&amp;d=1</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Albanian Journal of Agricultural Sciences</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2218-2020</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.14/n.2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>