<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="AL2016111717">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">The Study of Adaptation of the New Peach Cultivars in the Agricultural Region of Vlora</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>FERRAJ BARDHOSH</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>FERAJ ARIOLA</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>GJYLI ATHINA</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>MERKOHITAJ RAMO</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Department of Horticulture, Agricultural University of Tirana, Tirana, Albania</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Department of International Relations, University of Tirana, Tirana, Albania</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Center for Technology Transfer, Vlora, Albania</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Center for Technology Transfer, Vlora, Albania</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">varieties</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">collection</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8157</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1756</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Drupaceous fruits are placed in the first place in the species structure of Albania’s farms. To anticipate problems in
the development of arboriculture and market production, scientific institutions have started a research to find possible
solutions for the development of this sector. This is the reason why through collaboration between, CTT Vlore &amp; IAM
Bari was made possible to bring from Italy during the years 2000-2001, 96 cultivars of peaches, plums, cherries,
apricots, nectarines, almonds. These cultivars dominate the production markets of the Mediterranean countries. In this
project were included 21 peach cultivars 10 years old, rootstocks, planting material of basic category, clear of viruses
and other pathogens. As the main rootstocks were selected GF 677 and MRS 2/5.
To study the behavior, adaptability and productivity of the peach cultivars, in the warm coastal areas, specialists from
the Agriculture University of Tirana and Center for Technology Transfer in Vlora carried out a number of tests and
evaluations during a three year period.
At the end of the study it resulted that the cultivars with a very early maturation better adapted in the coastal areas
were: ‘Cardinal’, ‘May Crest’, and ‘Spring Crest’. The cultivars with early maturation and consolidated productivity
were: “Red Haven”, “Bolero”, “Dixired”, “Early Crest”, “Iris Rosso”. Cultivars with an average maturation period
were: “Red Haven Bianca”, “Red Top”, “Regina Bianca”, “Sun Crest”. The most suitable cultivars with a delayed
maturation period are considered: “Big Moon”, “Domiziana”, “Haile”, “Laure”, “Maria Delizia”, “Rome Star”,
“Pontina” and “Red Cal”. The only cultivar with a very delayed maturation is “Padana”.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">https://sites.google.com/a/ubt.edu.al/rssb/revista_3_2015_file/14_BARDHOSH%20FERRAJ%20-NR.%203_pp%20300-309.pdf?attredirects=0&amp;d=1</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Albanian Journal of Agricultural Sciences</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2218-2020</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.14/n.3</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>