<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="AL2016109766">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Water and Sediment Heavy Metal Pollution in Ereniku River of Kosovo</dc:title>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Heavy metals</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">pollution</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">water</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Soil</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2223</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6077</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8309</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7156</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Soil, water and sediment samples were collected in 13 sampling stations along Erenik River, in the western part of
Kosovo in order to assess heavy metal pollution. The concentration of hevy metals as Cd, Hg, Pb, Cr, Cu and Zn were
determinated in water, soil and sediment samples. The concentration of heavy metals in water samples was measured
using the flame atomic absorption spectrophotometer (AAS), while for sediment and soil samples was used
inductively coupled plasma mass spectrometry (ICP-MS). Obtained results showed that the concentrations in soil of
heavy metals Cd, Pb, Cu and Zn were under the proposed limit values by the European guideline for “soil
background", while the obtained values of Cr in all stations were higher than proposed limit values. The
concentrations of heavy metals in sediment were often higher than the values determined with low action on the
biological systems of the river ecosystem (ERL Effect Range Low) but smaller than the values that negatively
affecting the extent &gt; 50% of organisms on core Effect Medium Range - ERM (Cu, Pb and Ni). The total values of Cr
were higher than ERM but its origin is mainly geological more than human activities, thus the biological effect of this
element can be probably low. Our results indicated that heavy metals as Pb, Zn and Cu were found in high portion in
fine sediment fraction (</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">https://sites.google.com/a/ubt.edu.al/rssb/revista_2_2015_files/9_Faton%20Maloku%20pp%20137-148.pdf?attredirects=0&amp;d=1</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.14/n.2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>