<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="AL2016102345">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Advantages of beer produced of basic extract of high gravity compared to beer produced of normal gravity</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>PAJAZITI MYBESHIR</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>KONGOLI RENATA</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>The Department of Biotechnology and Food, Agricultural University of Tirana, Tirana 1030, Albania,</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">This study was done to attain a higher quality beer by optimizing the production process at a lower cost at the J.S.C. “Birra Peja” brewery, Peja, Kosovo. The aim of this study was to increase the extract concentration without reducing the beer quality, which in turn would make the brewery lose its market competitive edge. We studied and monitored the beer quality and the organoleptic characteristics in order to compare the beers produced of four different concentration basic extracts: E = 10.5 oP</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">E = 13 oP</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">E = 15 oP</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">and, E = 16 oP. The study was reviewed by the technical laboratories at “Birra Peja” and “Union Brewery”, Ljubljana, Slovenia. Quality tasting was made from two tasting groups, each from the above-mentioned breweries. Chemical and microbiological tests were based on methods under the “EBC (European Beer Convention)” and the “MEBAK (Mitteleuropäische Brautechnische Analysenkommision e.V.)” guidelines. Based on the conducted analyses, we have come to the conclusion that beer produced of 16 oP basic extract is of higher quality and this is the beer that will be produced at “Birra Peja” brewery.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Albanian Journal of Agricultural Sciences</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2218-2020</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.13/n.1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>