<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="AL2016109907">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Climate Change Adaptation Actions in Tirana</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>MALLTEZI JAMARBER</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>HANXHARI ROMEO</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>ZELA GAVROSH</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>SULÇE SULEJMAN</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Department of Agroenvironment and Ecology, Agricultural University of Tirana, Tirana, Albania</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Municipality of Tirana, Tirana, Albania</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Department of Agroenvironment and Ecology, Agricultural University of Tirana, Tirana, Albania</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Department of Agroenvironment and Ecology, Agricultural University of Tirana, Tirana, Albania</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">climate</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Land</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Adaptation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1665</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4172</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_117</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Tirana has recently experienced changing weather patterns such as rising temperatures and occurrence of extreme
weather events. Such events – in combination with a rapid increase of urban areas and impermeable cement covering
the natural soil in the city – have caused increased flooding, riverside erosion, delayed traffic, increased spending for
cooling during the summer, increased need for health services, and an urgent need to plan the city smartly.
Tirana is preparing a set of Climate Change Adaptation Actions in order to manage the posed risks and adapt to
climate change. The city administration should integrate climate change adaptation in their management and planning
processes. This exercise was prepared by using the Climate Compass tool and included the vulnerability assessment of
different sectors in the city, evaluated the risks posed to vulnerable target groups and proposed feasible adaptation
options. It outlines mostly actions to be taken to manage risks and build climate resilience across essential public
infrastructure and services.
Such actions would require better land use planning to maintain – and where possible increase – the natural areas and
leave the natural soil undisturbed. Key to success is integrating adaptation concepts into the city planning and
development investments. The result is a novel approach and guidance to better integrate adaptation concepts in city
planning and new technologies to prevent heat waves, flood risks in the city, etc.Administrators of the Tirana
Municipality should keep in mind and integrate the climate change adaptationactions into daily planning and decision
making for several sectors including urban planning, transport, public services, water infrastructure, emergency
response, etc. in order to ensure sustainable development for the city.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">https://sites.google.com/a/ubt.edu.al/rssb/revista_2_2015_files/5_MALLTEZI%20pp%20102-111.pdf?attredirects=0&amp;d=1</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Albanian Journal of Agricultural Sciences</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2218-2020</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.14/n.2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>