<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="AL2016104739">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Hygienic Status of some Veterinary Clinics in Tirana, Albania</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>DOKU OLSI</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>SHOSHI NATALIA</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>ÇABELI PRANVERA</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>DOKU BLERINA</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>SHOSHI PJERIN</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Department of Clinic, Faculty of Veterinary Medicine, Agricultural University of Tirana, Albania</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Veterinary Clinic Vetmedica, Tirana, Albania</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Faculty of Economy, University Aleksander Moisiu, Durrës, Albania</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Nosocomial infections are present in the companion animal clinics due to the high microbial presence in manipulation surfaces and pavements of these clinics. The hygienic status of the clinics carries a lot of problems as a consequence of non-application of a correct disinfection scheme. This observation induced the initiation of this study.This study was carried in 5 representative clinics in Tirana The aim of this study was the evaluation of hygienic status of these clinics and isolation of pathogen agents present in manipulation surfaces and pavements with the final aim to create and suggest a preventive program against nosocomial infections.The clinics under evaluation were disinfecting the environment but not in the accurate way and this procedure was not based in a disinfection scheme. In this study was tested the microbial load of manipulation surfaces and pavements of each clinic. The isolation and identification of microbial agents was done according to the standard procedures.The result of bacterial tests on the manipulation surfaces and pavements testified the presence of these bacterial agents: Staphylococcus aureus, Escherichia coli, Pseudomonas aeruginosa, Proteus mirabilis and Bacillus subtilis. These results show that there is an urgent need to applicate correct disinfection scheme in these clinics in order to control the nosocomial infections.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">https://sites.google.com/a/ubt.edu.al/rssb/ajas_2014/12_Olsi_Doku_pp%2063-65.pdf?attredirects=0&amp;d=1</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">en</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Albanian Journal of Agricultural Sciences</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2218-2020</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.13/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>