<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="AL2016109779">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Heavy Metal Concentration and Physico-Chemical Parameters in Koder Kamza Soils</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>DUKA IRENA</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>SHALLARI SEIT</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>MAÇI ARDIAN</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>SHEHU JULIAN</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Department of Agroenvironment and Ecology, Agricultural University of Tirana, Tirana - Albania</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Department of Agroenvironment and Ecology, Agricultural University of Tirana, Tirana - Albania</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Department of Agroenvironment and Ecology, Agricultural University of Tirana, Tirana - Albania</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Department of Agroenvironment and Ecology, Agricultural University of Tirana, Tirana - Albania</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">This study aims to provide information on some physicochemical parameters and some heavy metals concentration in
Koder Kamza soils. The sample was taken in 0-30 cm depth. Characterization of soil parameters included moisture
content, particle size, electrical conductivity, pH, iron (Fe), nitrogen (N), phosphorous (P), potassium (K) and heavy
metals like cadmium (Cd) copper (Cu), Cobalt (Co), nickel (Ni) lead (Pb), zinc (Zn). Particle size analysis was
determined via the hydrometer method of Bouyoucous (1951)</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">EC and TDS were determined by using Conductivity
meter Cond 7110</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">soil pH was measured electrometrically with a glass electrode pH meter Sartorius Basic Meter PB-
11</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">the concentrations of Fe and heavy metals (Cd, Cu, Co, Ni, Pb and Zn) were determined by using atomic
absorption spectrophotometer (AAS). N and P total presence in the soil were determined by colorimetric method, total
K was determined by Flame Photometer Models PFP7. Total carbon (C) and total organic matter (OM) were also
determined by modified Walkley and Black method. Moisture content results ranged from 4.35% to 4.38%, the values
of soil pH ranged from 6.33 to 6.52, i.e. within the range for optimal growth of plants, total carbon ranged between
1.16 and 1.17%, total organic matter content between 2 and 2.02 %, an electrical conductivity between 75.6 and
93.5μS/cm. The texture resulted to be sandy loam with average composition of 61.83 % sand, 21.77 % silt and 16.4 %
clay. Nitrogen 0.13 and 0.14 % is slightly higher than that of the control soil. Phosphorus 0.09 and 0.1% contents were
low and high respectively. Total concentration of Fe ranged between 3083.07-3263.10 mg/kg. Cd and Cu was found in
lower levels (</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">https://sites.google.com/a/ubt.edu.al/rssb/revista_2_2015_files/11_IRENA%20DUKA%20pp%20157-161.pdf?attredirects=0&amp;d=1</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Albanian Journal of Agricultural Sciences</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2218-2020</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.14/n.2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>