<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="AL2016106252">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Growth Indicators of Engraulis encrasicolus, (Linnaeus, 1758) Populations in Albanian Waters for Two Seasons of their Lifecycle</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>KRISTO ROLAND</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>HARIZAJ FATOS</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>MACI ADRIAN</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>KOLITARI JERINA</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Department of Aquaculture and Fisheries, Faculty of Agriculture and Environment, Agricultural University of Tirana, Albania</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Faculty of Agriculture and Environment, Agricultural University of Tirana, Albania,</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">allometry</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_24962</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Morphometric studies are essential to determine the growth form and growth rate of a species, which is important for responsible exploitation and management of the population of a species. The length-weight relationship was computed for the anchovy Engraulis encrasicolus, (Linnaeus, 1758). A total of 656 individuals were used for the study. The length and weight measurements of the fish are positively related to each other. From the study result that the average values according to seasons of coefficient "b" are 3.0259 ± 0.1633 for the period from January to February and 2.8585 ± 0.1788 for period October - November. Condition factor for the same period respectively have values Kn = 0.60 ± 0.23 (January 0.45 ± 0.04 and February 0.72 ± 0.22) and Kn = 0.90 ± 0.42 for period October – November. The study indicates inter-seasonal variation by change of weight in relation to length of fish. The higher Kn value (Kn = 1.19) is indicative of increased deposition of fat as a result of adaptability and high feeding activity, corresponding with the end of the spawning season.The weight-length relationship is a useful tool in fish biology, physiology, ecology and stock assessment. In fish, size is generally more biologically relevant than age, mainly because several ecological and physiological factors are more size-dependent than age-dependent. Consequently, variability in size has important implications for diverse aspects of fisheries science and population dynamics [7]</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">https://drive.google.com/a/ubt.edu.al/file/d/0B_i7_HlsPT6HaDhmVHhpRW5nOWc/view?usp=sharing</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Albanian Journal of Agricultural Sciences</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2218-2020</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.14/n.1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>