<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A04843">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">RESOURCE AND ECOLOGICAL ZONING OF FORESTS IN BRYANSK OBLAST</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>РЕСУРСНО-ЭКОЛОГИЧЕСКОЕ РАЙОНИРОВАНИЕ ЛЕСОВ БРЯНСКОЙ ОБЛАСТИ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>USTINOV Mikhail</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>USTINOV Маxim</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Bryansk State Engineering Academy</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Russian Timiryazev State Agrarian University</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">forestry</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Zoning</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3055</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_36936</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Forestry zoning has always been and still is of great importance for forest management. According to the Forest Code (2006), there was a radical change in the attitude to the forest lands rating towards their multipurpose use. Effective management of forestry and forest industry requires modern systematization of the division of the forest fund territory into the typical areas. The purpose of the research is to divide the Bryansk region territory into resource-ecological forest areas with the use of multivariate statistical methods. An assessment of the complex of 34 variables which are the characteristics of soil-climatic, ecological, forest and forest valuation factors was carried out. Besides the considered variables show economic, social and ecological factors in all the 18 forestries of the region. Six main components of the explained factors were determined. According to the Euclidean distance, soil and climatic factors have the greatest load. The second place in the load level take the areas of separate structures of the forest fund, the areas depending on the types of forests and taxation indices by forests’ types. When clustering along the separation strategy, 7 groups of forestries by six main components were revealed. Their reliability is confirmed by clustering of the objects, subsequently conducted by the coordinates of objects in the system of 5-, 4- and 3 principal components. In the four analyzed variants of the discriminant assessment, an intercluster Mahalanobis distance (D2) exceeds the 95 percent confidence level. An assessment of the differences between the averages of variables according to the Student’s t-test revealed the variables influencing the difference between clusters. Thus, the selected clusters have the lowest variability of indicators, included in the analysis, and therefore they correspond to the notion of typicality (homogeneity) for the entire list of indicators involved. "A schematic map of the resource-ecological forest areas of the Bryansk region" which may serve as a basis for the typological, ecological, economic and other types of fractional or ambitious zoning as well as for other scientific and industrial purposes was made.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Обосновано разделение территории Брянской области на ресурсно-экологические лесные районы с учётом почвенно-климатических, экологических условий, пространственной структуры и таксационных показателей лесного фонда с применением многомерных статистических методов.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://ojs.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/58/35</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.23/n.3</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>