<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A04854">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">USAGE OF WOOD CONCRETE AS THERMAL INSULATION-BALLAST MATERIAL OF UNDERWATER PIPELINES OF THE CENTRALIZED HEATING SYSTEM</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ПРИМЕНЕНИЕ АРБОЛИТА В КАЧЕСТВЕ ТЕПЛОИЗОЛЯЦИОННО-БАЛЛАСТНОГО МАТЕРИАЛА ПОДВОДНЫХ ТРУБОПРОВОДОВ ЦЕНТРАЛИЗОВАННОГО ТЕПЛОСНАБЖЕНИЯ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>CHEMODANOV Аlexander</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>GORINOV Yuriy</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>SAFIN  Rushan</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>ALIBEKOV Sergey</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Volga State University of Technology</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Kazan National Research Technological University</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">E80</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">pipes</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5925</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">New technique development is impossible without composite materials. By means of the optimum selection of the components, it is possible to obtain the best physical and mechanical properties of the materials. Wood concrete belongs to such materials. It can be used both for buildings construction and for underwater construction of heat pipes. Pipeline consists of a steel pipe in the plastic protective cover and tube space, filled with wood concrete. The goal of the research is to ground the usage of a new wood concrete composite with 1160 kg/m3 density and with the coefficient of heat conduction of 0.12 W/mK as a cover of underwater pipelines of the centralized heat supply. With this end in view, a test of stability was carried out and the waste of heat through the wall was defined. Results. The calculations showed the following: underwater pipe construction has a negative buoyancy and stable position in the soil, waste of heat is less than the normalized value. Based on these results, it was concluded that the elaborated wood concrete composite has the necessary properties to be used as thermal insulation and ballasting of underwater pipelines.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Обосновано применение арболита для тепловой изоляции и балластировки подводных теплопроводов. Выполнены расчёты устойчивости трубопровода и передачи теплоты через стенку трубопроводной конструкции, включающей стальную трубу в защитном полиэтиленовом кожухе с заполненным межтрубным пространством арболитом в качестве теплоизоляционно-балластного материала.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://ojs.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/60/37</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.23/n.3</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>