<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A11470">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">THEORETICAL RESEARCH OF PLANTLETS LIFTING PROCESS WITH SOIL CLOD</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ТЕОРЕТИЧЕСКИЕ ИССЛЕДОВАНИЯ ПРОЦЕССА ВЫКОПКИ САЖЕНЦЕВ С КОМОМ ПОЧВЫ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>DRUCHININ  Denis</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>DORNYAK Olga</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>DRAPALYUK Mikhail</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>FGBOU VPO «Voronezh State Timber Engineering Academy»</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2013-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">planting stock</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Mathematical models</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_16111</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_24199</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">At present heavy plantlets, replaced with soil clod, are more extensively used in silvicultural treatment, reforestation work and gardening of territories. Earlier the authors suggested the design of the special machine - plant lifter, and developed the mathematic model of interaction of the plant lifter tool with the soil and plantlet roots for mechanization of lifting process and replanting of heavy plantlets with soil clod. The aim of this research is study of plantlets lifting process with soil clod on the basis of developed mathematic model of the studied process through computer experiments. The basis for the model is the developed by the authors difference equation of the basic element of the plant lifter – its operating tool in the form of a double-arm lever around a stationary shaft. To solve this difference equation, the program “Modeling of movement of operating tool for lifting plantlets with soil clod” in Matlab programming language was developed and necessary calculations were made. Computer experiment with the model consisted in simulation of lifting process of plantlets with soil clod by the plant lifter. The operating tool moves in semicircle at a constant speed in the soil, strengthened with plant roots. Thus a few blade components cut the plantlet root, others are involved in the soil cutting process. So, dependence of the total value of moment on all external forces, applied on the operating tool of the machine about the ОYМоу axis and other moments, produced by other forces, are fixed. Conducting theoretical experiments of the mathematic model enabled to study lifting process of plantlets with soil clod by the plant lifter. The results obtained enable to calculate force values of the studied process and subsequently define optimal design parameters of the operating tool of the plant lifter.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Разработана математическая модель рабочего процесса машины для выкопки саженцев с комом почвы. На основе математического моделирования проведены теоретические исследования процесса выкопки саженцев с комом почвы. Представлены результаты компьютерных экспериментов, позволяющие оценить силовые показатели исследуемого процесса.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://ojs.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/102/88</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.18/n.2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>