<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A11462">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">GROWTH PARTICULARITIES AND LONG LIFE OF «INDUSTRIAL OAKS» STANDS AT THE CLIMATIC SOIL TYPE OF DRY STEPPE DON REGION</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ОСОБЕННОСТИ РОСТА И ДОЛГОВЕЧНОСТЬ НАСАЖДЕНИЙ «ДУБРАВ ПРОМЫШЛЕННОГО ЗНАЧЕНИЯ» НА ЗОНАЛЬНЫХ ПОЧВАХ СУХОСТЕПНОГО ПРИДОНЬЯ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>MANAENKOV Alexander</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>KOSTIN Maksim</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>SHKURINSKIY Vyacheslav</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Department of Struggle Against Agro-Landscape Degradation at the State Scientific Institution «All-Russian Research Institute of Forest Amelioration»</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2013-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">plantations</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5990</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Planted forest outliers are of high ecological and social and economic importance for almost all unforested regions in the South of Russia. They grow in the plain territory near the water (plakors). Most of the forests were planted in the 1950s (Volgograd and Astrakhan oblasts), the Don and the Manych (Rostov oblast). Surrounded by ploughed fields, they carry out the functions of biological reserves, places of outdoor activities and the source of merchantable wood. The purpose of the research is to make better some technologies in order to increase longevity, improve productivity and meliorative efficiency of Oak groves growing in the unforested zone of dry steppe. Materials on forest management (2004–2005) were studied, an exploratory research of the 30-60-years stands, which occupy several thousand hectares, was carried out. Growth period, state of stand and the main soil characteristics were studied in detail on the 11 study plots, which were made in accordance with the standard methods, ened in 6–7 years after their planting. A large share of top storey of trees dried out, there were It was found out that the state of all Oaks which were planted in the 1950s many trees with dry tops. To create vast plantations in heavy subsaline and chestnut and dark chestnut soil, English oak is the best species to plant. In case of traditional cultivation, life period of Oak groves is no more 40-60 years. The main reason for early death of artificial stands is forest environment destruction and deterioration of water schedule of mid-age stands. Pure stands are replaced with steppe plant formation, mixed stands are replaced with underbrush shrubs. The stands which are considered to be more productive and durable are planted in low areas and in the shady slopes of upland hydrographic network. They are of better productive capacities due to additional soil moistening by redistributed precipitation. So, it is wise to use the landscape method while planting trees in the dry steppe. At that, Oak trees should be planted at the best ecotopes (best forest sites). The upper lands and slopes should be left apart in order to restore steppe vegetation as well as to create shrubby area. Pure narrow-row closed stand are the best conditions for Oak cultivation. If the silvicultural activities are well organized, 150–450 m3 duced, productive forest hunting and recreational lands will be formed. Usage of complex schemes of mixture of species lead to need in increased attention and additional costs on thinnings. Oak needs in constant agrotechnical tendings if the plantation is pure and with wide interrow spacing (5–6 m). At the heavy idiomorphic soil of arid area it is possible to improve the quality and life period of plantations by means of elongation of the period of rapid growth, and consequently, by means of intensification of differentiation of young stands, contribution to optimization of their density and longer preservation of forest environment. In order to achieve the specified results, it is important to accumulate large stocks of buffer moisture in the soil, create pure dense plantations, carry out timely thinning, stimulate of underbrush formation. The technology of creation of long-lived plantations at the plain territory near the water (plakors) in the arid area should include a 2–5-year clean cultivation, plantation establishment with 2,5–3,0 m raws ( number of planting pots - 7–10 ths./ha ), carrying out of agrotechnical tendings before closing of crop as well as thinnings every 2-3 year from the end of the juvenile period (up to 10–15 % to the number of trunks). For the purposes of stimulation of natural formation in the middle-aged plantations of uncompetitive soil-improving underbrush, for each 10– 15 raws of Oak it is advised to plant 3–4 raws of acacia. In case of small contour planting, it is reasonable to plant acacia at the plantations periphery. It is important to build dams in the stock strain to increase growth of the formed plantations. Nevertheless, dams building should not lead to their long-term flood during the warm season. Usage of the landscape approach and the new technology of plantations creation shall make it possible to increase life of Oak outliers in dry steppe up to 65–70 years. In some cases, better results are expected.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Приведены материалы изучения современного состояния, особенности роста чистых и смешанных искусственных дубрав на комплексе каштановых и темно-каштановых почв водоразделов Сало-Манычского междуречья. Обоснована и предложена технология повышения качества и долговечности древостоя дуба.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://ojs.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/108/115</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.18/n.2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>