<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A04863">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">BIOLOGICAL CHARACTERISTICS OF THE JUNGLANS L. GENUS IN THE CENTRAL BLACK EARTH REGION</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>БИОЛОГИЧЕСКИЕ ОСОБЕННОСТИ РОДА JUNGLANS L. В УСЛОВИЯХ ЦЕНТРАЛЬНОГО ЧЕРНОЗЕМЬЯ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>BARANOVA Tatiana</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>NIKOLAEV Evgeniy</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Voronezh State University</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F63</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">cultivation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">cytology</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2018</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2091</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The goal of this research is to study somatic ploidy of the local sorts of Junglans regia and its winter hardness depending on geographic origin and perspectivity of its cultivation and cultivation of its hybrid in conditions of Central Black Earth region. The following local sorts of germinated Junglans regia – Verkhnekievskaya, Verkhne-Ramonetskaya, Таrusovskaya, Limarevskaya, Кravtsovskaya, Каntemirovskaya, Perevalenskaya, Моrozovskaya – were the data for the study. Germinated Junglans regia of such Moldavian sorts as Tonkoskorlupnaya, Obyknovennaya, Bolgarskaya were used for the control. Constantly pressed slides were prepared by the methods, elaborated for European white birch. Examination of the microscope slides was carried out with the use of microscope МBI-6 in the optical field with К7х eye glass and 20, 40, 90 object glass. Twenty rootlets of each sort were analyzed. Four thousand interphases were studied. A share of multinucleate cells was calculated as a relation of their number to the total number of cells in the interphase (percentage). Winter hardness was determined by N.К. Vekhov scale. Conclusions. A share of multinucleate cells as a cytological index is connected with winter hardness of Junglans regia sorts. A share of multinucleate cells in the rootlets is significantly higher in local sorts of Junglans regia in comparison with the Moldavian sorts. Local sorts of Junglans regia have better winter hardness than the Moldavian sorts. Local somatic polyploidy in ontogeny hypothetically contributes to formation of more resistant species. Sorts of Junglans are perspective for cultivation in the Central Black Earth region. They may be used in landscaping and forestry.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Зимостойкость, заморозкоустойчивость, засухоустойчивость, устойчивость к вредителям и болезням, долговечность, характер роста, плодоношение являются показателями перспективности выращивания видов рода Junglans в условиях Центрального Черноземья. Доля многоядерных клеток как цитологический показатель связана с зимостойкостью форм Junglans regia. Доля многоядерных клеток в корешках значительно выше у местных форм Junglans regia, чем у молдавских. Местные формы Junglans regia отличаются большей зимостойкостью, чем молдавские. Частичная соматическая полиплоидия в онтогенезе предположительно способствует формированию более стойких особей. Виды рода Junglans перспективны для культивирования в Центральном Черноземье. Возможно их применение в садово-парковом строительстве и лесном хозяйстве.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://ojs.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/63/40</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.23/n.3</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>