<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A03095">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">VARIATION AND PROSPECTS OF CONIFERS IN THE CULTURE OF EX SITU IN THE SOUTHERN TAIGA SUBZONE</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ИЗМЕНЧИВОСТЬ И ПЕРСПЕКТИВНОСТЬ СОСНОВЫХ В КУЛЬТУРЕ EX SITU В ПОДЗОНЕ ЮЖНОЙ ТАЙГИ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>LAZAREVA Svetlana</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Volga State University of Technology</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2013-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Pinaceae</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Seasonal development</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Winter hardiness</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Drought resistance</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5886</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6909</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_16067</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2392</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The modern representatives of the pine family (Pinaceae Lindl.) are relatively few in number, nevertheless they are the most important tree species, which provide ecological services. Besides, they are of high commercial demand and are of aesthetic, phytosanitary and spiritual values. Irrational use of forest areas with low forest restoration, climate change, land degradation, increased droughts, increase of affected by fires, pests and deceases areas led to threat of extinction 55 species of Pine. At that, 31 species are still in a state close to threatening. Addressing biodiversity, Pine can go several ways, including introduction of a culture of ex situ. Botanical GardenInstitute of the Volga Tech has 74 years of experience in introduction of woody plants. An attempt to discuss the main results of the work on introduction and acclimatization of the genera Pinus, Picea, Abies, and Pseudotsuga in the family Pinaceae is made in the research. The objects of study were representatives of three subfamilies: Pinoideae Pilg. (Pinus L., Picea A. Dietr.), Laricoideae Melcioret Werermann (Pseudotsuga Carriere), Abietoideae Pilg. (Abies Mill.). All the objects of study are to complete a full cycle of seasonal development. Year-variability calendar dates the small onset of the individual phases of seasonal development or a lower rate of variation. Analysis of variance showed a high proportion of the influence of temperature on the level of variability fenodat. The trend lines show that the negative consequences in the long term may occur in P. jezoensis, P. asperata., P. schrenkiana, A. alba, A. concolor, P. strobus, P. peuce</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">conditionally negative – P. glehnii, P. omorica, P. pungens, A. balsamea, A. lasiocarpa, A. veitchii, A. nephrolepis, P. sibirica, P. pumila, P. mugo</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">positive – P. glauca, P. obovata, P. rubens, P. mariana, A. fraseri, A. sibirica subsp. semenovii, A. holophylla, P. banksiana, P. cembra and P. koraiensis. Drought tolerance test plants BGI, estimated from the time of loss of 50% contained in the isolated needles of water (MAS), showed varying degrees of resistance as a separate species and genus complexes in general. Comparatively high resistance to drought of pine subsections Cembrae and Strobi, fir sections of Momi and Grandis was shown. Data on the influence of climatic factors on the length of the annual growth of the shoots of the second order can build a number of drought-sections, subsections and clades (of the Spruce) with continental affiliation (in parentheses) in the order of decreasing: Contortae – Alba – Balsamea (FE – AZ – NA) – Cembrae (Az – FE – WE) – Grandis – Momi – V Clade (FE – AZ – NA – WE) – Strobi (NA – WE) – IV Clade – III Clade, generic complexes – Abies – Pinus – Picea. A similar series of demands to the heat in ascending order as follows: generic complexes – Picea – Abies – Pinus, sections, subsections, clades – V Clade (NA – WE) – Contortae – V Slade (FE) – Balsamea (FE – NA) – Grandis – Momi – Pinus (ZE – EA), V Clade (MAz – WE – EA), Balsamea (immediately) – Cembrae (Az – FE – WE) – Strobi (NA – WE). The age of generative phase of exotic species ranged from 6 to 51 years. To create an exotic conifer plantations for regionalized planting, mother material is best to choose for local seed plant reproduction of the most valuable biotypes. Indicators of pollen viability values are similar in the species belonging to the same section or subsection. The best indicators are characterized by pine subsection Strobi, followed by the representatives of sections Contortae and Pinus, and the list Cembrae. In the generic complexes Picea and Abies which are less than half emerging in a culture of pollen were viable.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">Представлены результаты исследований динамики сезонного развития, зимостойкости, засухоустойчивости, влияния количества осадков и сумм активных температур +10°С на величину текущих приростов побегов второго порядка, возраста возмужалости, мужской и женской генеративной сфер, сеянцев местной семенной репродукции 29 экзотов и трех местных видов семейства Pinaceae.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://ojs.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/120/122</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.19/n.3</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>