<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A11509">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">BIOGEOCENOSIS CHANGES IN CENTRAL PART OF THE BRAYNSK REGION AFTER HOT SUMMER-2010</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ИЗМЕНЕНИЯ В БИОГЕОЦЕНОЗАХ ЦЕНТРАЛЬНОЙ ЧАСТИ БРЯНСКОЙ ОБЛАСТИ ПОСЛЕ ЛЕТНЕЙ ЖАРЫ 2010 ГОДА</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>IVANOV Valery</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>MARCHENKO Sergey</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>GLAZUN Igor</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>NARTOV Dmitry</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>SOBOLEVA Ludmila</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Bryansk State Engineering and Technological Academy</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2013-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">forestry</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Pinus sylvestris</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Picea abies</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Quercus robur</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Betula pendula</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Fires</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3055</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5912</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5852</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_15794</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_26399</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2915</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Extensive and slow-moving anticyclone in the Central part of Russia in summer 2010 did not let pass other air masses in the region and led to heat wave. From June 24 till late August day-time temperature in the Bryansk region was constantly over 30°C. Recorded maximum was +38.4°С. Lack of atmospheric precipitates, low air humidity and reduction in reserves of all kinds of humidity in the soil accompanied the long heat wave. There were no such weather for more than a century. The work objective is to evaluate the condition of natural ecosystems components with the use monitoring data. The process of monitoring was launched in 2001 for scientific and practical purposes. The objects of research were forest soils, forest stands of Pinus sylvestris L., Picea abies L., Quercus robur L., Betula pendula Roth, undergrowth, genesic processes of the main forest forming species, soil mesofauna, sanitary- pathological condition of plantations and herb coens. The work was carried at the stationary sampling area with the use of standard approved methods. Soil research was based on the results of strong soil pits morphological characteristics laid on the stationary sampling areas. At that, an activity of some groups of soil mesofauna, earthworms activity in particular, was registered. Study of genesic processes of the main forest forming species was carried out with the use of traditional phonological methods. Besides, some authors methodological techniques were also used. Plants homeostasis evaluation, the European white birch evaluation in particular, was carried out by the system of Zakharov V.M. and his coauthors. Dendrochronological research was carried out by the system of Bitvinskas T.T. Woody plants accretion (height) study was carried out by the system of Molchanov A.A. and Smirnov V.V. Sanitary and forest pathological condition of the forest stands was determined with the use of standard methods. Low soil humidity caused by hot weather slows down the process of organic substances decomposition, reduces mesofauna and small mammals biodiversity. No significant deviances in genesic processes of the Pinus sylvestris L., Picea abies (L.) H.Karst., Quercus robur L., Betula pendula Roth for 2010-2011 years were revealed. The reason for it is that drought season took place in late July and August.Early leaves decolourizing and defoliation of the Betula pendula Roth were observed in the research area. Drought caused accretion reduction in diameter. A significant accretion reduction of autumn timber was observed. Biological sustainability of the Picea abies (L.) H.Karst., and Quercus robur L has become weaker. Picea abies (L.) H.Karst with lateral root system showed the most serious drying. Pinus sylvestris L., and Quercus robur L. species turned out to be more sustainable to the described weather conditions. Drought led to spread of the infection diseases among weak plantations. As a result, a number of dead-wood increased and forest pathological condition of the plants became worse. Fir-tree undergrowth drying, pine-tree (and in some cases oaks) undergrowth quality worsening can lead to forest succession in the nearest future. Herb plants growing on upland dry meadows and old arable lands suffered from drought most of all. All herb plants biodiversity survived, but plant stand productivity reduced. Consequences of drought season negative influence on plant community are evident, but the situation may worsen if the drought season will take place at the time of plants active growth.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Представлен анализ воздействия аномально высокой жары и засухи в июле-августе 2010 года на основные компоненты лесных биогеоценозов в Почепском районе (географическом центре) Брянской области. Выявлена неоднозначная реакция изучаемых представителей биоты на жару и засуху в зависимости от времени и длительности воздействия. Установлены компоненты, с наибольшим и наименьшим ущербом перенёсшие жару. Даны прогнозные оценки по устойчивости компонентов природных экосистем.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://ojs.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/91/77</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.17/n.1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>