<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A11551">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">MICROBIOLOGICAL INDICATION OF SOIL ECOLOGICAL CONDITIONS WHEN USING ALTERNATIVE AMELIORANTS</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>МИКРОБИОЛОГИЧЕСКАЯ ИНДИКАЦИЯ ПОЧВЕННО-ЭКОЛОГИЧЕСКИХ УСЛОВИЙ ПРИ ИСПОЛЬЗОВАНИИ НЕТРАДИЦИОННЫХ МЕЛИОРАНТОВ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>GORDEYEVA Tatyana</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>MALYUTA Olga</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>GAVRITSKOVA Natalia</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Volga State University of Technology</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2013-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">P34</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">soil micromorphological features</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_26827</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The research was conducted in Kokshaisk forest area, meant for a new arboretum of the Mari El Republic. The soil of the experimental plot is sod, mesopodzol, light loamy, developed from mantle loams. Alternative organic manure (AOM) on the basis of waste water mud and sawdust of conifers and broadleaved trees with 3 years composting duration was used in the experiment in a dose of 120 t/ha. The proportion of mud to filler is 1.4:1. The control was the option without ameliorant application. The virgin soil (forest), surrounding the arboretum, was tested as ecological control. Biological activity of the soil was defined using application methods. The toxic level of the soil ameliorant was evaluated through toxicological testing using three test-organisms: daphnia (DaphniamagnaStraus), Ecolum luminescent bacteria and Chlorella (Algae) (Chlorellavulgaris Beijer). Recovery and census of microorganisms was performed using conventional microbiological methods. It has been concluded that alternative organic manure, which is used in the experiment, is characterized by 4 grade hypotoxity hazard category for the environment. Microbiological analysis showed that the bacterial complex with the population about 4.5 – 17.7 mln. cfu/gm of moisture-free soil is dominant in the micro flora of the soils under study. Micromycete population is insignificant, it ranges from 85.0 thousand cfu/gm of moisture-free soil and lower. The analysis of the population of main physiological groups of micro-organisms showed that the use of compost on the basis of waste water mud increases the heterotrophic microorganism population in comparison with the heterotrophic microorganism population in nonfertilized soil. The use of AOM increases the number of ammonifiers, their spores, aminoautotrophs, actinomycetes, it is indicative of enhancement of mineralization processes in soil. Relative index of the soil biogenicity, reflecting the proportion of bacteria number and fungus number, is varying over a rather wide range: from 78.82 (virgin soil) to 193.75 (manured soil) and is located in the following manner in order of reduction of biogenicity index: forest &lt; control &lt; ameliorant. The rate of mycelial microflora in the structure of cellulose-digesting microorganisms is increasing. It has been concluded that the number of azotobacters and yeasts reduced in soil with ameliorant. The use of compost on the basis of waste water mud increases the species diversity of micromycetes in comparison with the species diversity of micromycetes in the control soil. Thus the frequency of occurrence and the number of different kinds of cellulose-digesting fungi is increasing. The cellulose-digesting soil activity, treated with alternative organic manure, is increasing, in comparison with the activity of the virgin soil. As it can be seen from the above the use of alternative organic manure for sod, mesopodzol, light loamy soil at the first stage of amelioration activates microbiological processes of soil, including the processes of organic matter decomposition that helps to accumulate fertilizer elements for plants.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Исследовано микробиологическое состояние дерново-подзолистой легкосуглинистой почвы, мелиорированной нетрадиционным органическим удобрением на основе осадков сточных вод. Оценку проводили по трем группам показателей: биологическая активность почвы (протеазная, аммонифицирующая, целлюлозоразрушающая)</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">численность и функциональное разнообразие почвенных микроорганизмов</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">экологотрофическая структура микробного комплекса почвы. Установлено, что удобрения активизируют почвенно-микробиологические процессы, усиливая минерализацию углерод- и азотсодержащих органических соединений, что способствует накоплению элементов питания для растений.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://ojs.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/97/83</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.17/n.1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>