<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A10435">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">CYTOGENETIC CHANGES OF BETULA PENDULA SPROUTS WHEN ENVI-RONMENT POLLUTION</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>ЦИТОГЕНЕТИЧЕСКИЕ ИЗМЕНЕНИЯ ПРОРОСТКОВ БЕРЁЗЫ ПОВИСЛОЙ ПРИ ЗАГРЯЗНЕНИИ ГОРОДСКОЙ СРЕДЫ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>BARANOVA Tatiana</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Voronezh State University</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K70</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">environment</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">pollution</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Betula</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2593</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6077</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_892</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The results of study of European white birch (Betula pendula Roth.) sprouts cytogenetic responses are given. The sprouts were obtained from the seeds, taken in Voronezh and its suburb (different level of man-made pollution). It was shown that environment pollution provoked significant changes of all the cytogenetic characteristics of European white birch (Betula pendula Roth.) sprouts. It particularly concerns cytogenetic distortions. It was determined that in case of low environment pollution, mitotic index was 9 %, and the share of cytogenetic distortions was 4,2 %. In the area of high environment pollution, mitotic index is 8,6 - 10,5 %, and the share of cytogenetic distortions is 8,9 - 9,3%. Figures of all the cytogenetic distortions are closely correlated with each other. There is particularly strong correlation between the share of prophases and the mitotic index, which is nonlinear. Cytogenetic distortions, which include another information about Euro-pean white birch seed generation changes, are the least correlated with cytogenetic characteristics. Cytogenetic characteristics of European white birch (Betula pendula) sprouts (share of cytogenetic distortions in particular), may be successfully used in assessing seed generation, together with other characteristics to estimate environment pollution influence on the biota.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Приведены результаты изучения цитогенетических реакций проростков берѐзы повислой (Betula pendula Roth.), полученных из семян, собранных в районах г. Воронежа и на пригородной территории с разным уровнем антропогенного загрязнения. Установлено, что при слабой степени загрязнения среды митотический индекс (МИ) составляет 9 %, а доля цитогенетических нарушений (ЦН) – 4,2 %. В районах с сильной степенью загрязнения МИ колеблется от 8,6 до 10,5 %, а доля ЦН – от 8,9 до 9,3%. Семенное потомство из относительно экологически чистого района отличается от контроля по цитогенетическим характеристикам: более низкому митотическому индексу и статистически большему числу нарушений деления.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://ojs.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/79/56</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.26/n.2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>