<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A11365">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">INFLUENCE ANALYSIS OF PHYSICAL AND MECHANICAL PROPERTIES OF WOOD ON THE QUALITY OF ACOUSTIC PANELS</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>АНАЛИЗ ВЛИЯНИЯ ФИЗИКО-МЕХАНИЧЕСКИХ СВОЙСТВ ДРЕВЕСИНЫ НА КАЧЕСТВО АКУСТИЧЕСКИХ ПАНЕЛЕЙ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>SHLYCHKOV Sergey</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>IVANOV Oleg</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Volga State University of Technology</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2013-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Wood</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8421</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">It is known that wooden panels are widely used in decoration. If the panels are used to improve the quality of sounds in the premises, they are referred to acoustic panels. Wooden acoustic panels, which are attached to the ceiling or walls, are considered in the article. It is grounded that designing of the construction which could have maximum number of natural frequencies (full spectrum) below the critical frequency is necessary for an effective adjustment to the acoustic characteristics of a room in the low frequency range. The frequency is determined on the basis of specific geometrical and physical parameters. Expected dynamic model of the panel is designed on the basis of finite elements. Eight-node shell finite elements with 6 nodal degrees of freedom are used to discretize the plate. An iteration method in the subspace of eigen vector is used for calculation of twenty lowest natural frequencies and modes of vibration. Acoustic panel is represented in the form of hinged rectangular plate made of spruce wood. The four constitutive variants of acoustic panels from different plates of timber were considered. Displacement fields calculated for normal distributed load were made and analyzed. An analysis of influence of elastic material properties on the dynamic properties of the panel was carried out. In the lower frequency range a comparative analysis of oscillation spectrum of the panels was carried out and the best option was found. It was determined that in order to achieve high quality of acoustic panels they should be made of timber obtained through half-radial saw cut.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Анализируются динамические характеристики акустических панелей, изготовленных из пиломатериалов древесины ели с различными физико-механическими свойствами. Расчётная динамическая модель панели построена на базе метода конечных элементов. В диапазоне низших частот проведён сравнительный анализ спектра колебаний панелей, на основании которого даны рекомендации по выбору пиломатериала для их изготовления.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://ojs.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/115/101</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.20/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>