<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016A10429">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">DEVICE FOR HEAT TRANSFER FROM CHIPPINGS WHEN STORAGE IN HEAPS</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>УСТРОЙСТВО ДЛЯ ОТВОДА ТЕПЛА ИЗ МАССИВА ТЕХНОЛОГИЧЕСКОЙ ЩЕПЫ В УСЛОВИЯХ КУЧЕВОГО ХРАНЕНИЯ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>BRATILOV Dmitry</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>DESNEV Alexander</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Northern (Arctic) Federal University</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">pipes</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Models</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Forestry production</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5925</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4881</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3061</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Introduction. Woodprocessing enterprises store chippings and other particulate wood-base materials at the unsheltered storage area in the heaps. Serious shortcoming of the mode of storage is spontaneous heating of chippings up to smoulder temperature and its spontaneous ignition caused by vital activity of microorganisms. As a result of moldering, cellulose content is decreased and timber chemical omposition is changed. It leads to permanent losses of vast number
of chippings and provokes fire hazardous situation. Chipping is heated in the center of a heap most of all, accumulating heat. Thus, it is bligatory to deflect the heat and lower the temperature of chippings. It is possible to solve the problem with the help of system of heatremoving elements,
made on the basis of heat pipes. The goal of the research is to study a test model of a device for heat transfer from chippings when storage in heaps. Tasks in hand is to develop and produce a test model of heat pipe, and to experimentally study pipe temperature head. Research technique.The test model of heat pipe made of stainless steel 08Х13 (2,5 mm width and 50 mm diameter) was elaborated and produced. Body of pipe consists of cylindrical and conical portions and it includes valve cover. The valve is meant for pipe filling with low boiling liquid. Pipe capacity is 2,65 l. Acetone with 56○C boiling temperature was used as heat-transfer material. Surrounding air temperature (Тsur.air ) was 16○С. The plan of experiment included two variable factors: temperature of
heated medium Тheated medium. , оС</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">and volume of heat carrier Vheat carrier volume, l. Pipe temperature in the evaporation zone Т evaporation ○С and Тcondensation ○С in the condensation zone were measured in the course of the experiment, than temperature difference ΔТ, ○С was defined evaporation сondensation Mathematic simulation and results interpretation. Regression analysis made it possible to
define mathematic dependence of temperature difference ΔТ, ○С on the temperature of heated medium Тheated medium , ○С and heat carrier volume in the pipe Vheat carrier volume , l. Allowed to define that pipe rejected heat more intensively when it was filled with heat-transfer material up to 0,23…0,30 of its inner volume. Conclusions. The obtained mathematical relation allows to define the necessary heat, which heat-transmitting element may transfer from the heap of chippings into the environment, consequently, it is the device for heat spreading
system design .</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">В статье приведено описание конструкции и даны рабочие характеристики теплового элемента, предназначенного для отвода излишнего тепла из массы технологической щепы при хранении еѐ кучевым способом. Проблема заключается в самопроизвольном нагреве щепы до температуры тления и самовоспламенения под воздействием жизнедеятельности микроорганизмов, в результате чего ухудшается качество технологической щепы и возникает пожароопасная ситуация. Для предотвращения негативных последствий предлагается отводить излишнее тепло от технологической щепы с помощью системы, состоящей из тепловых труб.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://ojs.volgatech.net/index.php/forest/article/view/76/53</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>VESTNIK of Volga State University of Technology. Series: Forest, Ecology, Nature Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2306-2827</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.26/n.2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>