<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016P17252">
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">ОЗЁРНАЯ И СЕРЕБРИСТАЯ ЧАЙКИ НА ТЕРРИТОРИИ ХАКАСИИ</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>HERRING AND BLACK-HEADED GULLS ON THE KHAKASSIA TERRITORY</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Savchenko  A.P.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Emelyanov  V.I.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Karpova  N.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Savchenko  P.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Kucherenko  A.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2016-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L20</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">biogeography</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_915</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>Keywords: Khakassia, biodiversity conservation, birds, herring gull, black-headed gull, limiting factors, wetlands, viral infections, influenza A virus</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Республика Хакасия расположена в пределах северо-западных отрогов Саяно-Алтайского нагорья и занимает значительную часть Минусинской котловины. Протяженность территории с севера на юг составляет 460 км, с запада на восток (в наиболее широкой части) – 200 км. Площадь Республики Хакасия 61 900 км2. Общая протяженность рек составляет 8 тыс. км, самые крупные реки Хакасии – Енисей, Абакан, Чулым и Томь. В республике более 500 озѐр. Чайковые птицы – важнейшее звено экосистем водоѐмов Хакасии. В работе представлены результаты исследования, характеризующие современное состояние
двух видов чайковых (озѐрной и серебристой), встречающихся на внутренних водоѐмах Республики Хака-
сия. Представлены сведения о характере пребывания и численности. Обсуждаются причины сокращения
численности ранее многочисленной озѐрной чайки.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The Republic of Khakassia covers the big part of Khakass-Minusinsk Depression, and located within
the north-western spurs of the Sayan-Altai mountains. The length from north to south is 460 km, from west to east
(in the widest part) – 200 km. Khakassia Republic Square is 61 900 km2. The total length of the rivers is 8 thousand
km. The Yenisei, Abakan, Chulym and Tom rivers are the largest in Khakassia. There are more than 500 lakes
in the republic. Gull birds are the important link of Khakassia pounds ecosystems. The paper presents the results of
investigation, describing the current state of 2 gull species (black-headed and herring gulls) that inhabit the inland
waters of the Republic of Khakassia. Information about the current species composition and distribution is presented.
The reasons for the abundance rarity of previous large black-headed gull are discussed.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://modernscienc-org.1gb.ru/release/USNO_2016_5_2_tom.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Modern Science Success</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2412-6608</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.6/n.№5 (part 2), 2016</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>