<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016P12579">
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">КОГДА ОБЩИНА ПЕРЕСТАЛА БЫТЬ МИРОМ</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>WHEN THE COMMUNITY STOPPED BEING THE WORLD</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Lurye  S.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">E51</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Rural population</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6705</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>Key words: peasant community, self-governing world, church parish, collectivization</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Статья посвящена исследованию вопроса о функционировании русской крестьянской об-
щины как церковного прихода, истории духовенства в русской деревне и его связи с крестьянами. Рассмат-
ривается упадок духовной жизни русской деревни в XIX – начале XX века. С этой точки зрения исследует-
ся процесс отхода крестьян от религии в 20-ые годы, духовный слом и отсутствие сопротивления коллекти-
визации. Делается вывод, что хотя крестьянская община переживала в эти годы расцвет как трудовой кол-
лектив, она теряла свой идеальный смысл, и потому не могла выйти из периода смуты, теряя свой статус
самоуправляющегося ''мира''. Результаты исследования могут быть использованы для разработки политики
по отношению к российской деревне в духовной и культурной сферах.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The article is devoted to the study the functioning of the Russian peasant community as the Church
parish, the history of the clergy in the Russian countryside and its relationship with the peasants. The spiritual life
decline of the Russian village in XIX – the beginning of the XX century is considered. From this point of view the
process of peasants’ withdrawal from religion in the 20th years, spiritual demolition and lack of resistance of collectivization
are investigated. It is concluded that though the peasant community endured these years blossoming as
a labor collective, it lost its ideal meaning and therefore it couldn't leave the distemper period, also losing the status
of the self-governing ''world''. Results of the research can be used for the development of policy relation to the Russian
village in spiritual and cultural spheres.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://media.wix.com/ugd/3e7d27_60fd80d1243849019f1ac86891d5fdb7.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Modern Science Success</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2412-6608</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.7/n.№3, 2015</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>