<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016P13730">
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">ТЕОРЕТИЧЕСКИЙ АНАЛИЗ ЭКОНОМИЧЕСКИХ КАТЕГОРИЙ, ИСПОЛЬЗУЕМЫХ ПРИ ИССЛЕДОВАНИИ МАРКЕТИНГОВЫХ СТРАТЕГИЙ ПРЕДПРИЯТИЙ АПК</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>THEORETICAL ANALYSIS OF ECONOMIC CATEGORIES</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="">
      <dcterms:alternative>USED AT RESEARCH OF MARKETING STRATEGY OF THE AGRARIAN AND INDUSTRIAL COMPLEXES ENTERPRISES</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Kazova  Z.M.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Abrokova  L.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">E10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">agricultural economics</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Policies</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8672</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6062</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>Key words: agro-industrial complex, marketing strategy, agromarketing activity of the enterprises</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">В статье проведено исследование проблемы развития маркетинговых стратегий агропромышленного комплекса в период трансформации экономики. В настоящей работе проведен теоретический анализ экономических категорий, используемых при исследовании маркетинговых стратегий предприятий АПК. Сделан вывод, что маркетинговые стратегии представляют собой, по существу, ведущую систему деятельности агропромышленного предприятия по изучению и удовлетворению потребительского спроса в
условиях появления новых, более сложных задач, обусловленных динамичностью и неопределенностью
экономической ситуации.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">A problem of development of marketing strategy of agro-industrial complex during economy transformation is conducted in the article. In the real work the theoretical analysis of the economic categories used at research of marketing strategy of the enterprises of agro-industrial complex is carried out. The conclusion is drawn that marketing strategy represent, in essence, leading system of activity of the agro-industrial enterprise for studying and satisfaction of a consumer demand in the conditions of emergence of the new, more complex challenges caused by dynamism and uncertainty of an economic situation.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://media.wix.com/ugd/3e7d27_b3aaaad50ea1436192841e289aa4dd94.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Modern Science Success</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2412-6608</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.4/n.№5, 2015</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>