<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016P11812">
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">ЭКОЛОГИЧЕСКИЕ ОСОБЕННОСТИ ПОЧВЕННЫХ РЕСУРСОВ  БЕЛОРЕЧЕНСКОГО РАЙОНА КРАСНОДАРСКОГО КРАЯ</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>ECOLOGICAL FEATURES OF SOIL RESOURCES IN BELORECHENSK  REGION OF KRASNODAR TERRITORY</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Fedorenko  K.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">P35</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">soil fertility</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7170</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>Key words: agriculture sector, soil degradation, soil modification, waste production of fertilizers, slitization, sludge collectors, phosphogypsum, ecology</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">В статье анализируются экологические аспекты природно-ресурсного потенциала  края, который обычно связывают с зоной рекреации, а затем с почвенными ресурсами. Исследования показали, что интенсивные технологии возделывания сельскохозяйственных культур привели к развитию деградационных процессов, таких, как: снижение содержания в почве гумуса, подвижных элементов питания, её уплотнение и слитизация. Решение этих проблем – актуальная проблема аграрного сектора.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The article analyzes the environmental aspects of natural resource potential of the territory, which is usually associated with the area of recreation, and then with soil resources. The studies have shown that intensive technologies of cultivation of crops led to developing of degradation processes, such as: reduction of soil humus, mobile nutrients, its seal and slitization. The solution of these problems is the actual problem of the agricultural sector.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://media.wix.com/ugd/3e7d27_1660bd039ef74b5e8074835a507147b0.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Success of Modern Science and Education</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2412-9631</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.4/n.№2, 2015</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>