<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016P13911">
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">РЕГУЛИРОВАНИЕ ЧИСЛЕННОСТИ СОРНЫХ РАСТЕНИЙ ПРИ ВНЕДРЕНИИ ЭНЕРГОСБЕРЕГАЮЩИХ ТЕХНОЛОГИЙ ОСНОВНОЙ ОБРАБОТКИ ПОЧВЫ</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>QUANTITY REGULATION OF WEEDS DURING THE IMPLEMENTATION OF ENERGYEFFICIENT TECHNOLOGIES OF MAIN CULTIVATION OF LAND</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Ivchenko  V.K.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Voloshin  E.I.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Rudoy  N.G.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">cultivation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2018</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>Key words: crop rotation, weeds, soil cultivation, herbicides, spring wheat</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Исследования, проведенные в зернопаровом севообороте на черноземе выщелоченном свидетельствуют, что вторая пшеница после чистого пара имеет высокую степень засоренности сорными растениями, среди которых превалирующее положение занимает овсюг. Установлено, что уровень засоренности посевов яровой пшеницы для овсюга превышал порог экономической эффективности на отвальном и поверхностном фонах в 6-10 раз соответственно. Применение баковой смеси гербицидов позволило резко снизить засоренность посевов яровой пшеницы со 190-243 шт/м2 до 4-7 шт/м2, при этом доля овсюга в посевах яровой пшеницы снизилась до 0,1-0,4%.
Полученные результаты свидетельствуют, что замена отвальной обработки почвы на поверхностную по-
вышает уровень рентабельности возделывания зерна яровой пшеницы.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang=" ">The researches, carried out in corn-fallow crop rotation on leached chernozem soil, indicate that wheat (Triticum) after pure fallow has high level of clogging with weeds, among which wheat oat (Avena fatua) prevails. It is estimated that the level of clogging with weeds of spring wheat for wheat oat exceeded threshold of economical effectiveness on different methods of cultivation of land from 6 to 10 times respectively.
Using the mixture of herbicides allowed to reduce the level of clogging with weeds of spring wheat for wheat oat from 190-243 pc/m2 to 4-7 pc/m2, along with the amount of oat grass in the sowing of spring wheat reduced to 0,1 – 0,4 %.
The results of the research are the evidence that the change of the method of cultivation of land increases the level of profitability of spring wheat cultivation.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://media.wix.com/ugd/3e7d27_bedd806123a94cdc9a668380d87d78ce.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Success of Modern Science and Education</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2412-9631</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.4/n.№5, 2015</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>