<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016P13997">
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">КЛАССИФИКАЦИЯ СОРТОВ ПШЕНИЦЫ ПО СТЕПЕНИ ЧУВСТВИТЕЛЬНОСТИ К ФОТОПЕРИОДУ НА ОСНОВЕ ГЕНЕТИЧЕСКИХ АНАЛИЗОВ В УСЛОВИЯХ ЕСТЕСТВЕННОГО КОРОТКОГО ДНЯ АЗЕРБАЙДЖАНА</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>CLASSIFICATION OF VARIETES OF WHEAT BY SENSITIVITY DEGREE TO THE PHOTOPERIOD ON THE BASIS OF GENETIC ANALYSES IN THE CONDITIONS OF NATURAL SHORT DAY OF AZERBAIJAN</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Aliyev  E.B.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Ahmedov  Sh. H.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Gadzhieva  S.K.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">cultivation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2018</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>Key words: photoperiodic response, wheat, prepotent genes, recessive genes, genotype, sensitivity, expression, variety</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">В статье на основе многолетних генетических анализов «F2» впервые дана четкая классификация сортов пшеницы по степени чувствительности их к естественному короткому дню (11-13 час.), таким, каким является территория Азербайджанской Республики.
Показано, что сорта мягкой пшеницы в зависимости от числа доминантных генов «Ppd», определяющих их реакцию на естественный короткий день сгруппируются в 5-ти классах – класс нейтральной, слабой
чувствительности, относительно чувствительной, сильной и суперсильной чувствительности. Для каждого класса определены тестерные сорта, несущие разное количество доминантных генов «Ppd», колеблющих от одного до четырех генов.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">On the basis of long-term genetic analyses F2 accurate classification of varieties of wheat by degree of
their sensitivity to natural short day (11-13 hour) such what is the territory of the Azerbaijan Republic is given in
the article. It is shown, that varieties of common wheat depending on number of the dominant genes Ppd defining their sensitivity, reaction for natural short day will be grouped in 5 classes – a class of neutral, weak sensitivity, concerning
sensitive, strong and superstrong sensitivity. The varieties are defined for each class bearing different quantity of
dominant genes Ppd, shaking from one to four dominant genes of photoperiodic reaction.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://media.wix.com/ugd/3e7d27_bedd806123a94cdc9a668380d87d78ce.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Success of Modern Science and Education</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2412-9631</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.9/n.№5, 2015</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>