<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016P12816">
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">ОСНОВНЫЕ ВРЕДИТЕЛИ УНАБИ И РАЗРАБОТКА АГРОТЕХНИЧЕСКИХ МЕР БОРЬБЫ ПРОТИВ НИХ НА АПШЕРОНЕ</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>THE MAIN WRECKERS OF THE UNABI AND THE DEVELOPMENT OF AGROTECHNICAL MEASURES OF FIGHT AGAINST THEM ON APSHERON</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Zhigarevich  G.P.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Mamedova  G.D.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Mamedov D.Sh.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">H10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">pest monitoring</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_37663</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>Key words: unabi, unabi fly, purple scale, web tick, limacon, agrotechnical measures of fight, point, productivity</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Приведены краткие сведения биоэкологических особенностей развития основных вредителей унаби: унабиевой мухи, фиолетовой щитовки, паутинного клеща и улиток. Средний балл заселения унабиевой мухой - 1,2, фиолетовой щитовкой 0,7, паутинным клещом - 0,9, улитками - 2,9 баллов. Лучшие
результаты получены в варианте (глубокая обрезка + перекопка приствольных кругов). Биологическая эффективность вариантов опыта по отношению к контролю 82, 76 и 53%. Степень поврежденности по сравнению с контролем ниже соответственно в 5,7</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">4,3 и 2,1 раза. Испытание механического метода защиты унаби от улиток показало, что после проведения мероприятий исходная численность в 3,0 балла снизилась до 0,5. Биологическая эффективность 83%.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">Short data of bioecological features of the main wreckers development of unabi are provided: unabi fly, purple scale, web tick and snails. The average score settling of unabi fly is 1, 2, a purple scale – 0, 7, a web tick – 0, 9, snails – 2, 9 points. The best results are received in option (deep cutting + redigging of the tree trunk circles). Biological efficiency of experience options in relation to control is equal to 82, 76 and 53%. Damage degree
in comparison with control is lower respectively in 5,7</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">4,3 and 2,1 times. Test of a mechanical method of protection
of unabi against snails showed that after carrying out all the actions initial number in 3,0 points decreased to
0,5. Biological efficiency is 83%.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://media.wix.com/ugd/3e7d27_60fd80d1243849019f1ac86891d5fdb7.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Modern Science Success</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2412-6608</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.6/n.№3, 2015</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>