<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016P19133">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">AN ANALYSIS OF FACTORS INFLUENCING LENTILS AN CHICKPEAS MARKETING CHANNEL CHOICES AMONGST FARMERS IN SYRIAN ARAB REPUBLIC</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Abdelghany  Abdalatief</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Yiguzu  Atnaf Yigyzu</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Ebtesam  Jasem</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2016-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">cultivation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2018</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>Keywords: institutional and technical factors, New Institutional Economics, multinomial logistic regression model</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Farmers of lentil and chickpea in Aleppo and Al-Hassaka provinces do not use output markets effectively
due to a number of factors. The technical and institutional factors that demoralize them from marketing are
identified in this research. It is asserted that an explicit analysis on the relationship between technology, institutions
factors and markets may be useful in developing livelihood improving programs. In an effort to identify factors
influencing lentils and chickpeas marketing, data were collected from 221 farmers who were selected using multistage random sampling. To capture data, a questionnaire was administered through face-to-face interviews. In order
to test the factors that have a probability of influencing formal and informal marketing channel choices among the
sampled farmers, a multinomial logistic regression model was used in the area under study. The results show that
market information, expertise on grades and standards, contractual agreements, social capital, market infrastructure,
group participation and tradition significantly influence farmer marketing behavior. Several points are suggested to
activate the participation of farmers in the process of marketing effectively.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://modernscienc-org.1gb.ru/release/USN_2016_7_2_tom.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">en</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Modern Science Success</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2412-6608</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.4/n.№7 (part 2), 2016</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>