<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016P12549">
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">ЭФФЕКТИВНОСТЬ ИСПОЛЬЗОВАНИЯ ВЛАГИ ПОСЕВАМИ ЛУКА РЕПЧАТОГО В ЗАВИСИМОСТИ ОТ ОРОШЕНИЯ, УДОБРЕНИЯ И СИДЕРАТОВ</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>ЭФФЕКТИВНОСТЬ ИСПОЛЬЗОВАНИЯ ВЛАГИ ПОСЕВАМИ ЛУКА РЕПЧАТОГО В ЗАВИСИМОСТИ ОТ ОРОШЕНИЯ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="">
      <dcterms:alternative>УДОБРЕНИЯ И СИДЕРАТОВ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Avdeenko S.S.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">cultivation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2018</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>Key words: Allium sulfur, onions, irrigation, fertilizer, green manure, plant water relations, water consumption</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Приведены результаты исследований по влиянию комплекса орошения, удобрения и сиде-
ратов на продуктивность лука репчатого и эффективность использования воды посевами. Установлено
влияние дополнительного орошения на уровень влажности почвы по периодам вегетации лука, расход воды
растениями лука репчатого и коэффициент водопотребления. Подобраны эффективные нормы полива для
обеспечения оптимальной влажности почвы. Результаты исследований рекомендуются для использования
хозяйствами Ростовской области при выращивании лука репчатого на орошении.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Results of researches on influence of a complex of an irrigation, fertilizer and siderat on efficiency of
onion and effectiveness of use of water are given by crops. Influence of external reflux on the level of humidity of
the soil on the periods of vegetation of an onion, a water discharge by plants of onion and water consumption coefficient
is established. Efficient norms of watering for ensuring optimum humidity of the soil are picked up. Results
of researches are recommended for use by farms of the Rostov region at cultivation of onion on irrigation.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://media.wix.com/ugd/3e7d27_60fd80d1243849019f1ac86891d5fdb7.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Modern Science Success</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2412-6608</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.4/n.№3, 2015</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>