<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016P13704">
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">НОВЫЕ СИБИРСКИЕ СОРТА СОИ, УСТОЙЧИВЫЕ К ГИДРОТЕРМИЧЕСКИМ СТРЕССОРАМ И ПОРАЖЕНИЮ ФИТОПАТОГЕННЫМИ ГРИБАМИ</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>NEW SIBERIAN VARIETIES OF SOYBEANS THAT ARE RESISTANT TO HYDROTHERMAL STRESSORS AND DEFEAT PHYTOPATHOGENIC FUNGI</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Rozhanskaja  O.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Ashmarina  L.F.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Potapov  D.I.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Konyaeva  N. M.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F30</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Plant genetics</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">breeding methods</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_49985</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1079</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>Key words: soybean, breeding, Siberia, biotechnology, plant pathogens, sustainability, adaptability</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Для импортозамещения сои и расширения еѐ посевов в Сибири необходимы новые сорта с повышенной продуктивностью и устойчивостью к патогенам, не являющиеся ГМО. Цель работы – изучение новых сортов сои, задачи – оценка адаптивности к экологогеографическим факторам и устойчивости к
фитопатогенам в условиях Сибири. Селекционный материал создан в Сибирском НИИ кормов методом
многократного индивидуального отбора из линий, полученных с использованием сомаклональной измен-
чивости и γ-мутагенеза на базе сорта СибНИИК-315. Представлены результаты изучения эксперименталь-
ных линий, сочетающих скороспелость с высокой семенной продуктивностью в сложных погодных и фи-
тосанитарных условиях Сибири. Выявлена комплексная устойчивость к комплексу листостеблевых и семенных инфекций у сортообразцов 7RS, 8RS и 9RS. С 2013 г. проходит Государственное сортоиспытание скороспелый и высокоурожайный сорт сои СибНИИК-9 (9 RS). В 2015 г. передан в ГСИ ещѐ более скороспелый сорт сои Краснообская (8 RS).</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">For import substitution of soy and expansion of its crops in Siberia it is necessary to use new varieties with increased productivity and stable-STU to pathogens, which are not GMO. The purpose of the work was to learn new sorts of soybean. The tasks were to assess the adaptability to the ecological-geographical factors and resistance to phytopathogens in Siberia. Breeding material was created in the Siberian research Institute of forages by the method of multiple individually-selection of lines produced using somaclonal variation-the stability and γmutagenesis based on SibNIIK-315 varieties. The results of study of experimental lines that combine earliness with high seed production in difficult climatic and phytosanitary conditions of Siberia are presented here. Complex stability to the complex of leafy and seed infections in the 7RS, 8RS and 9RS samples is identified. The early ripening  and high-yielding variety of soybean SibNIIK-9 (9RS) passes the state testing since 2013. Even more earlymaturing soybean variety Krasnoobskaja (8RS) has been submitted to SVTC in 2015.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://media.wix.com/ugd/3e7d27_b3aaaad50ea1436192841e289aa4dd94.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Modern Science Success</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2412-6608</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.5/n.№5, 2015</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>