<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016P12570">
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">ПРОБЛЕМА АКТУАЛИЗАЦИИ ФАКТОРОВ УСТОЙЧИВОГО РАЗВИТИЯ СЕЛЬСКИХ ПОСЕЛЕНИЙ (ТЕОРИЯ, ПОЛИТИКА, ПРАКТИКА)</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>THE UPDATING PROBLEM OF THE FACTORS OF SUSTAINABLE DEVELOPMENT OF RURAL SETTLEMENTS (THEORY</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="">
      <dcterms:alternative>POLICY</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="">
      <dcterms:alternative>PRACTICE)</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Golubeva  T.G.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">E51</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Rural population</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6705</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>Key words: rural settlements, local self-government, sustainable development, local communities</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">В статье исследуются причины возникновения противоречий между теорией и практикой развития территории. Акцентируется внимание на взаимосвязи трех структурных элементов методологии формирования системного подхода к проблеме устойчивого развития сельских поселений: теоретического, политического, практического. В современных условиях основным актором политического регулирования
процессов социально-экономического характера на местном уровне определяются органы местного само управления сельских поселений. Их деятельность, направленная на мотивацию активности локальных сообществ позволит актуализировать не только экономические, но и институциональные и социально-политические факторы устойчивого развития сельских поселений.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The reasons of contradictions between the theory and practice of territorial development are investigated
in this article. The attention is focused on the interaction between three structural elements of the methodology
of formation of a system approach to the problem of the sustainable development of rural settlements: theoretical,
political and practical. In modern conditions, the main factor of the political regulation of the socio-economic
processes at the local level is the local self-government of rural settlements. Their functioning directed on motivation
of local communities activity will allow to actualize not only economic, but also institutional and sociopolitical
factors of sustainable development of rural settlements.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://media.wix.com/ugd/3e7d27_60fd80d1243849019f1ac86891d5fdb7.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Modern Science Success</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2412-6608</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.5/n.№3, 2015</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>