<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016P16939">
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">МАТЕМАТИЧЕСКИЙ ПОДХОД К ФОРМИРОВАНИЮ ЭФФЕКТИВНОЙ ГОСУДАРСТВЕННОЙ ПОДДЕРЖКИ ПРЕДПРИЯТИЙ СЕЛЬСКОГО ХОЗЯЙСТВА РЕГИОНА</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>MATHEMATICAL APPROACH TO FORMATION OF EFFECTIVE STATE SUPPORT OF THE ENTERPRISES OF AGRICULTURE OF THE REGION</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Bondarenko  Y.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Azarnova  T.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Kashirina  I.L.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Shchepina  I.N.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2016-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">E10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">agricultural economics</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Policies</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8672</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6062</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>Keywords: agriculture enterprise, government support, region, mathematical model</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Рассматривается проблема формирования эффективной государственной адресной поддержки администрацией региона (муниципального образования) предприятий сельского хозяйства, целью которой является достижение приемлемых значений экономических показателей деятельности предприятий и социально-экономических показателей развития муниципального образования. Предлагается алгоритм формирования эффективной государственной поддержки предприятия сельского хозяйства, позволяющий рассчитать минимально необходимый размер финансовых средств. Особенностью предлагаемого подхода является использование математической модели формирования оптимальной траектории развития предприятия сельского хозяйства, учитывающей современные условия его функционирования.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">In the following article we consider the problem of formation of an effective state targeted support of the regional (municipality) administration of agricultural enterprises, which aims to achieve reasonable economic performance of enterprises and socio-economic indicators of the municipality development. We propose an algorithm for the formation of an effective state support of agricultural enterprises, allowing to calculate the minimum required amount of targeted funds. A feature of the proposed approach is using a mathematical model of the optimal trajectory of the agricultural enterprises development, taking into account the current conditions of its
functioning.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://modernscienc-org.1gb.ru/release/USN_2016_4_2_tom.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Modern Science Success</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2412-6608</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.8/n.№4 (part 2), 2016</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>