<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="BR2016301772">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Design, installation and calibration of a weighing lysimeter for crop evapotranspiration studies</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="pt">
      <dcterms:alternative>Projeto</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="">
      <dcterms:alternative>instalação e calibração de um lisímetro de pesagem para estudos de evapotranspiração de culturas agrícolas</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Schmidt Carlos Daniel Seifert</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Pereira Francisco Adriano de Carvalho</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Oliveira Aureo Silva de</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Gomes Júnior João Fonseca</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Vellame Lucas Melo</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2013-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Lysimeters</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Nicotiana tabacum</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4486</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5177</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Lysimeters are tanks filled with soil commonly used in studies of crop ET and movement of water and
chemicals in the soil profile. The objective of this work is to describe the procedures for construction, installation
and calibration of a precision weighing lysimeter for water demand studies of Sumatra type tobacco (Nicotiana
tabacum L.) in Bahia, Brazil. The lysimeter was 1.60 m long, 1.10 m wide and 0.60 deep, with an internal soil
surface of 1.76 m2. The lysimeter was installed in an area covered by a 30% shading screen used specifically for
production of this type of tobacco. The inner box of the lysimeter was made of steel plates and the outer box
was built on site with burnt-clay bricks bonded with cement mass. The weighing platform comprised four 1,000
kg capacity load cells placed underneath the inner tank and a datalogger for data recording. The lysimeter was
calibrated in the field using standard loads of known mass. Five cycles of loading and unloading were performed
(47 points) in the range of 0 to 110 kg (62.5 mm). The system showed a strong linear relationship between standard
mass and load cells output (r2 &gt; 0.99 and Sy/x = 0.033 mm). The load cell accuracy, which combines the effects of
hysteresis, linearity and repeatability errors, was found to be of the order of ±0.06 mm and the datalogger was
found to be able to resolve mass changes less than 0.1 mm. These uncertainty parameters combined with the
ability of the lysimeter to respond to relatively small mass changes suggest that the weighing lysimeter herein
described is adequate to measure tobacco ET over time periods of one hour or longer. The investment was around
US$ 5,100.00, including hardware and field work for installation.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="pt">Lisímetros são tanques preenchidos com solo comumente utilizados em estudos de ET das culturas
e movimento da água e solutos no perfil do solo. O objetivo deste trabalho é descrever os procedimentos de
construção, instalação e calibração de um lisímetro de pesagem para estudo da demanda de água do fumo
(Nicotiana tabacum L.) tipo Sumatra, na Bahia, Brasil. O lisímetro, com área interna de 1,76 m2, tinha 1,10 m
de largura, 1,60 m de comprimento e 0,60 m de profundidade e foi instalado em área comercial de fumo coberta
com tela de sombreamento de 30%. A caixa interna era feita de chapas de aço e a caixa externa de alvenaria
construída no campo. A plataforma de pesagem continha quatro células de carga com capacidade de 1.000 kg e
um datalogger para armazenamento dos dados. O lisímetro foi calibrado no campo por meio de pesos-padrão no
intervalo de 0 a 110 kg (62,5 mm). O procedimento de calibração incluiu cinco ciclos de incremento e decremento
(47 pontos) do peso total do lisímetro. Como esperado, o sistema mostrou forte relação linear (r2 &gt; 0,99 e Sy/x =
0,033 mm) entre os pesos-padrões e o sinal das células de carga. A acurácia das células de carga, que combina
os erros de histerese, linearidade e repetibilidade, foi em torno de ±0.06 mm. A resolução do datalogger foi
inferior a 0,1 mm. Estes dados de desempenho combinados à sensibilidade do lisímetro a pequenas variações de
massa sugerem que o lisímetro de pesagem aqui descrito é adequado para medição da ET do fumo em intervalos
de tempo iguais ou superiores a uma hora. O custo total do sistema foi da ordem de US$ 5.000,00, incluindo
equipamento e mão de obra para instalação.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.ufrb.edu.br/wrim/images/wrim-2-2-2013/v02n02a02.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">en</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Water Resources and Irrigation Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2316-6886</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.2/n.2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>