<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016018300">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Soil cover of the north of central Siberia as displayed on the soil map of the Russian Federation (1988) and on sheets of the state soil map</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Почвенный покров севера Средней Сибири на почвенной карте РСФСР (1988) и на листах государственной почвенной карты</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Ananko T.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Konyushkov D.E.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">P31</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Peat soils</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">calcareous soils</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">cartography</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5648</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1194</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1344</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The Soil Map of the Russian Federation (SMRF) (1988) is the document synthesizing knowledge about Russian soils accumulated by the 1980s. The work of I.P. Gerasimov about the genetic specificity of Siberian soils was a call for discovering new regularities of the genesis and geography of soils in relation to the broadening of the actual base of soil studies. Corrections have been made for the territory of Northern Central Siberia and presented on the corresponding sheets of the State Soil Map of Russia (SSMR) on a scale of 1:1000 000. The most significant of them concern the representation of cryohydromorphic nongley soils (cryozems) as modal soils of the considered region. On the SMRF, these soils were represented by a single type of taiga high-humus nongley soils. On the SSMR, two different types of cryozems (thixotropic and homogeneous cryozems) are presented and their further subdivision with respect to the character of organic horizons, manifestation of gleyic features, possible differentiation of surface horizons, and the presence of residual carbonates. A different picture of the soil cover is shown for the territories composed of hard calcareous rocks. The area of metamorphic pale soils developing from the carbonate-free substrates has been extended. The major regularities of the soil cover patterns as displayed on the SSMR are illustrated by a schematic small-scale map. Information about ecological niches of the soils displayed on the SSMR and SMRF is presented in a tabular form.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Почвенная карта РСФСР (1988 г.) представляет собой документ, синтезировавший все накопленные к 1980-м годам сведения о почвах страны. В работах И.П. Герасимова о самобытности генетических типов почв Сибири была дана установка на поиск новых закономерностей генезиса и географии почв в связи с расширением фактической базы исследований. Корректировки и уточнения для территории севера Средней Сибири проведены при составлении и редактировании листов Государственной почвенной карты (ГПК) масштаба 1 : 1 млн. Наиболее значимые изменения касаются географии и генезиса модальных для рассматриваемого региона криогидроморфных неглеевых почв (криоземов), которые на Почвенной карте РСФСР представлены одним типом таежных высокогумусных неоглеенных почв, а на листах ГПК – двумя различными типами криоземов (криоземами гомогенными и криоземами тиксотропными) с дальнейшим подразделением по преобладающему характеру органогенных горизонтов, возможным проявлением глееватости, поверхностной дифференциации минерального профиля и содержанию остаточных карбонатов. Более дифференцированно отражен на листах ГПК почвенный покров в районах развития плотных карбонатных пород. Расширен ареал палевых почв на бескарбонатных отложениях. Основные закономерности почвенного покрова, отраженные на листах ГПК, проиллюстрированы генерализованной картосхемой. В табличной форме охарактеризованы экологические ниши почв, выделенных на Почвенной карте РСФСР и ГПК в северной части Среднесибирского плоскогорья.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">https://yadi.sk/i/EA50BTockYmRR</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Bulletin of V.V. Dokuchaev Soil Science Institute</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">0136-1694</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 81</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>