<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016017988">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Genetic reserves of increase of a protein content of cows of herd of Open Company &amp;quot;Gorshikha&amp;quot;</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Генетические резервы повышения белковомолочности коров стада ООО племзавод "Горшиха"</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Tamarova R.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Tolobova E.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Bulls</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Mothers</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">proteins</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">milk</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Casein</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en" />
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1148</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4952</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6259</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4826</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1357</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Research of genetic reserves for increase of protein content in milk of cows bred in the "Gorshikha" factory, taking the leading position for its Yaroslavl breed, was done. The data of the breeding account is used: cards of breeding of cows and bulls, results of DNA-testing of the bulls on genotypes of the kappa-casein taken from the check lists on breeding work of the Open Society "Yaroslavskoye", the appraisal data. The controlled livestock consisted of daughters of 20 bulls-fathers from the four basic lines of the Yaroslavl breed: YaYa-4370, YaYa-2456, YaYa-4574 and YaYa-4388. Methods of population genetics and the variation statistics helped to estimate indicators of dairy efficiency of daughters of bulls. Heritability of protein content from mothers was determined by the method of correlations in related pairs "mother-daughter". Parental indexes on a protein content of bulls-fathers and their realisation in offspring are calculated. Parental protein content index for all controlled livestock was 3.47% on the average, and its realisation in daughter offspring - from 95% to 110% depending on a linear belonging, compatibility of parental pairs and hereditary capacity of sires. It is found that 56.3% of bulls-fathers have the V-allele in a genotype which is a marker of the raised protein content and improved technological properties of milk, with 18% of them having the homozygous genotype ВВ. The best bulls-improvers on indicator of the protein content in milk of the daughters, which were revealed as a result of research, are recommended to use in selection for increase of protein content. They are: Arbat 190 and Nalet 1160 of Volniy YaYa-4370 line, Zapad 297, Gordiy 1157 and Zlak 221 of Murat YaYa-4388 line, Zaboy 764, Zavetniy 59 and Braslet 301 of Marta YaYa-2456 line.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Проведены исследования по оценке генетических резервов для повышения содержания белка в молоке коров, разводимых в ведущем по ярославской породе племзаводе "Горшиха". Использованы данные племенного учета: карточки племенных коров и быков, результаты ДНК-тестированния животных по генотипам каппа-казеина, взятых из каталогов быков-производителей ОАО "Ярославское" по племенной работе, данные бонитировок. Подконтрольное поголовье составляли дочери (n=201) 20 быков-отцов, относящихся к 4 основным линиям ярославской породы: Вольного ЯЯ-4370, Марта ЯЯ-2456, Жилета ЯЯ-4574 и Мурата ЯЯ-4388. Методами популяционной генетики и вариационной статистики оценены показатели молочной продуктивности дочерей быков. Наследуемость белковомолочности от матерей определяли методом корреляций в родственных парах "мать-дочь". Рассчитаны родительские индексы по белковомолочности быков-отцов и реализация их в потомстве. В среднем по всему подконтрольному поголовью родительский индекс быков по белковомолочности составил 3,47%, а его реализация в дочернем потомстве - от 95 до 110% в зависимости от линейной принадлежности, сочетаемости родительских пар и препотентности производителей. Установлено, что В-аллель, являющийся маркером повышенной белковомолочностии улучшенных технологических свойств молока, имеют в генотипе 56,3% быков-отцов, из них гомозиготный генотип ВВ - 18%. Лучшие быки-улучшатели по показателю массовой доли белка в молоке дочерей, выявленные в результате исследований, рекомендованы к использованию в селекции на повышения белковомолочности. К ним относятся: Арбат 190 и Налет 1160 линии Вольного ЯЯ-4370, Запад 297, Гордый 1157 и Злак 221 линии Мурата ЯЯ-4388, Забой 764, Заветный 59 и Браслет 301 линии Марта ЯЯ-2456.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.yaragrovuz.ru/images/Vestnik_APK/15-4/65-72_4-2015.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Herald of Agroindustrial complex of Upper Volga region</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1998-1635</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>