<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016018401">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Anti-stress activity and efficacy of pharmacologic complex SPAO to the chickens of parent flock</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Антистрессовая активность и эффективность применения фармакологического комплекса СПАО курам родительского стада</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Fisinin V.I.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Miftakhutdinov A.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Ponomarenko V.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Anosov D.E.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Chickens</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">transport of animals</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Stress</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">antioxidants</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">drug therapy</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1540</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_32612</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7452</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_511</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2394</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The anti-stress pharmacologic complex for poultry industry (SPAO) is developed. It contains lithium salt of citric acid, vitamins and other biologically active compounds. Stressrelieving activity and efficiency during preventive technology stress treatment of parent flock chicken for meat production were researched. Studies were conducted during chickens transfer from rearing flocks department to the department of adult and vaccination. It was proved that this processing method is accompanied by the launch of adaptive mechanisms a formation of the stress response. Use of SPAO-complex with water in a norm of 185 mg/kg of body weight, according to the scheme 2 days before transfer and vaccination, at the day of the procedure and every 2 days after transfer and vaccination had a great impact on the stress-relieving effect on chickens. This effect manifested at all stages of stress reaction development during short period of adaptation, the period of stress development and the phase of development of long-term adaptation. Pharmacologic stress prevention was brought three times to evaluate efficacy of SPAO-complex during parent flock chicken management: at the age of 120 days in the period of transfer and vaccination, at the age 260 days during vaccination and at the age of 290 days during the introduction of parent stock of young cocks. In comparison with the control group we had higher economic performance in the group where pharmacologic stress prevention was brought: livability is higher by 2.25%, egg production is higher by 2.11%, hatching rate is up by 4.11% mainly due to the increase of fertile eggs by 4.30%. Damage by the mortality of parent flock chicken was prevented due to use of SPAO-complex, and incremental product was got. Economic efficiencyof 1 ruble of expenses was 13.83 rubles.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Разработан антистрессовый фармакологический комплекс для промышленного птицеводства (СПАО). Он содержит лимоннокислую соль лития, витамины и др. биологически активные вещества. Изучали его антистрессовую активность и эффективность при профилактике технологических стрессов у кур родительского стада мясного направления продуктивности. Исследования проводили в период перевода кур из цеха выращивания ремонтного молодняка в цех взрослого стада и вакцинации.Доказано, что этот технологический прием сопровождается активацией адаптационных механизмов и формированием стрессовой реакции. Использование СПАО-комплекса с водой в дозе 185 мг/кг массы тела, по схеме за 2 сут. до перевода и вакцинации, в день и в течение 2 сут. после перевода и вакцинации оказало выраженное стресс-протекторное воздействие на организм кур, проявляющееся на всех стадиях развития стрессовой реакции: в период краткосрочной адаптации, в период развития стресса и фазу формирования долговременной адаптации. Для оценки эффективности СПАО-комплекса при содержании кур родительского стада фармакологическую профилактику стресса проводили трижды: в возрасте 120 сут. при переводе и вакцинации, в 260 сут. при вакцинации и в 290 сут. при спайкинге. В группе, где применяли фармакологическую профилактику стрессов, по сравнению с контрольной группой получены более высокие экономические показатели: сохранность выше на 2,25%, яйценоскость – на 2,11%, вывод цыплят – на 4,11% преимущественно за счет повышения оплодотворенности яиц на 4,30%. В результате использования СПАО-комплекса был предотвращен ущерб от падежа кур родительского стада, и получена дополнительная продукция. Экономическая эффективность на 1 руб. затрат составила 13,83 руб. Табл. 5. Библ. 11.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://avu.usaca.ru/ru/issues/90/articles/2066/pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Agrarian Bulletin of the Urals</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1997-4868</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.12</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>