<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016018255">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Influence of ultrasonic treatment on bacteria preservation during spray drying of fermented milk products</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Влияние ультразвукового воздействия на сохранность бактерий при распылительной сушке кисломолочных продуктов</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Khmelev V.N.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Shalunov A.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Golykh R.N.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Nesterov V.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Dorovskikh R.S.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Skiba E.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Shavyrkina N.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">Q02</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">cultured milk</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Ultrasonics</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">ultrasonic treatment</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">drying</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">spray drying</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en" />
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Bifidobacterium</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2023</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8044</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_28598</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2402</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_24088</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_23898</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">High demand for dry fermented milk products (FMP) determines the relevance of the modernization of drying methods. The existing designs of spray dryers are not suitable for drying of FMP because of strict limitations on allowable product temperature (commonly 40–45 deg. C) enabling to preserve the viability of microorganisms. The considered alternative approach to the implementation of a low-temperature spray drying of FMP is characterized by the use of ultrasonic treatment for spraying of raw materials and the interaction between the droplets formed by spraying and the stream of drying agent (air). Ultrasonic spraying of raw materials makes it possible to form an almost monodispersed spray jet (with an average droplet diameter equal to 31 μm), which prevents the entrainment of the product due to the absence of fine fraction and increases the productivity of the process at low temperatures. In turn, the application of ultrasonic vibrations at the stage of interaction between droplets and air intensifies the process of moisture evaporation (by increasing the diffusion coefficient), which makes it possible to reduce the drying temperature to a value not affecting the survival of the bacteria. A result of experiments have shown that ultrasonic exposure at both stages of spray drying of FMP, does not ensure the survival of useful microorganisms (lactic acid bacteria and bifidobacteria). Ultrasonic spraying of raw materials in the drying chamber reduces the number of bacteria by more than 10 times comparing with pneumatic spraying because of cavitation. Ultrasonic vibration exposure during evaporation of moisture from the droplets formed by spraying reduces the number of bacteria up to 180 times. The results obtained showed that ultrasonic treatment is not applicable to the spray drying of FMP, but it may be recommended for the drying of thermolabile plant extracts and medicines to remove contaminating microorganisms.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Высокая востребованность сухих кисломолочных продуктов (КМП) определяет актуальность модернизации способов сушки. Существующие конструкции распылительных сушилок не пригодны для сушки КМП из-за жестких ограничений по допустимой температуре КМП (как правило, не более 40…45 град. C), позволяющей сохранить жизнеспособность микроорганизмов. Рассмотрен альтернативный подход к реализации низкотемпературной распылительной сушки КМП, который заключается в применении ультразвукового (УЗ) воздействия для распыления сырья, а также при взаимодействии сформированных распылением капель с потоком сушильного агента (воздуха). УЗ распыление сырья позволяет сформировать факел распыла, близкий к монодисперсному (со средним диаметром капель, равным 31 мкм), что исключает унос продукта благодаря отсутствию мелкой фракции и повышает производительность процесса при низких температурах. Применение УЗ на стадии взаимодействия капель с воздухом интенсифицирует процесс испарения влаги (за счет увеличения коэффициента диффузии), что дает возможность снизить температуру сушки до величины, не влияющей на выживаемость бактерий. В результате проведения экспериментальных исследований показано, что УЗ воздействие при распылительной сушке КМП на обеих стадиях процесса не обеспечивает выживаемость полезных микроорганизмов (молочнокислых и бифидобактерий). УЗ распыление сырья в сушильную камеру приводит к сокращению численности бактерий более чем в 10 раз (по сравнению с пневматическим распылением) из-за кавитационных явлений. Воздействие УЗ колебаниями при испарении влаги с поверхности капель, сформированных распылением, сокращает численность бактерий до 180 раз. Согласно полученным результатам УЗ воздействие не может применяться для распылительной сушки КМП, но может быть рекомендовано для сушки термолабильных растительных экстрактов и лекарственных препаратов с целью удаления контаминирующих микроорганизмов.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://fptt-journal.ru/stories/archive/39/18.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Food Processing: Techniques and Technology</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2074-9414</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>