<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016018021">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Simulation of dynamic management of water distribution at canals of open irrigation net</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Моделирование динамического управления водораспределением на каналах открытой оросительной сети</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Shchedrin V.N.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Churayev А.А.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Shkolnaya V. М.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Yuchenko L.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F06</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Crops</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">irrigation systems</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">management</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">models</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1972</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_25332</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_16086</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4881</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The objective of the research is to develop a simulation model for dynamic management of water distribution at canals of open irrigation net. To achieve the objective, hydrometric “velocity – area” method for discharge characteristics of net hydraulic facilities and method for math simulation of technological processes were used. During the investigation an algorithm for creating math model was developed. The algorithm includes 8 main steps: 1) construction of plan layout of irrigation net</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">2) plotting of longitudinal and cross-sectional profiles of irrigation net canals</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">3) splitting of canal longitudinal profiles into calculated sections of water control</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">4) determination of coefficient of efficiency of irrigation net canals</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">5) determination of the values of discharges, depths, and mean velocities of water movement on calculated sites</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">6) determination of duration for readjustment of depths at the boundaries of calculated irrigation net sections</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">7) construction of theoretical and experimental relationships of duration for readjustment on calculated sections</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">8) conducting scenario studies for the model of dynamic management of water distribution processes to optimize the use of irrigation water. Theoretical and experimental relationships for velocity of flow on the depth of canal calculated sections, as well as total duration of readjustment of the depths of calculated sections were obtained. Maximal values of asymmetry parameter and variation coefficient and experiment data were CS = 1.86 (CS less than 5), Cv = 0.15 (Cv less than 3) respectively. As a result of the research, simulation model of water distribution was developed. The model enables to determine total discharge in the head of a canal, actual volume of water supply, time for providing discharges for water outlets and the quantity of simultaneously working pumping units for required discharges.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">Целью исследований являлось построение имитационной модели динамического управления водораспределением на каналах открытой оросительной сети. Для достижения поставленной цели был использован гидрометрический метод получения расходных характеристик сетевых гидротехнических сооружений "скорость – площадь" и метод математического имитационного моделирования технологических процессов. В процессе исследований был разработан алгоритм создания имитационной математической модели, включающий 8 основных этапов: 1) построение плановой схемы оросительной сети</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">2) построение продольных профилей и поперечных сечений каналов оросительной сети</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">3) разбивка продольных профилей канала на расчетные участки водорегулирования</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">4) определение КПД каналов оросительной сети</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">5) определение значений расходов, глубин и средних скоростей движения воды по расчетным участкам</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">6) определение продолжительности перерегулировки глубин на границах расчетных участков каналов сети</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">7) построение теоретических и экспериментальных зависимостей продолжительности перерегулировки по расчетным участкам</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">8) проведение сценарных исследований применения модели динамического управления процессами водораспределения при реализации цели оптимизации использования оросительной воды. Получены теоретические и экспериментальные зависимости скорости течения от глубины наполнения расчетных участков канала, а также суммарной продолжительности перерегулировки глубин на расчетных участках. Максимальные значения коэффициентов асимметрии и вариации теоретических и опытных данных составляют соответственно CS = 1,86 (CS &lt; 5), Cv = 0,15 (Cv &lt; 3). В результате исследований была построена имитационная модель водораспределения, которая позволяет определить суммарный головной расход в голове канала, фактический объем водоподачи, время обеспечения расходами водовыделов и количество одновременно работающих насосных агрегатов для обеспечения необходимых расходов.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.rosniipm-sm.ru/dl_files/udb_files/udb13-rec367-field6.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Scientific Journal of Russian Research Institute of Land Improvement Problems</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2222-1816</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>