<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016017053">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Soil and soil cover changes in spruce forests after final logging</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Изменение почв и почвенного покрова еловых лесов после сплошнолесосечных рубок</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Lapteva E.M.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Vtyurin G.M.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Bobkova K.S.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Kaverin D.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Dymov A.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Simonov G.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">P33</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Boreal forests</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">podzols</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1014</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6044</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The research was conducted in the Komi Republic. Mature bilberry spruce forest was used as the control plot, young leaf and spruce forest as well middle-aged birch forest rich in herbs that were formed after clear-cuttings in winters 2001/2002 and 1969/1970, respectively, as experimental ones. Soil cover transformation and changes of morphological and chemical properties of Albeluvisols at clear-cuttings of middle taiga spruce forests were studied. The observed changes in structure and properties of podzolic texturally-differentiated soils at cuttings of spruce forests in the middle taiga subzone do not cause their transition to any other soil type. Soil cover of secondary deciduous-coniferous forests which replace cut forests are characterized with a varied soil contour and a combination of the main type of podzolic soils under undisturbed spruce forests. The increased surface hydromorphism at cut areas causes formation of complicated sub-types of podzolic texturally differentiated soils (podzolic surface-gley soils with microprofile of podzol) and enlarges their ratio (up to 35-38%) in soil cover structure. Temporary soil over-moisturing at the initial (5-10 years) stage of after-cutting self-restoring vegetation succession provides for soil gleyzation, improves yield and segregation of iron compounds, increases the migratory activity of humic substances. Low content and resources of total nitrogen in forest litters mark anthropogenic transformation processes of podzolic soils at this stage. Later (in 30-40 years after logging), soils at cut areas still retain signs of hydromorphism. Forest litters are denser, less acid and thick with a low weight ratio of organic carbon as compared with Albeluvisols of undisturbed spruce forest. The upper mineral soil horizons under secondary deciduous-coniferous forests contain larger amounts of total iron, its mobile (oxalate-dissolvable) components, and Fe-Mn-concretions.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Исследование проводили в Республике Коми. Изучали подзолистые суглинистые почвы спелого ельника черничного (контроль) и производных фитоценозов – лиственно-елового молодняка и средневозрастного березняка разнотравного, сформировавшихся после сплошнолесосечных рубок, проведенных зимой 2001/2002 и 1969/1970 гг. соответственно. Показано, что в биоклиматических условиях средней тайги вырубка ельников черничных, занимающих относительно дренированные территории, приводит к временному поверхностному переувлажнению подзолистых текстурно-дифференцированных почв (ПТДП). Почвенный покров производных лиственно-хвойных насаждений, формирующихся на вырубленных участках, характеризуется мелкоконтурностью и сочетанием основных подтипов подзолистых почв, характерных для ненарушенных еловых лесов. Усиление поверхностного гидроморфизма на вырубках обусловливает формирование сложных подтипов ПТДП (подзолистых поверхностно-глееватых с микропрофилем подзола) и возрастание их доли (до 35-38%) в структуре почвенного покрова. Временное переувлажнение почв на первых стадиях (5-10 лет) после самовосстановительной сукцессии растительности обусловливает поверхностное оглеение почв, активизацию выноса и сегрегации соединений железа, возрастание миграционной активности гумусовых веществ, уменьшение содержания и запасов общего азота в органогенных горизонтах На поздних стадиях (30-40 лет) восстановления благодаря смене древесных пород в ПТДП сохраняется остаточное переувлажнение, отмечается возрастание плотности лесных подстилок, снижение в них кислотности, мощности и массовой доли органического углерода по сравнению с почвами коренного насаждения. В верхних минеральных горизонтах почв производных насаждений, различных стадий сукцессии, отмечено возрастание по сравнению с контрольными почвами содержания валовых форм соединений железа, его подвижных (оксалатрастворимых) компонентов, Fe-Mn конкреций.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://goo.gl/GPbmAs</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Siberian Journal of Forest Science</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2311-1410</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 5</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>