<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016017956">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Sowing period influence on the spring triticale’ s developmental growth in the southern climates of the Amur region</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Влияние сроков посева на рост и развитие ярового тритикале в условиях южной зоны Амурской области</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Tikhonchuk P.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Muratov A.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Kravchuk O.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2016-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F62</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Triticosecale</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">crop yield</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">plasticity</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">STABILITY</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33914</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_10176</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_28498</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_36930</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Spring triticale’s developmental growth and crop yield progress specifics were studied depending on sowing period. Experiments were conducted in 2014-2015 in Amur region. The 1st one was favorable in weather conditions, the 2nd one – droughty. Three varieties (Yarilo, Ukro, Carmen) and 4 sowing periods were compared. Field germination and survival rate, interphase periods’ duration, plant height and crop yield were determined. Optimal soil temperature for crop development (12-16 deg C) was registered in all research years during sowing on April 29. Sowing into warmer soil naturally resulted in field germination rate enhancement. The longest (16-18 days) “sowing-shoots” period was with the earliest sowing periods (April 15 and 22). During “stooling - leaf-tube formation” phase it was registered that there is tendency to increasing in period duration from early to late sowing period, from 12 to 26 days respectively. Inverse relation was registered during next periods. On the whole the longest vegetation period (94-97 days) has been registered in the early sowing period (April 15), the shortest (81-82 days) – when sowing on May 5. The maximal crop yield has been gained with the varieties of Ukro and Yarilo when sowing in early April periods (2.43 and 2.12 t/hectare on average for 2 years respectively). Quite lower crop yield (1.76 t/ha) has been registered only in late sowing period (May 5). It is connected with the reduction of vegetation period. When sowing on April 15, 22, 29 the crop yield has been almost at the same level, within 2.13–2.17 t/ha. The maximal crop yield on average for 2 years (2.49 t/ha) has been gained with the variety of Ukro when sowing on April 29. This variety in general differed in high productivity regardless of sowing date (2.38 t/ha against 1.18 and 1.95 in other varieties on average for 4 terms and 2 years). The recommendation is to sow spring triticale from the middle till the end of April in the southern zone of the Amur Region.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Изучали особенности роста, развития и формирования урожайности зерна ярового тритикале в зависимости от сроков посева. Опыты проводили в Амурской обл. в 2014 и 2015 гг., первый из которых оказался благоприятным по погодным условиям, второй – засушливым. Сравнивали 3 сорта (Ярило, Укро, Кармен) и 4 срока посева. Определяли полевую всхожесть и выживаемость, продолжительность межфазных периодов, высоту растений, урожайность зерна. Оптимальная для развития культуры температура почвы (12-16 град. С) во все годы исследований наблюдалась при посеве 29 апреля. Посев в более прогретую почву закономерно сопровождался повышением полевой всхожести. Наиболее продолжительным (16-18 дней) период "посев – всходы" был при самых ранних сроках посева (15 и 22 апреля). В фазу "кущение – выход в трубку" отмечали тенденцию к увеличению продолжительности периода от раннего к позднему сроку посева соответственно от 12 до 26 дней. Обратная зависимость наблюдалась при прохождении последующих периодов. В целом наибольший вегетационный период (94-97 дней) наблюдался при раннем сроке посева (15 апреля), наименьший (81-82 дня) - при посеве 5 мая. Наибольшая урожайность была получена при посеве в ранние апрельские сроки у сортов Укро и Ярило (2,43 и 2,12 т/га в среднем за 2 года соответственно). Существенно более низкая урожайность (1,76 т/га) наблюдалась лишь при позднем сроке посева (5 мая), что связано с сокращением вегетационного периода. При посевах 15, 22, 29 апреля урожайность была примерно на одном уровне, в пределах 2,13-2,17 т/га. Максимальная урожайность зерна в среднем за 2 года (2,49 т/га) получена при посеве 29 апреля у сорта Укро. Этот сорт в целом отличался высокой урожайностью вне зависимости от сроков посева (в среднем по 4 срокам и 2 годам 2,38 т/га против 1,18 и 1,95 у других сортов). Рекомендуем посев ярового тритикале в южной зоне Амурской области проводить с середины до конца апреля.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik.dalgau.ru/images/gurnal/vipusk_2016/nomer_1/Tikhonchuk.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Far Eastern Agrarian Herald</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1999-6837</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>