<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016017186">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Analysis of scenarios for agricultural sector development in the Plegolya catchment as a determining factor of nutrient load</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Анализ сценариев развития агропромышленного сектора в водосборном бассейне реки Преголи как определяющего фактора биогенной нагрузки</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Gorbunova Yu.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Domnin D.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Chubarenko B.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">E21</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">runoff</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en" />
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">watersheds</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Rivers</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Baltic Sea</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_35388</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8334</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6617</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_800</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Intensity of the biogenic load from the catchment area of the Pregolya River and its possible changes greatly depend on the socio-economic development scenarios of the region. A comparative assessment and analysis of the current agricultural status of the Pregolya catchment area in the Kaliningrad region of the Russian Federation and the Warmian-Masurian Voivodeship of the Republic of Poland have been performed. Prospects for long-term development in accordance with the existing documents on strategic planning of these countries have been reviewed. Transboundary catchment position causes a diverse socio-economic situation in its different parts as the two countries have developed different systems of management and decision-making. The area actually used for plowing in Warmian-Masurian Voivodeship is 3 times bigger than in the Kaliningrad region (where less than 50% of available land is used). Indicators of animal breeding development are also higher there, for example, the number of cattle is 7 times bigger. Further socio-economic development of Warmian-Masurian Voivodeship and environmental measures (including nutrients runoff prevention) depends on the implementation of the European Union program "Development of Eastern Poland in 2014-2020". However, it does not presuppose a significant increase in agricultural production. Analysis of the "The long-term strategy of socio-economic development of the Kaliningrad region" suggests increase of arable lands of 70%, cattle stock of 3,5 times, the main crops yields of more than two times. In the case of the implementation of these plans biogenic load from the catchment area will significantly increase – both diffused one from croplands, pastures and from point sources, namely livestock breeding farms.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Интенсивность биогенной нагрузки с водосбора р. Преголи и ее возможные изменения существенно зависят от сценариев социально-экономического развития региона. Проведены сравнительная оценка и анализ существующей в водосборном бассейне р. Преголи ситуации в агропромышленном секторе (на территориях Калининградской области Российской Федерации и Варминьско-Мазурского воеводства Республики Польши), а также перспектив долгосрочного развития этого сектора в соответствии с имеющимися документами по стратегическому планированию стран. Трансграничное положение водосбора обуславливает разнородную социально-экономическую ситуацию в его национальных частях, так как на территории двух стран сложились разные системы хозяйствования и принятия управленческих решений. В Варминьско-Мазурском воеводстве площади, фактически используемые под пашни, в 3 раза больше, чем в Калининградской области, где задействовано менее 50% имеющихся угодий. Показатели развития животноводства там также выше, например, количество голов крупного рогатого скота там больше более чем в 7 раз. Дальнейшее социально-экономическое развитие Варминьско-Мазурского воеводства и проведение природоохранных мероприятий (в том числе по предотвращению стока биогенов) зависят от реализации программы Европейского союза "Развитие Восточной Польши в период 2014-2020 гг. ", но существенного увеличения с.-х. производства в ней не предвидится. Для Калининградской области "Стратегия социально-экономического развития Калининградской области на долгосрочную перспективу" предполагает к 2020 г. увеличение площади пашен на 70%, поголовья крупного рогатого скота в 3,5 раза, повышение урожайности основных с.-х. культур более чем в 2 раза. В случае реализации этих планов существенно возрастет биогенная нагрузка с водосборного бассейна, как распределенная – с пахотных угодий, пастбищ, так и от точечных источников с животноводческих комплексов.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.klgtu.ru/science/magazine/news_kstu/2015_39/gorbunova.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>KSTU News</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1997-3071</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 39</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>