<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016017687">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">The evaluation of genealogical lines of Hereford cattle at various stages of selective breeding</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Оценка генеалогических линий крупного рогатого скота герефордской породы на разных этапах селекции</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Durov A.S.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Cows</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Cattle</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Breeds (animals)</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">animal breeding</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">breeding lines</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">live weight</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">milk performance</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1939</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1391</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_423</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_29226</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_37247</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_24276</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The Hereford breed plays an important role in cattle breeding in Russia. Over a period of more than 50 years the Siberian scientists jointly with the specialists of farming enterprises have achieved several selection inventions including the following: three breeding farm’s lines of Maer Verne 88480, Shalun D-50, and Yarlyk 413, breeding farm’s types “Sonskiy” and “Sadovskiy”. The study was conducted in the Novosibirsk region at the Breeding Farm “Sadovskiy” in 2001 during the preparation for the testing of the “Sadovskiy” type. To compare with the stage of work for forming the breeding farm’s type “Sonskiy” the data from B.O. Inerbaev’s thesis published in 1989 were used. . The data on the productive and exterior features of the cows at the age of the 3rd calving and older were used for data processing. The analysis for each index was conducted to determine the reliability of the difference between the compared groups. The breeding farm’s line of Maer Verne 88480 qualifies for the Class II (516-512 kg) in terms of live weight and to the breed standard (210-209 kg) in terms of milk production. The cows of the Shalun D-50 line qualify for the live weight Class II (508-503 kg) and the breed standard of milk production (213-208 kg). The family group of Baron 3344 qualifies for the live weight Class II (525-516 kg) and to the breed standard in milk production (209-206 kg). The live weight of the cows of the family group of Klen 70272 qualifies for Class II (508-501 kg) and the milk production to the breed standard (224-205 kg). The study of the trends in the main lines and related groups of Hereford breed shows the transition from an extended conformation type to a tall type. This may be explained by the effect of the environment in which the “Sadovskiy” type is bred. This also may be explained by the fact that the Hereford population of the Breeding Farm “Sadovskiy” was created by accumulation cross breeding of Simmental cows by Hereford bulls to the IV-V generations.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Герефордская порода играет важную роль в скотоводстве России. За период более чем 50 лет учёными Сибири совместно со специалистами АПК создано несколько селекционных достижений, включающих в себя 3 заводские линии: Маер-Верна 88480, Шалуна Д-50, Ярлыка 413, заводской тип "Сонский" и тип "Садовский". Исследования проведены в Новосибирской обл. на племзаводе "Садовское" в 2001 г. в период активной работы по подготовке к апробации типа "Садовский"., Для сравнения с этапом работы по формированию заводского типа "Сонский" использованы данные Б.О. Инербаева, опубликованные в 1989 г. Для обработки использованы данные по продуктивным и экстерьерным признакам коров в возрасте III отёла и старше. Для каждого показателя проведён анализ с определением достоверности разницы между сравниваемыми группами. Заводская линия Маер-Верна 88480 по живой массе соответствует требованиям II класса (516-512 кг), а по молочности – стандарту породы (210-209 кг). Представительницы линии Шалуна Д-50 соответствуют требованиям II класса по живой массе (508-503 кг) и стандарту породы по молочности (213-208 кг). Родственная группа Барона 3344 имеет живую массу на уровне требований II класса (525-516 кг), а молочность – стандарту породы (209-206 кг). Живая масса коров родственной группы Клёна 70272 соответствует требованиям II класса (508-501 кг), молочность – стандарту породы (224-205 кг). Анализ тенденции в изменении параметров основных линий и родственных групп герефордской породы показывает переход от растянутого типа телосложения к высокорослому. Данный факт можно объяснить влиянием среды, в которой разводят животных типа "Садовский". Также нельзя исключить влияния того, что популяция герефордской породы племенного завода "Садовский" была создана путём поглотительного скрещивания симменталов герефордскими быками до IV-V поколений.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.asau.ru/files/vestnik/2015/12/093-097.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Bulletin of Altai State Agricultural University</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1996-4277</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 12</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>