<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016017743">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Sowing qualities and yielding properties of sudan grass depending on fractionation of seeds</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Посевные качества и урожайные свойства суданской травы в зависимости от фракционирования семян</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Kryukova T.I.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Goleva G.G.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Borovkova A.N.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Crops</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">varieties</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">separating</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Density</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Seeds</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">germinability</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">crop yield</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1972</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8157</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6973</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2186</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6946</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3246</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_10176</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The object of this study was the Voronezhskaya 24 Sudan grass cultivar area-specific to the Central Chernozem Region. The purpose was to find out the influence of fractioning seeds on the sowing qualities and yielding properties of herbage of Sudan grass. The experiments were conducted in the Voronezh region in 2012-2014. The seeds were separated into 5 fractions using an aerodynamic separator. Extreme fractions were thrown off. The seeds of the remained 3 fractions were compared with each other and with non-fractioned seeds. Weight per 1000 grains and seed germination rate were determined by conventional methods. Laboratory germination rate was determined in a roll and in sand. Field experiments were undertaken in plots with the accounting area of 4 m2 in 4 replications. Sowing was carried out with selective planter at the rate of 2 million viable seeds per hectare. The space between rows was 15 cm. Harvesting herbage was performed manually and accounted by weighing. There has been identified the dependence of the amount of Sudan grass herbage yield on a seed fraction. In years with different weather conditions better germination was observed in the 3-fraction seeds, that is, medium size - 92.2%, against 85.7% in control. Plants grown from these seeds showed maximum level of productivity of feed mass which in the amount of two cuttings was equal to 405 dt/ha (in control – 360 dt/ha). The lowest level of productivity was obtained from the seeds of the 4-th fraction (relative to the light weighed fraction – 298 dt/ha. It has been found that with the help of a separator it is possible to select biologically valuable seeds of Sudan grass formed in the middle part of the panicle, to remove lightweight impurity, to improve the quality of seeds and to significantly increase the average yield of herbage by 13%.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Объектом исследования являлись семена суданской травы сорта Воронежская 24, районированного по Центрально-Черноземной зоне РФ. Цель – установить влияние фракционирования семян на посевные качества и урожайные свойства зеленой массы суданской травы. Опыты проводили в Воронежской обл. в 2012-2014 гг. Семена разделяли на 5 фракций с использованием сепаратора аэродинамического. Крайние фракции отбрасывали. Семена оставшихся 3 фракций сравнивали между собой и с нефракционированными семенами. Массу 1000 зерен и всхожесть семян определяли по стандартным методикам. Лабораторную всхожесть определяли в рулоне и песке. Полевые опыты закладывали на делянках с учетной площадью 4 м2 в 4-кратной повторности. Посев осуществляли селекционной сеялкой с нормой высева 2 млн. всхожих семян/га. Ширина междурядий составляла 15 см. Уборку зеленой массы проводили вручную, урожайность учитывали путем взвешивания. Выявлена зависимость величины урожая зеленой массы суданской травы от фракции семян. В годы с различными погодными условиями лучшей всхожестью обладали семена 3-й фракции, т.е. средние по размеру - 92,2%, против 85,7% в контроле. У растений, полученных из этих семян, отмечен наибольший уровень урожайности кормовой массы, которая в сумме за 2 укоса составила 405 ц/га (на контроле – 360 ц/га). Низкими урожайными свойствами обладали семена 4-й (относительно легковесной) фракции – 298 ц/га. Установлено, что с помощью сепаратора можно отобрать биологически ценные семена суданской травы, сформированные в средней части метелки, удалить легковесную примесь, существенно повысить качество посевного материала и, как следствие, повысить урожайность зеленой массы (в среднем на 13%).</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://vestnik.vsau.ru/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/22-26.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Voronezh State Agrarian University</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2071-2243</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>