<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016018205">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">The reflection of the solar radiation range in ecosystems on the data of remote sensing of the Earth</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Отражение спектра солнечной радиации в экосистемах по материалам дистанционного зондирования Земли</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Berezin L.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">P05</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">land cover</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">soil</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Remote sensing</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Multispectral imagery</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">solar radiation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_37897</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7156</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6498</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_36765</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_14415</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Agricultural lands soil and agrochemical inspection technique in plain regions without relief digital model creation was improved. The technique is based on the differentiated study of influence of shooting ranges by the complicated cluster analysis of light reflection of ecosystems. The possibility of color channels variation in RGB system for the separate consideration of absorption of solar radiation by the soil and vegetable cover has been taken into account. Light reflection of agrocoenosis in the period of soil resting and the subsequent cultivation of spring-sown soft wheat while its blossoming on the fallow lands was studied according to the pictures of high resolution (5 m per pixel) made by the RapidEye spacecraft (Germany). The research was conducted in the forest-steppe zone of the Ishim-Irtysh interstream area of Western Siberia in 2011-2014. While synthesizing the pictures received in the different ranges of frequencies the priority of near infrared range of a range of solar radiation reflection (0.845-0.885 microns) which brings more part of energy in comparison with short-wave visible part of a range is offered. In the article the offer to calculate the absorption amount of solar radiation by ecosystems using the comparison of the greatest possible size of radiation arriving at the Earth surface to its reflection by this or that ecosystems or its components is proved for the first time. Each component absorbs selectively the part of solar energy for biomass formation or for accumulation of humus and other soil processes. Information of space pictures on soil condition differs from the aerial photographs which are the basis for a traditional technique of soil mapping. The latter isn’t determined by an open field surface which absorbs more than 90% of the coming radiation, but according to the spectral analysis of the reflected part of an agrocenosis of field cultures prevailing in the region, or biogeocenosis of typical natural ecosystems.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Усовершенствован способ почвенно-агрохимического обследования земель сельскохозяйственного назначения в равнинных регионах без построения цифровой модели рельефа. Способ основан на дифференцированном изучении влияния диапазонов съемки путем усложненного кластерного анализа светоотражения экосистем. Учитывалась возможность варьирования цветовыми каналами в системе RGB для раздельного учета поглощения солнечной радиации почвенным и растительным покровом. По космическим снимкам высокого разрешения (5 м на пиксель) космического аппарата RapidEye изучалось светоотражение агроценозов в период парования поля и последующего возделывания на нем яровой мягкой пшеницы в фазе ее цветения, а также на залежных землях, намечаемых к повторному освоению, в лесостепной зоне Ишим-Иртышского междуречья Западной Сибири в 2011-2014 гг. На этапе синтезирования снимков, полученных в разных диапазонах частот, предлагается приоритет ближнего инфракрасного диапазона спектра отражения солнечной радиации (0,845-0,885 мкм), который несет относительно большую часть энергии по сравнению с коротковолновой видимой частью спектра. Впервые обосновывается предложение рассчитывать величину поглощения экосистемами солнечной радиации сопоставлением максимально возможной величины радиации, поступающей на поверхность Земли, с ее отражением той или иной экосистемой или ее компонентами. Каждый из них избирательно поглощает свою долю солнечной энергии на формирование биомассы либо на накопление гумуса и другие почвенные процессы. Информация космических снимков о состоянии почвенного покрова отличается от информации аэрофотоснимков, положенных в основу традиционной методики почвенного картирования тем, что она определяется не по открытой поверхности поля, которая поглощает более 90% приходящей радиации, а по спектральному анализу отраженной её части агроценозами преобладающих в регионе полевых культур, либо биогеоценозами типичных природных экосистем.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik.omgau.ru/wp-content/files/20_5.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Bulletin of Omsk State Agrarian University</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2222-0364</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>