<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016018223">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">The use of ultasonic exposure as the factor of intensification of dispersion process in food production</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Использование ультразвукового воздействия как фактора интенсификации процесса диспергирования в пищевых производствах</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Fatkullin R.I.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Popova N.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">Q02</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">foods</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">ultrasonic treatment</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">intensification</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">food production</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3032</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_28598</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33485</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3025</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The possibility of using the cavitational ultrasonic exposure (USE) for intensification of the dispersion process when producing drinks was studied. During the study a mode of USE was chosen (power 180 W, duration 5 min, frequency (22+-1.65) kHz). The list of the research subjects includes 3 samples of cranberry water obtained with the help of traditional (control sample - CS) and innovative technologies (S1 and S2). S1 was subjected to USE only at the extraction stage, and S2 – also while disinfecting the finished drink (power - 240 W, duration - 3 min.). As a result of using USE the volume concentration of sediment (16.7 and 25% for S1 and S2, respectively) has increased, which may be connected with intensification of the extraction process. The disperse composition of fruit drink is changed. The presence of disperse particles which size of 5670 nm is typical for the CS. There are particles within the range of 743–5200 nm in S1. Although, the particles which size is 5200 or 1960 nm prevail. Particle sizes in S2 are within 236.8–5830 nanometers, with prevalence of particles which size is 1059 and 5830. By the organoleptic indicators the CS has got 90.4% of possible points, S1 – 94.4%, S2 – 97.0%. The conclusion about the reasonability of using cavitational USE for intensification of the dispersion and extraction process in the technology of fruit drink production was done.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Изучали возможность использования кавитационного ультразвукового воздействия (УЗВ) для интенсификации процесса диспергирования при производстве напитков. В рамках исследования был установлен режим УЗВ (мощность 180 Вт, продолжительность воздействия 5 мин, частота (22 ± 1,65) кГц) и сформирован перечень объектов исследований, включающий 3 образца клюквенного морса, полученных по традиционной (контрольный образец - КО) и модифицированным технологиям (О1 и О2). О1 подвергали УЗВ только на этапе экстракции, а О2 – еще и при обеззараживании готового напитка (мощность 240 Вт, продолжительность 3 мин). В результате использования УЗВ увеличилась объемная доля осадка (16,7 и 25% для О1 и О2 соответственно), что может быть связано с интенсификацией процесса экстракции. Изменяется и дисперсный состав морса. Для КО характерно присутствие дисперсных частиц, размер которых составляет 5670 нм. В О1 присутствуют частицы в диапазоне 743–5200 нм, с преобладанием частиц размером 5200 и 1960 нм, в О2 - 236,8–5830 нм, с преобладанием частиц размером 1059 и 5830. По совокупности органолептических показателей КО получил 90,4% возможных баллов, О1 – 94,4%, О2 – 97,0%. Сделан вывод о целесообразности применения кавитационного УЗВ для интенсификации процесса диспергирования и экстракции в технологии производства морсов.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://vestnik.susu.ru/food/article/view/4458/3970</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Bulletin of South Ural State University</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2310-2748</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>