<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016017695">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Lowering barriers of the access to involving agricultural lands for building</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Снижение барьеров доступа к вовлечению сельскохозяйственных угодий под застройку</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Shagaida N.I.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">E11</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">farmland</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Construction</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Zoning</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">land use</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">delinquent behaviour</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Regulations</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2808</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_35060</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_36936</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4182</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_28663</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6493</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Today there is increased competition at the market of agricultural lands between agricultural producers and developers. The state does not demonstrate the readiness of regulating that conflict, adopting variously directed juridical norms. To the State Duma of the RF repeatedly introduced are the projects of the law, which abolishes the main protective mechanism - category of “agricultural purpose land” in the absence of agricultural zones, regulations of plots using, lists of valuable agricultural lands and concept how all these must be determined in theory and in practice. Using the world experience, it is suggested to extend the zone of agricultural purpose to plots, which fall into the category of agricultural purpose lands , to elaborate the classifier of kinds of permitted using the plots on the basis of All-Russian Classifier of Economic Activity Types, to adopt the rules of elaborating regulations for the plot, on their basis there must be established regulations of using each plot, including its possible or impossible exclusion from agricultural zone, to adopt the principle of excluding valuable and especially valuable plots from agricultural purpose lands: valuable ones - systematically covered with sowing, as well as uncovered ones, which can be referred to in natural characteristics to productive and high productive ones, especially valuable ones - covered with special kinds of plants (citrus fruits, tea etc), using especially valuable plots for non-agricultural purposes must be forbidden, the valuable ones - limited, for special cases (development of populated areas) there can be applied a mechanism for removal of valuable lands for state and municipal needs. Those and other mechanisms must be reflected in the law, in order to be possible for discussing.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Сегодня усиливается конкуренция на рынке с.-х. угодий между сельхозпроизводителями и девелоперами. Государство не демонстрирует готовность урегулировать этот конфликт, принимая разнонаправленные юридические нормы. В Государственную думу РФ неоднократно вносятся проекты закона, который отменяет основной защитный механизм - категорию "земли с.-х. назначения" при отсутствии с.-х. зон, регламентов использования участков, перечней ценных с.-х. земель и понятия, как это все должно определяться в теории и на практике. Используя мировой опыт, предлагается распространить зону с.-х. назначения на участки, входящие в категорию земель с.-х. назначения, разработать классификатор видов разрешенного использования участков на основе Общероссийского классификатора видов экономической деятельности, принять правила разработки регламентов на участок, на их основе должен устанавливаться регламент использования каждого участка, включая возможность или невозможность его исключения из сельхоззоны, принять принцип выделения ценных и особо ценных участков из земель с.-х. назначения: ценные - систематически занимаемые посевами, а также незанятые, которые по природным характеристикам можно отнести к продуктивным и высокопродуктивным, особо ценные - занятые особыми видами растений (цитрусовыми, чаем и т.д.), использование особо ценных участков для несельскохозяйственных целей должно быть запрещено, ценных - ограничено, для особых случаев (развитие населенных пунктов), может применяться механизм изъятия ценных земель для государственных и муниципальных нужд. Эти и другие механизмы должны быть отражены в законе, чтобы их можно было обсуждать.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vniiesh.ru/documents/document_20705_Shagaida.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Agribusiness Sector: Economics, Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">0235-2443</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 11</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>