<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016018308">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">The peculiarities of the dynamics of copper compounds in the agrocenosis on soddy-podzolic soils under a long-term application of fertilizers</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Особенности динамики соединений меди в агроценозах на дерново-подзолистых почвах при длительном применении удобрений</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Mineev V.G.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Edemskaya N.L.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F04</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Crops</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Copper</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en" />
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">fertilizers</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">liming</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">field experimentation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1972</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1868</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2867c82c5e5a</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_25206</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33990</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The authors studied copper dynamics in a soil-plant-fertilizers system within long-term stationary field experiments in Moscow region established in 1937, 1969, 1933 and 1950 in grain-forage and forage rotations. The soils in the experiments were sand-loam, silty-loam and clay-loam soddy-podzolic soils. Depending on experimental variants mineral fertilizers were used at the rates of 0–60 kg per ha annually and organic fertilizers and lime materials at the rates equivalent to hydrolytic acidity (HA). The soil profile and plant samples taken in 1989-2004 were investigated for the following indices: total copper content, mobile forms (extracted by ammonium-acetate buffer (AAB) at pH 4.8 and 1M HCl) and copper fractions. The impact of technogenic input of copper was assessed with reference to the composition of atmospheric precipitations. Natural, technogenic factors and long-term fertilizers application have been shown to influence the copper state in the agroecosystems under study. The copper input from fertilizers and that from precipitation were comparable in the investigated soils. The influence of fertilizers on the copper state indices in the investigated soils was connected with the contamination of the fertilizers with copper and with the fertilizers’ impact on soil formation processes. A long-term application of fertilizers enhanced the profile differentiation of the copper total content. In the silt soil the fraction connected to organic matter prevailed and amounted to 16.8-28.9% of the total content. The copper content in grain and forage crops the experimental variants was considerably lower than the maximum permissible concentration.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Динамику соединений меди в системе почва–растение–удобрение изучали в 4 стационарных полевых опытах, заложенных в 1937, 1969, 1933 и 1950 на территории Московской области в зерно-кормовых и кормовых севооборотах. Почвы опытов дерново-подзолистые, по гранулометрическому составу – от супесчаных до тяжелосуглинистых. В вариантах опытов вносили минеральные и органические удобрения в дозах 0-60 кг/га, навоз, известковые мелиоранты (в дозах по 1 гидролитической кислотности). Отборы проб почв и растений произведены в период с 1989 по 2004 гг. В почвенных профилях определяли валовое содержание меди, ее подвижные формы (извлекаемые 1 М HCl и аммониево-ацетатным буфером с рН 4,8), фракционный состав соединений меди. Для оценки аэротехногенного воздействия на исследуемые агроэкосистемы исследовали химический состав атмосферных осадков. Установлено, что на состояние меди в исследуемых агроэкосистемах влияют природные, техногенные факторы и длительное применение удобрений. Уровни поступления меди из удобрений и атмосферных выпадений для агроэкосистем сопоставимы. Влияние удобрений на показатели состояния меди связано с присутствием в них примесей этого элемента, а также с воздействием удобрений на почвообразовательные процессы. Длительное применение удобрений приводит к усилению профильной дифференциации валового содержания меди. В тяжелосуглинистой почве в составе соединений меди преобладала фракция, прочно связанная с органическим веществом, составляющая 16,8-28,9% от валового содержания. Содержание меди в зерновых и кормовых культурах во всех вариантах опытов было значительно ниже предельно допустимого.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://agroproblem.soil.msu.ru/images/2015-4-3.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Agrochemistry and ecology problems</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2072-0386</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>