<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016017758">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Investigation of antioxidant activity of blackberry and cranberry liqueurs, prepared by the method of ultrasonic extraction</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Исследование антиоксидантной активности настоек из ежевики и клюквы</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="">
      <dcterms:alternative>приготовленных методом ультразвукового экстрагирования</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Rodionova N.S.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Manukovskaya M.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Kolomnikova J.P.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Serchenya M.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">Q02</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en" />
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">blackberries</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">cranberries</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">antioxidants</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Ultrasonics</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">extracts</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_947</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1944</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_511</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8044</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2767</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Antioxidant activity of berry liqueurs prepared by the method of ultrasonic extraction (USE) was determined in comparison with liqueurs, obtained by the traditional method. Blackberries and cranberries characterized by a high content of antioxidants were chosen as the research subjects. Cranberry and blackberry liqueurs were used in the experiment. An extractor with submersible ultrasonic transducer was used as an experimental device. The USE process was carried out in the frequency range of 20-20.5 kHz at the temperature of 20-22 deg. С. In accordance with the traditional technology of preparation of berry liqueur blackberry was kept for a longtime (60 days) in 40% ethanol solution at a ratio of berries to extractant of 1:5,cranberrywas kept there for 7 days. Operating parameters of USE were determined experimentally in the research process. With the increase in exposure time, the yield of biologically active substances increases to reach an equilibrium state corresponding to the most complete raw materials depletion. The optimum USE time during which the maximum possible transfer of solids in the extract occurs was determined and was 15 min. USE method can significantly reduce the processing time and provide a more complete extraction of substances. Antioxidant activity of cranberry and blackberry liqueurs obtained by USE was 9.92 and 10.30 mg/dm3, and of those obtained by the traditional way – 5.71 and 6.10 mg/dm3 respectively.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Определяли антиоксидантную активность ягодных настоек, приготовленных с применением метода ультразвукового экстрагирования (УЗЭ) с сравнении с настойками, полученными традиционным методом. В качестве объектов исследования были выбраны ягоды ежевики и клюквы, характеризующиеся высоким содержанием антиоксидантов. В опыте использовали настойки из ежевики и клюквы. Экспериментальной установкой служил экстрактор с ультразвуковым погружным излучателем. Процесс УЗЭ проводили в диапазоне частот 20–20,5 кГц при температуре 20-22 град. С. В соответствии с традиционной технологией приготовления ягодной настойки ежевику длительно (60 дн.) выдерживали в 40%-ном растворе этилового спирта в соотношении ягоды – экстрагент 1:5, клюкву выдерживали 7 дн. В процессе исследований экспериментально установлены режимные параметры УЗЭ. С увеличением продолжительности воздействия выход биологически активных веществ увеличивается до достижения равновесного состояния, соответствующего наиболее полному истощению сырья. Была установлена оптимальная продолжительность УЗЭ, обеспечивающая максимально возможный переход сухих веществ в экстракт – 15 мин. УЗЭ позволяет значительно сократить длительность процесса и обеспечить более полное извлечение веществ. Антиоксидантная активность настоек из клюквы и ежевики, полученных УЗЭ, составила 9,92 и 10,30 мг/дм3, а полученных традиционным способом – 5,71 и 6,10 мг/дм3 соответственно.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik-vsuet.ru/vguit/article/view/810/772</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Proceedings of the Voronezh State University of Engineering Technologies</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2226-910X</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>