<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016018392">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Assessment of technological properties of soft winter wheat varieties of different ecological origin</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Оценка технологических качеств зерна сортов озимой мягкой пшеницы разного экологического происхождения</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Kravchenko N.S.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Podgorny S.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Samofalov A.P.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F60</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Triticum aestivum</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Winter crops</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Quality</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">proteins</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Gluten</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">breadmaking</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">evaluation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">crop yield</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7951</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_24917</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6400</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6259</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3294</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1072</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2736</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_10176</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The main quality indicators of grain and flour of soft winter wheat different ecologic origin are considered. Trials of 76 varieties have been conducted in Rostov region in 2013-2014. The analysis of statistic parameters of grain quality showed their slight variability. The index of gluten deformation and dough deformation, which characterize physical properties of gluten (resilience, extensibility) turned to be the most variable: coefficient of variation (CV) was of 12.9% and 35.2% on average, respectively. The other studied technological and baking traits are characterized with a low CV, less than 10%). According to a variety and the year of study it has been noted a significant variation in protein content - from 12.5% to 17.0% with a mean value of 14.4%. The results of the study show that 23% of varieties comply with a class of strong wheat in a protein content in grain. 30% of the studied varieties match the class of valuable wheat by gluten content in grain. Comparative assessment of the winter wheat varieties on productivity has been carried out. Through a set of the indicators we have selected the varieties appropriate to the class of “strong wheat”. A correlation analysis of Pirson has been fulfilled, correlations between quality and productivity of winter wheat have been determined. It has been found out, the strongest and the most significant correlations were between a mass share of protein and a mass share of gluten (r = 0.79), between volume of bread and total assessment of bread-baking (r = 0.92). Any significant correlations between productivity and a mass share of gluten, specific work on dough deformation, volume of bread and total assessment of bread-baking haven’t found. Through a set of the indicators of quality it was found out, that the varieties Aksiniya, Donskaya bezostaya, Marafon, Don 95 (bred by All-Russian Research and Development Institute of Cereal Crops), Liga 1, Esaul (bred by Krasnodar Research and Development Institute of Agriculture) were the most appropriate to the class of strong wheat. These varieties are recommended to be used in the programs of grain quality improvement</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Рассмотрены основные показатели качества зерна и муки сортов озимой мягкой пшеницы разного экологического происхождения. Испытания 76 сортов проводили в 2013-2014 гг. в Ростовской обл. Анализ статистических параметров показателей качества зерна выявил их незначительную изменчивость. Индекс деформации клейковины и удельная работа деформации теста, которые характеризуют физические свойства клейковины (упругость, растяжимость), в среднем за годы изучения оказались наиболее вариабельными: коэффициент вариации (CV) составил 12,9% и 35,2% соответственно. Все остальные изученные технологические и хлебопекарные показатели качества характеризовались низкими (меньше 10%). В зависимости от сорта и года исследований отмечено значительное варьирование массовой доли белка от 12,5 до 17,0%, при среднем значении 14,4%. По показателю массовой доли клейковины в зерне классу сильных пшениц соответствовало 23% сортов. Классу ценных пшениц по массовой доле клейковины в зерне соответствовали 30%изучаемых сортов. Проведена сравнительная оценка сортов пшеницы по урожайности. По комплексу показателей качества выделены сорта, соответствующие классу сильных пшениц. Проведен корреляционный анализ Пирсона, определены взаимосвязи между показателями качества и урожайностью сортов озимой пшеницы. Установлены сильные значимые связи массовой доли белка с массовой долей клейковины в зерне (r = 0,79), объемного выхода хлеба и общей хлебопекарной оценки (r = 0,92). Не выявлено значимых коэффициентов корреляции между урожайностью и массовой долей клейковины, с удельной работой по деформации теста, объемным выходом хлеба и общей хлебопекарной оценкой. По комплексу показателей качества классу сильных пшениц соответствовали сорта: Аксинья, Донская безостая, Марафон, Дон 95 (выведенные во Всероссийском НИИ зерновых культур), Лига 1, Есаул (селекции Краснодарского НИИ сельского хозяйства), которые рекомендуется использовать в селекционных программах по улучшению качества зерна.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://avu.usaca.ru/ru/issues/90/articles/2057/pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Agrarian Bulletin of the Urals</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1997-4868</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 12</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>