<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016019203">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Increase in administrative competences of heads of the agricultural organizations</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Повышение управленческих компетенций руководителей сельхозорганизаций</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Balashov A.P.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Shchetinina I.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2016-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">E20</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Leaders</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">agricultural organizations</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Standards</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en" />
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">approaches</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">evaluation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_15550</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_50154</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7367</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_330992</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2736</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">There are considered problems and ways of raising the qualitative composition for managers of agricultural organizations. Analyzed is the qualitative composition for managers of agricultural organizations, Under market conditions there is required more professional control of agricultural organizations, than in the planned economy, however, it is shown on example of the Novosibirsk region that the qualitative composition of managers in agriculture has become worse, than it was before. In particular, the highest economic or managerial education is possessed only by 24.1% of managers, but 30.5% on the whole possess no profile education. It is shown that existing market conditions of management in the countryside and operating system of raising the qualification of the personnel are not able to solve that problem and for its solution it is necessary to use other economic levers. There are substantiated measures for activating the activity of federal, regional and municipal organs of agriculture management, directed for raising the qualitative composition in managerial personnel of agricultural organizations, also suggesting the methods for assessing managerial competences of the manager. It is invited to evaluate for 20 labor functions using a 5-point grading scale. There presented the results of approbating the methods on example of one of agricultural organization of the Novosibirsk region. The conclusion is made that qualitative composition in managerial personnel of agricultural organizations of Siberia does not correspond to minimum requirements of market economy. Under those conditions any measures of federal and regional organs on raising the effectiveness of the agricultural production will not bring required results. Regional organs of management need adopting the program for raising managerial competences of agricultural organizations managers in conformity with requirements of the professional standard Manager of commercial (noncommercial) organization. While its elaborating and fulfilling there can be used the approaches and methodical recommendations, stated in the article.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Рассматриваются проблемы и пути повышения качественного состава руководителей сельхозорганизаций. Анализируется качественный состав руководителей сельхозорганизаций Сибири. В рыночных условиях требуется более профессиональное управление сельхозорганизациями, чем в плановой экономике, однако на примере Новосибирской области показано, что качественный состав руководителей в сельском хозяйстве стал хуже, чем это было прежде. В частности, высшее экономическое или управленческое образование имеют лишь 24,1% руководителей, а у 30,5% вообще нет профильного образования. Показано, что сложившиеся рыночные условия хозяйствования на селе и действующая система повышения квалификации кадров не способны решить эту проблему и что для ее решения необходимо использовать другие экономические рычаги. Обосновываются меры по активизации деятельности федеральных, региональных и муниципальных органов управления сельским хозяйством, направленные на повышение качественного состава управленческих кадров сельхозорганизаций, в том числе предлагается методика оценки управленческих компетенций руководителя. Оценку предлагается проводить по 20 трудовым функциямЮ используя 5-балльную шкалу. Приводятся результаты апробации методики на примере одной из с.-х. организаций Новосибирской области. Сделан вывод, что качественный состав руководителей сельхозорганизаций Сибири не соответствует минимальным требованиям рыночной экономики. В этих условиях любые меры федеральных и региональных органов по повышению эффективности сельхозпроизводства не принесут желаемых результатов. Региональным органам управления необходимо принять программу повышения управленческих компетенций руководителей сельхозорганизаций в соответствии с требованиями профессионального стандарта "Руководитель коммерческой (некоммерческой) организации". При ее разработке и выполнении могут быть использованы подходы и методические рекомендации, изложенные в статье.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vniiesh.ru/documents/document_20729_Balashov.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Agribusiness Sector: Economics, Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">0235-2443</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>