<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016018396">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Experience of the application of EM-technology in dairy cattle</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Опыт применения ЭМ-технологии в молочном скотоводстве</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Lorets O.G.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Belookova O.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Gorelik O.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">Q55</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Dairy cows</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Probiotics</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">milk performance</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">milk fat yield</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">milk protein yield</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">efficiency</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_26767</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_32692</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_24276</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_331328</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_331327</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2491</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Possibility of  dairy performance increase in cows of black-and-white breed, and also improvements of physical and chemical indicators of milk due to application in a diet of animalsEM-preparations (EM-effective microorganisms of normal gut microflora) are considered. The experiment was realized in a farm in Chelyabinsk region on 3 cow groups, 25 heads in each. The experimental animals were treated dailyAs a result with Baikal-EM1 (dilution 1:100, 30 ml/head) and EM-Kurunga(500 ml/head) preparations, beginning from 60 days before calving. Treatments were stopped after calving. Milk performance data were recordedfor the initial 90 days of lactation.As a resultof additives application,the increase in dairy performanceof cows from initial 1970 kg by 8.1–25.0%is noted, with milk of animals of experimentalgroups more milk fat is emitted for 10.4–14.8 kg and protein – for 8.4–14.0 kg incomparison with control. The solid content in milk of cows of experimental groups was12.02 and 12.15% that is more by 0.12 and0.25% than in control. The content of fat in milk of cows of control group averaged 3.57%, and in 1 and 2 experimentalgroups its quantity increased by 0.05 and 0.13% respectively. The same regularity is revealed in relation to the total protein content. Also cows of experimental groups had a level of profitability of milk production of more and made in 1 experimental 25.0%, in 2 experimenta – 38.5% against 12.5% in control. The greatest economic effect is gained when EM-Kurunga preparation have been used in cows feeding .</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Изучали возможность повышения молочной продуктивности коров черно-пестрой породы, а также улучшения физико-химических показателей молока за счет применения в рационе животных т.н. ЭМ-препаратов, содержащих в своем составе т. н. эффективные микроорганизмы нормальной микрофлоры кишечника. Опыт проводили в одном из хозяйств в Челябинской обл. на 3 гр. коров по 25 гол. в каждой. Животным опытных групп ежедневно давали препараты Байкал ЭМ1 в разведении 1:100 (30 мл/гол.) и ЭМ-Курунга (500 мл/гол.), начиная в срок предположительно 60 дн. до отела. После отела прием препаратов прекращали. Учет молочной продуктивности вели в первые 90 дн. лактации. В результате применения добавок отмечается увеличение молочной продуктивности коров с 1970 кг на 8,1–25,0%. С молоком животных опытных групп выделяется больше молочного жира на 10,4–14,8 кг и белка – на 8,4–14,0 кг по сравнению с контролем. Содержание сухого вещества в молоке коров опытных групп составило 12,02 и 12,15%, что на 0,12 и 0,25% больше, чем в контроле. Содержание жира в молоке коров контрольной группы в среднем составило 3,57%, а в 1-й и 2-й опытных группах его количество увеличилось на 0,05 и 0,13% соответственно. Такая же закономерность прослеживается и по содержанию общего белка. Уровень рентабельности производства молока был больше у коров опытных групп и составил в 1-й опытной 25,0%, во 2-й опытной – 38,5% против 12,5% в контроле. Наибольший экономический эффект получен при использовании в кормлении коров препарата ЭМ-Курунга. Табл. 3. Библ. 11.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://avu.usaca.ru/ru/issues/90/articles/2062/pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Agrarian Bulletin of the Urals</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1997-4868</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.12</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>