<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016017739">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Environmental aspect in the assessment of utilization of production wastes as chemical ameliorants of leached chernozems in the typical forest steppe of Voronezh oblast</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Экологический аспект в оценке использования отходов производства в качестве химических мелиорантов черноземов выщелоченных типичной лесостепи Воронежской области</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Koltsova O.M.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">P33</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Forest steppe</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Chernozems</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">soil chemicophysical properties</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">enzymic activity</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">fertilizers</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">anthropogenic factors</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3053</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1533</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7182</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_35150</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2867c82c5e5a</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_34996</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Studied were the soil fertility indices on the background of changing the physical and chemical parameters under intensive anthropogenic influence. The methods used were field, laboratory analytical, comparative and mathematical. All studies were conducted in the conditions of stationary experiment in the Voronezh region established in 1987 in a 6-field crop rotation. The soil was leached medium low-humic heavy loam chernozem. The variants of the experiments: control, organic background (OB) – 40 t/ha of black fallow manure, OB + CaCO3. Ameliorants were applied to black fallow in the dose equal to the sesquialteral value hydrolytic acidity. There are given data of changes in biochemical and biological indicators of fertility and the soil biotic complex as to 2014. They allow assessing the condition of leached chernozems at different levels of fertilization and use of chemical ameliorants. The most favorable physico-chemical properties were observed in chernozem of meadow community indicating the balance of circulation of basic biophilic elements and a sufficient amount of organic matter coming with leaf litter. Among the experimental variants the best and closest to the natural ecosystem were those with ameliorants. The author determined the activity of enzymes that coordinated the process of nitrogen metabolism (urease) and intensity of redox processes (catalase). It was shown that the activity of catalase was the lowest in the control variant (3.2 cm3 O2) and the highest in ameliorated variants (8.4 and 7.9 cm3 O2), while in the meadow community it was 7.0 cm3 O2, which indicates a high level of intensity of oxidative processes and life activity of soil organisms. There has been revealed a significant rearrangement of all the components of the soil biotic complex as a result of agricultural activities. A possibility of using biological and biochemical indicators  for characterizing the ecological condition of soil has been found.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Изучали показатели почвенного плодородия на фоне изменения физико-химических показателей в условиях интенсивного антропогенного воздействия. Применяли полевой, лабораторно-аналитический, сравнительный и математический методы. Исследования проводили в Воронежской обл. в стационарном опыте, заложенном в 1987 г. в 6-польном севообороте. Почва – чернозем выщелоченный среднемощный малогумусный тяжелосуглинистый. Варианты опыта: контроль, органический фон (ОФ) – 40 т/га навоза в черный пар, ОФ + N60P60K60, ОФ + дефекат, ОФ + CaCO3. Мелиоранты вносили в черный пар в дозе, равной полуторному значению гидролитической кислотности. Приводятся данные об изменениях биохимических и биологических показателей плодородия и почвенно-биотического комплекса по состоянию на 2014 г. Они позволяют оценить состояние черноземов при различном уровне удобренности и использовании химических мелиорантов. Наиболее благоприятными были физико-химические свойства чернозема лугового сообщества, что указывает на сбалансированность круговоротов основных биофильных элементов и поступление достаточного количества органического вещества с опадом. Из опытных вариантов наиболее близкими к естественной экосистеме были варианты с мелиорантами. Определяли активность ферментов, координирующих процессы азотного обмена (уреаза) и интенсивность окислительно-восстановительных процессов (каталаза). Показано, что наименьшей активность каталазы была на варианте контроля (3,2 см3 О2), а наибольшей – на мелиорированных вариантах (8,4 и 7,9 см3 О2), в то время как в луговом сообществе этот показатель составил 7,0 см3 О2, что указывает на высокую интенсивность окислительных процессов и жизнедеятельность почвенных организмов. Выявлена значительная перестройка всех составляющих почвенно-биотического комплекса в результате с.-х. деятельности. Установлена возможность использования биологических и биохимических показателей для характеристики экологического состояния почвы.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://vestnik.vsau.ru/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/12-21.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Voronezh State Agrarian University</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2071-2243</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>