<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016018186">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Implementation of correlative analysis of utility characters of chickpea in practical plant breeding</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Применение корреляционного анализа хозяйственно-ценных признаков нута в практической селекции</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Demyanenko K.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Kazydub N.G.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Burlakow A.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F30</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Cicer arietinum</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">cultivation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Vegetative period</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Genetic correlation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Research institutions</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Selection</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">agronomic characters</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1612</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2018</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_16095</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_29796</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6514</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6951</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_210</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The expansion of chickpea cultivation areas is slowed down due to the understudied biology and genetic potential of the crop and depends much on the results of selection, technology of new varieties cultivation and their seed breeding. There is one variety of chickpea that has been recommended for cultivation in the 3rd and 4th zones of Omsk region since 2004 - Krasnokutsky 123. Chickpeas have been selecting for early maturation, high productivity, mechanized harvest feasibility, good technological characteristics, resistance to diseases and pests, increased nitrogen fixation, balanced chemical composition of grain. The objective of this study is the correlative analysis of utility characters of chickpea and its implementation in practical plant selection. In total 47 samples, from which 22 are self-clones, were studied. Experiments planned in four replications. The standard was sown in 10 numbers. The data for 2011-2014 has been presented as a correlation pleiade. The “beans per plant number” indicator is closely connected with the “precipitation” indicator (r=0.411). To visualize the data received the correlations pleiades have been presented and due to their results the features for including the plant into the crossbreeding process have been formulated. The strongest correlation is between such features as “beans per plant number” (r=0.324), “mass of seeds per plant” (r=0.174), “growing season length” (r=0.355) and the “atmospherical temperature” indicator. The difference in the strength of some connections between the samples obtained in All-Russian Plant Breeding Institute and Siberian Research Institute of Forages has been revealed. The conclusion was that the air temperature has the essential influence on other indicators and the selection should be done with the aim of crop adaptation to the conditions of Southern forest-steppe of Western Siberia.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Расширение площадей под нутом сдерживается недостаточной изученностью биологии, генетического потенциала культуры и во многом зависит от результатов селекции, технологии возделывания новых сортов и их семеноводства. В Омской области с 2004 г. рекомендован для возделывания в 3-4-й зонах один сорт нута - Краснокутский 123. Ведется селекция нута на скороспелость, высокую продуктивность, пригодность к механизированной уборке, высокие технологические качества, устойчивость к болезням и вредителям, повышение азотфиксации, сбалансированность химического состава зерна. Цель работы -корреляционный анализ хозяйственно-ценных признаков нута и его применение в практической селекции. Всего изучено 47 образцов, из которых 22 представляют собой самоклоны. Опыты заложены в 4 повторностях. Через 10 номеров высевался стандарт. Данные за 2011-2014 гг. представлены в виде корреляционной плеяды. Показатель "число бобов с растения" имеет прочную связь с показателем "количество осадков" (r = 0,411).Для визуализации полученных данных представлены плеяды зависимостей, по результатам которых рекомендованы признаки для включения в процесс гибридизации. Наиболее сильную корреляцию имеет связь таких показателей, как "число бобов с растения" (r = 0,324), "масса семян с растения" (r = 0,174), "продолжительность вегетационного периода" (r = 0,355) с показателем "температура воздуха". Выявлены различия по силе отдельных связей между образцами, полученными из Всероссийского НИИ растениеводства и Сибирского НИИ кормов. Сделан вывод, что температура воздуха в наибольшей степени влияет на остальные показатели, и селекцию следует вести на адаптацию культуры к условиям южной лесостепи Западной Сибири.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik.omgau.ru/wp-content/files/20_3.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Bulletin of Omsk State Agrarian University</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2222-0364</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>