<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016018387">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Sizes of the constitution of animals of herd of LLC “Mezenskoye”</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Размеры телосложения животных стада ООО «Мезенское»</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Rusin M.N.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Novikov A.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Romanovskaja A.R.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L40</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en" />
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Growth</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">animal performance</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3394</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5698</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The work purpose is to estimate milk performance, exterior size, growth and development of heifers grown in one of the farms of Sverdlovsk region (LLC “Mezenskoye”) and select animals whose inheritance allows to get the most productive in terms of an economy. The study was done in 2011-2014. Two hundred and two heifers, descendent of 13 sires were estimated by the exterior and milk production. Exterior measurements of heifers were following: height at the withers – 134.2 cm, in the sacrum – 141.3, chest depth – 70.8, slanting body length – 144.9, the width in makloks – 51.5, chest – 192.4, metacarpus – 19,3 cm. The average productivity of animals – 7064 kg of milk with 3.81% fat and 3.07% protein with a live weight of 588 kg. The average live weight of calves at birth – 35 kg, in 6 months – 180 kg, in 12 months – 323 kg, in 18 months – 452 kg. Increased oblique body length from 130 to 164 cm promotes milk production to 7431 kg of milk per lactation, which on 367 kg more than the average for the herd. A comparative analysis of productive heifers focus on body forms was done. Lifetime milk yield in animals for three lactations will be 22117 kg milk with 3.94% fat, 3.12% protein and the live weight of 591 kg. Evaluation and selection of bulls: Jute 1323, Mudrets 38343,Siemens 1869, Lexus 51,016,263, Dzot 1477, Quint 1317, Modnik 3591 allows inherently secure useful traits in the offspring.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Цель работы – оценить молочную продуктивность, размеры экстерьера, рост и развитие первотелок, выращиваемых в одном из хозяйств Свердловской области (ООО "Мезенское"), а также выделить животных, наследственность которых позволяет получить наибольшую продуктивность в условиях хозяйства. Исследования проведены в 2011-2014 гг. По экстерьеру и молочной продуктивности оценено 202 коровы-первотелки от 13 быков-производителей. Промеры экстерьера коров-первотелок составили: по высоте в холке – 134,2 см, в крестце – 141,3, глубине груди – 70,8, косой длине туловища – 144,9, ширине в маклоках – 51,5, обхвату груди – 192,4, обхвату пясти – 19,3 см. Средняя продуктивность животных – 7064 кг молока с содержанием жира 3,81% и белка 3,07% с живой массой 588 кг. В среднем живая масса молодняка при рождении – 35 кг, в 6 мес. – 180 кг, 12 мес. – 323 кг, 18 мес. – 452 кг. Увеличение косой длины туловища с 130 до 164 см способствует повышению удоя до 7431 кг молока за лактацию, что на 367 кг больше среднего по стаду. Проведен сравнительный анализ продуктивной направленности первотелок по формам телосложения. Пожизненный удой животных за 3 лактации составит 22117 кг молока с содержанием жира 3,94%, белка 3,12% и живой массой 591 кг. Оценка и отбор быков: Джут 1323, Мудрец 38343, Сименс 1869, Лексус 51016263, Дзот 1477, Квинт 1317, Модник 3591 позволяют наследственно закрепить полезные признаки среди потомков. Табл. 3. Библ. 8.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://avu.usaca.ru/media/BAhbBlsHOgZmSSIvMjAxNS8xMi8xMC8wNV8yOF8wNV8xMzdfX19fXzIwMTUuMzBfMzMucGRmBjoGRVQ</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Agrarian Bulletin of the Urals</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1997-4868</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 11</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>