<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016017746">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Morphological and cultural characteristics of potato blight in pure culture</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Морфолого-культуральная характеристика альтернариоза картофеля в чистой культуре</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Melnikova E.S.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Melkumova E.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">H20</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Solanum tuberosum</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">culture media</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Pathogens</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7221</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_10204</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5630</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Climate changes towards warming have led to an increase in the activity of fungi of the g. Alternaria that ispreviously considered to be saprotrophs. Due to newly established climatic conditions some species of this genus have acquired the characteristics of facultative parasitism on many cultivated plants including potato. In the Central Federal District parasites on this culture are represented by 2 species of this genus: A. solani and A. alternata. External symptoms of the disease on leaves are difficult to be distinguished</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">however, it is known that the 1 of the mentioned species is more aggressive for potatoes. The objects of research were 3 potato varieties: Red Scarlett, Rocco and Picasso, the leaves of which presented with the symptoms of potato blight in the form of dark-brown concentric spots. The A. alternata and A. solani fungi were isolated into pure culture using conventional techniques. For this purpose their biological material was take from the affected potato leaves and placed on different culture media: synthetic (Czapek’s medium), semisynthetic (potato-glucose agar) and natural (potato slices). It is known that parasitic activity of causative agents is significantly influenced by the composition and quality of culture medium with the account for nutrition sources. The best medium for cultivation and identification of differences between strains was Czapek’s medium. 20-day-old sporulating cultures on this medium can be used for further infestation of potato cultivars. In the course of research it was established that on the territory of the Voronezh region potatoes are predominantly infested with A. alternata species. In cultivation on Czapek’s medium at 20-22 deg. C in the total absence of light 4 strains were identified differing from each other in morphological and cultural characteristics: size, consistency and color of colonies. Thus, the differences identified in the strains indicate complex intraspecific composition of this fungus population.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">С изменением климата в сторону потепления произошла активизация грибов р. Alternaria, прежде считавшихся сапротрофами. Из-за сложившихся климатических условий отдельные виды этого рода приобрели признаки факультативного паразитизма на многих культурных растениях, включая картофель. На данной культуре в условиях Центрального федерального округа представлено 2 вида этого рода: A. solani и A. alternata. Внешние симптомы проявления заболевания на листьях трудно различимы, однако известно, что 1 вид более агрессивен для картофеля. Объектами исследований являлись 3 сорта картофеля: Ред Скарлет, Рокко и Пикассо, на листьях которых представлены симптомы поражения альтернариозом в виде темно-буро-коричневых концентрических пятен. Выделение грибов A. alternata и A. solani в чистую культуру проводили по общепринятым методикам. Для этого с пораженных листьев картофеля извлекали их биологический материал, который помещали на различные питательные среды: синтетическую (среда Чапека), полусинтетическую (картофельно-глюкозный агар) и натуральную (ломтики картофеля). Известно, что на паразитическую активность возбудителей существенное влияние оказывают состав и качество питательной среды с учетом источников питания. Лучшей средой для культивирования и выявления различий между штаммами оказалась среда Чапека. Двадцатидневные спорулирующие культуры на этой среде могут использоваться для дальнейшего заражения сортового материала картофеля. В ходе проведенных исследований установлено, что на территории Воронежской области на картофеле преобладает популяция вида А. alternata. При культивировании биологического материала на среде Чапека в режиме 20-22 град. С и полном отсутствии света удалось выявить 4 штамма, отличаюшиеся друг от друга морфолого-культуральными признаками: размером, консистенцией и цветом колоний. Таким образом, различия, обнаруженные у штаммов, свидетельствуют о сложном внутривидовом составе популяции этого гриба.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://vestnik.vsau.ru/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/34-38.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Voronezh State Agrarian University</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2071-2243</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>