<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016019282">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">The productivity of grain-bare fallow-tilled crop rotation on chernozems in the Yenisei region of Siberia</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Продуктивность зернопаропропашного севооборота на чернозёмах в Приенисейской Сибири</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Rudoi N.G.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Trubnikov Yu.N.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2016-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Crops</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">crop rotation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">nitrogen content</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">soil</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Phosphorus</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Potassium</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Precipitation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">fertilizers</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">crop yield</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1972</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6662</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5193</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7156</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5804</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6139</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6161</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2867c82c5e5a</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_10176</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Hilly-lowland relief in the insular forest-steppes of the Yenisei region of Siberia led to the formation of mottling of chernozem. There was compared the productivity of fallow and horse-hoeing crop rotation links (CRL) on chernozem of forest-steppe complexes of the Yenisei region of Siberia. Field, comparative-analytical, expert and mathematical methods of research were used. Stationary experiment was put on heavy loamy spottiness of the chernozem leached with ordinary chernozem. Studied were 5 crop rotations (CR): bare fallow – wheat – wheat (barley) – corn – wheat – oats. The frequency was triple. The content of humus was 6.2–7.3%, phosphorus oxide (V) (according to Chirikov) was 19–26, potassium oxide (according to Maslova) was 21–30 mg / 100 g of the soil. During 5 CR average annual rainfall changed within 256–548 mm at average values for rotation of 376–423 mm. The crop productivity of fallow CRL without applying fertilizers made up 14.6–24.9, with using of fertilizers it was 16.5– 33.9 c/ha of grain units (GU). In the horse-hoeing CRL it was 12.8–24.4 and 21.2–36.5 c/ha, respectively. In the fallow CRL average productivity of wheat without fertilizers for 5 CR was 2.5 c/ha GU above, than in the horse-hoeing CRL . On the fertilized background the efficiency of grain crops in the horse-hoeing CRL exceeded the fallow CRL by 2.9 c/ha GU.. The high pay-back of unit of active ingredient of fertilizers was provided by single nitric fertilizer. Phosphoric fertilizers affect the productivity of wheat only in case of their row application. The effect of potash fertilizers is absent. In the studied mineral system of fertilizers for 5 CR it was applied per 1 hectare of arable land (in kg of active ingredient): nitrogen 1300, phosphates 970 and potassium 790. In a year it averaged 109 kg/ha at N:P:K ratio of 1:0.7:0.6. The equilibrium condition of soil’s humus status and lack of essential change of indicators of soil fertility in the 30-year experiment were found out. It is advisable to introduce grain horse-hoeing into the agriculture system of Yenisey Siberia.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Бугристо-западинный рельеф в островных лесостепях Приенисейской Сибири обусловил формирование пятнистости черноземов. Спавнивали продуктивность парового и пропашного звеньев севооборота (ЗС) на черноземных комплексах лесостепи Приенисейской Сибири. Использовали полевой, сравнительно-аналитический, экспертный и математический методы исследований. Стационарный опыт заложен на тяжелосуглинистой пятнистости чернозема выщелоченного с черноземом обыкновенным. Изучено 5 ротаций севооборота (РС) "пар – пшеница – пшеница (ячмень) – кукуруза – пшеница – овес". Повторность трехкратная. Содержание гумуса варьирует – 6,2–7,3%</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">оксида фосфора (V) (по Чирикову) – 19–26, оксида калия (по Масловой) – 21–30 мг/100 г почвы. В течение 5 РС среднегодовые осадки изменялись в пределах 256–548 мм при средних значениях за РС 376–423 мм. Урожайность культур парового ЗС без применения удобрений составляла 14,6–24,9, с применением удобрений – 16,5–33,9 ц/га зерновых единиц (ЗЕ). В пропашном звене соответственно 12,8–24,4 и 21,2–36,5 ц/га. В паровом ЗС средняя урожайность пшеницы без применения удобрений за 5 РС на 2,5 ц/га ЗЕ выше, чем в пропашном ЗС. По удобренному фону продуктивность зерновых культур в пропашном ЗС превышает паровое ЗС на 2,9 ц/га ЗЕ. Высокую окупаемость единицы действующего вещества удобрений обеспечивает одностороннее азотное удобрение. Фосфорные сказываются на урожайности пшеницы только в случае их рядкового применения. Эффект от калийных удобрений отсутствует. В изученной минеральной системе удобрений за 5 РС внесено на гектар пашни (в кг действующего вещества): азота 1300, фосфатов 970, калия 790. В среднем за год это составляет 109 кг/га при соотношении N:Р:К = 1:0,7:0,6. Выявлено равновесное состояние гумусированности почвы и отсутствие существенного изменения показателей почвенного плодородия за 30 лет опыта. Зернопропашные севообороты.целесообразно внедрять в систему земледелия Приенисейской Сибири.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.kgau.ru/vestnik/2016_2/content/24.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Bulletin of KrasGAU</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1819-4036</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>