<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016018412">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Molecular and biological characteristics, and cultivation of an attenuated strain 1974-VNIIVViM of rift valley fever virus</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Оптимизация культивирования и молекулярно-биологическая характеристика аттенуированного штамма 1974-ВНИИВВиМ вируса лихорадки долины рифт</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Imatdinov I.R.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Balysheva V.I.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Ponomarev V.N.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Kapustina O.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L73</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Rift Valley fever virus</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Antigens</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">immune response</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">phylogeny</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_16463</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_504</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3799</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_13325</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">In recent decades, a threat of spreading Rift Valley fever (RVF) to Asia and Europe raises serious concerns. This work was aimed at molecular and biological characterization of an attenuated RVF virus (RVFV) strain 1974-VNIIVViM. The results of the investigations showed that the virus accumulated in continuous cell cultures like saiga kidney (SK), Siberian mountain goat kidney (PSGK-60) and MDVK (calve kidney cell culture) at high titers with infectious (8.53±0.21 lg MICLD50/cm3) and antigenic (1:64 to 1:128 in the passive hemagglutination test) activity levels. We determined optimal regime of the virus growth in BHK-21/13 (Syrian hamster kidney cell culture) using a roller culture method: the culture bottle rotation speed of 12 to 15 r.p.h., the infection dosage of 0.01 to 0.001 MLD50/cell, the first 12 hours of the culture at pH = 6.4 to 6.8. Further, pH is maintained at 7.2 to 7.6 for 48 to 72 hours of culture at 37 deg С, which provides the raw virus production at high infectivity and antigenicity levels. Phylogenetic analysis of the nucleotide sequences of 3 sites in S and/or M segments showed that it was closely related to strains Smithburn and Entebbe. Comparative analysis of nucleotide sequences of genes encoding glycoproteins Gn and Gc, and the nucleoprotein N, shows that most of the substitutions in the sequences of the genes of the RVFV strain 1974-VNIIVViM are synonymous and do not alter the primary amino acid sequence, with insertion and deletion missing. In the nucleotide sequence encoding glycoprotein Gn we found 8 substitutions relative to a similar sequence of M segment of a virulent strain Entebbe, and 14 substitutions when compared with M segment of strain Smithburn. A lower (as compared with other attenuated strains) amount of significant amino acid substitutions in RVFV antigenic components was revealed.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Возможность распространения лихорадки долины Рифт (ЛДР) в Азию и Европу в последние десятилетия вызывает серьезные опасения. Целью представляемой работы стало изучение молекулярно-биологических свойств аттенуированного вируса ЛДР штамм 1974-ВНИИВВиМ. Результаты исследований показали, что в перевиваемых культурах клеток почки сайги (ПС), почки зеленой мартышки (CV-1) и почки сирийского хомячка (ВНК-21/13) вирус накапливается в высоких титрах при инфекционной активности 8,23±0,21 lg MLD50/см3 и антигенной активности в реакции пассивной гемагглютинации в разведениях 1:64-1:128. Отработаны параметры культивирования вируса роллерным методом в культуре клеток ПС: скорость вращения культуральных бутылей — 12-15 об/ч, доза заражения — 0,01-0,001 MLD50/кл, рН 6,4-6,8 в первые 12 ч культивирования. Последующее поддержание рН в пределах 7,2-7,6 в течение 48-72 ч при 37 град. С обеспечивает получение вирусного сырья с высокой инфекционной и антигенной активностью. Филогенетический анализ нуклеотидных последовательностей трех участков S- и M-сегментов вирусного генома позволил установить высокую степень родства штамма 1974-ВНИИВВиМ с известными штаммами Smithburn и Entebbe. Сравнительный анализ нуклеотидных последовательностей генов, кодирующих гликопротеины Gn и Gc и нуклеопротеин N, показал, что большая часть замен в последовательностях указанных генов у штамма 1974-ВНИИВВиМ вируса ЛДР синонимичны и не приводят к изменению первичных аминокислотных последовательностей, вставки и делеции отсутствуют. В нуклеотидной последовательности, кодирующей гликопротеин Gn, нами выявлены 8 замен относительно аналогичной последовательности М-сегмента генома у вирулентного штамма Entebbe и 14 замен при сравнении с М-сегментом у штамма Smithburn. У штамма 1974-ВНИИВВиМ по сравнению с другими аттенуированными штаммами установлено низкое число значимых аминокислотных замен в антигенных компонентах вируса ЛДР. (Табл. 1. Ил. 3. Библ. 31)</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.agrobiology.ru/articles/6-2015imatdinov-rus.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Agricultural Biology</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">0131-6397</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.50/n.6</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>