<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016018071">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">The importance of the potato-growing subcomplex in ensuring food independence of the Russian Federation</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Значимость картофелеводческого подкомплекса в обеспечении продовольственной независимости Российской Федерации</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Smirnov N.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Shamin A.E.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Smirnova A.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Borodavko E.I.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2016-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">E10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">import substitution</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Potatoes</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">food security</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Food supply</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">seed production</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">economic development</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_26788</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_13551</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_10967</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3029</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6937</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2471</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">For economy of Russia a problem of food security, still, one of the major both in political and in social and economic life of the country as she assumes such state of the economy and agrarian and industrial complex at which irrespective of influence of various internal and external factors needs of the population for the food according to norms of consumption are in full satisfied. The purpose of the research is definitions of a condition of a potato complex and its influence on an economic condition of a region. The condition of a potato complex in several regions of Volga Federal District is considered based on data for 2001-2014. The need of the population for food potatoes, based on calculations of the Ministry of Health is 100 kg per a year. The shares of food potatoes in total potato production, and security with food potatoes counting on 1 inhabitant according to norms of consumption are determined. Insufficient state of potato security (75.1% from need) is revealed in Orenburg region. High security (more than 260%) is specific for Chuvash and Mari-El Republics. Importance of development of the potato enterprises, the organizations of domestic seed farming in modern market conditions, development and improvement of technologies of storage of production of potato growing, and also a possibility of his realization is emphasized. It is necessary to ensure state control of demand and supply ratio in food potato market.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Для экономики России проблема продовольственной является одной из важнейших в политической в социально-экономической жизни страны, так как она предполагает такое состояние экономики и АПК, при котором независимо от влияния различных внутренних и внешних факторов в полном объеме удовлетворяются потребности населения в продовольствии в соответствии с нормами потребления. Целью исследования является определение состояния картофелеводческого подкомплекса и его влияния на экономическое состояние региона. Рассмотрено состояние картофелеводческого подкомплекса в отдельных областях Приволжского федерального округа по данным за 2001-2014 гг. Потребность населения в продовольственном картофеле, основанная на расчетах Министерства здравоохранения, составляет 100 кг в год. Определена доля продовольственного картофеля в общем объеме производства и обеспеченность продовольственным картофелем в расчете на 1 жителя в соответствии с нормами потребления. Недостаточная обеспеченность картофелем (75,1% от необходимого) выявлена в Оренбургской обл., высокая (свыше 260%) – в Республиках Чувашия и Марий Эл. Подчеркнута значимость развития картофелеводческих предприятий, организации отечественного семеноводства в современных рыночных условиях, разработки и совершенствования технологий хранения продукции картофелеводства, а также возможности его реализации. Необходимо обеспечить государственное регулирование соотношения спроса и предложения на рынке продовольственного картофеля.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://qje.su/regionalnaya-ekonomika-i-razvitie/moskovskij-ekonomicheskij-zhurnal-2-2016-31/?print=pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Moscow Economic Journal</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2413-046X</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>