<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016017983">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Efficiency of multicomponent grass stands at long use</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Продуктивность многокомпонентных травостоев при длительном использовании</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Sabitov G.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Mazurovskaya D.E.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Kosourov D.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Ivanova S.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Medicago</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Trifolium</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Haymaking</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">varieties</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4687</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7910</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_17757</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8157</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The research was conducted in Yaroslavl region in 2006-2014. Efficiency of the multicomponent grass stands including lucerne of Meadow 67 and Pasturable 88 varieties, and meadow clover of early Mars and Trio varieties was evaluated on haymaking and pasture. The efficiency of the grass stands was not less than 4000 feed units (FU) from 1 hectare in all years of multicut use (up to 8000 FU/hectare in first years). Forages with high energy and protein nutritiousness (10 megajoule exchange energy, 10-18 % of a crude protein in 1 kg of dry matter) are received. The cost price of one FU in the 8th year of use was 1.80 rbl. at two-cut use and 1.90 rbl. - at three-cut use in lucerne-cereal grass stand on haymaking. In cereal grass stands the cost price of one FU was 4.58 rbl. without nitrogen application and 2.44 rbl. - with application of N120P30K120. On the pasture grass stands with meadow and white clovers provided the cost price of one FU equal to 1.83 rbl., and with lucerne - 1.54-1.58 rbl. The conclusion was made that legumimous-cereal grass stands which structure includes lucerne providing biological nitrogen and cereal grass stands with annual application of nitric fertilizers (N120-180) are the most productive at the long term of use. For increase in productive longevity (8-10 years) it is expedient to create lucerne-cereal grass stands (along with clover-cereal) on the basis of new zonated lucerne varieties. 2 tables. 4 ref.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Исследования проводили в Ярославской обл. В 2006-2014 гг. Оценивали продуктивность многокомпонентных травостоев, включающих люцерну изменчивую сортов Луговая 67 и Пастбищная 88, а также клевер луговой ранних сортов Марс и Трио, на сенокосе и пастбище. Во все годы многоукосного использования продуктивность травостоев составляла не менее 4000 кормовых единиц (КЕ) с 1 гектара (в первые годы – до 8000 КЕ/га). Получены корма с высокой энергетической и протеиновой питательностью (10 МДж обменной энергии, 10-18% сырого протеина в 1 кг сухого вещества). Себестоимость 1 КЕ на 8-й год использования составила в люцерно-злаковом травостое на сенокосе 1,80 руб. при двухукосном использовании и 1,90 руб. - при трехукосном использовании. На злаковых травостоях себестоимость 1 КЕ составила 4,58 руб. без внесения азота и 2,44 руб. - с внесением N120P30K120. На пастбище травостои с включением клевера лугового и ползучего обеспечивали себестоимость 1 КЕ, равную 1,83 руб., а с включением люцерны - 1,54-1,58 руб. Сделан вывод, что наиболее продуктивными при длительном использовании являются бобово-злаковые травостои, в состав которых входит люцерна изменчивая, обеспечивающая биологический азот, и злаковые травостои при внесении ежегодно азотных удобрений (N120-180). Для увеличения продуктивного долголетия (8-10 лет) целесообразно создавать люцерно-злаковые травостои (наряду с клеверо-злаковыми) на основе новых районированных сортов люцерны изменчивой. Табл. 2. Библ. 4.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.yaragrovuz.ru/images/Vestnik_APK/15-4/26-28_4-2015.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Herald of Agroindustrial complex of Upper Volga region</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1998-1635</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>