<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016018407">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">African swine fever virus glycoproteins p54 and CD2v in the context of immune response modulation: bioinformatic analysis of genetic variability and heterogeneity</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Иммунологически значимые гликопротеины p54 и CD2v вируса африканской чумы свиней: биоинформатический анализ генетических вариаций и гетерогенности</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Mima K.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Burmakina G.S.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Titov  I.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Malogolovkin A.S.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L73</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">African swine fever virus</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">GLYCOPROTEINS</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">genetic variation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">gene expression</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">recombinant proteins</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">molecular weight</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8649</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3307</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_15975</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_27527</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_36920</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4892</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The African swine fever virus (ASFV) is a unique representative of Asfaviridae family. In this work we present the analysis of structure and functions of the most variable glycoproteins ASFV p54 and CD2v using bioinformatics analysis and recombinant constructs expressed in mammalian cell cultures, the African green monkey cell culture COS-I and the human embryonal kidney cell culture HEK-293. The index of variability of amino acid sequences for P54 and CD2v proteins was calculated by Simpson’s method. The CD2v protein has variable region (N-terminal domain), which is highly glycosylated (28-30 sites) and located in the outer surface of the cell membrane. This region also contains immunoglobulin domain (amino acids at positions 1-225). p54 protein has variable glycosylated extracellular and intracellular parts. Characteristic antigenic properties of ASF virus isolates can obviously be due to found peculiar post-translational processing and genetic variations on СD2v protein. A transient expression of gene constructions used to obtain the recombinant products, p54-EGFP and CD2v-HA. The fluorescence caused by p54-EGFP was observed in the cytoplasm of the COS-I cells, transfected with recombinant plasmid р54-pEGFP-N1, whereas recombinant CD2v-НА protein was detected only in cell membrane. According to immunoblotting analysis, the CD2v molecular weight was 90 kDa against calculated 65 kDa. Moreover, 25 kDa and 90 kDa CD2v molecules, the probable differently glycosylated forms, were revealed in immonoblotting test. Thus, protein CD2v is the most likely candidate to define the interaction of ASF virus with the virus-specific antibodies.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Вирус африканской чумы свиней (АЧС) — уникальный представитель возбудителей арбовирусных инфекций. Изучена структура и функции наиболее вариабельных гликопротеинов вируса АЧС p54 и CD2v с использованием биоинформатического анализа и рекомбинантных конструкций, экспрессируемых в экстрахромосомном состоянии в культурах клеток млекопитающих COS-I (клетки африканской зеленой мартышки) и HEK-293 (клетки почки эмбриона человека). Согласно результатам биоинформатического анализа, вариабельная область (N-концевой участок) СD2v сильно гликозилирована (содержит 28-30 сайтов N- и О-гликозилирования) и находится на наружной поверхности клеточной мембраны. Эта область также содержит иммуноглобулиновый домен (1-225-я аминокислоты). Белок p54 имеет вариабельную часть, локализованную с внутренней стороны клеточной мембраны, и гликозилированный экстраклеточный участок, расположенный с ее внешней стороны. Выявленными особенностями посттрансляционных модификаций и генетическими вариациями по белку СD2v, по всей видимости, объясняется разнообразие антигенных свойств изолятов вируса АЧС. Посредством транзиентной экспрессии в клеточных линиях млекопитающих получены рекомбинантные химерные продукты p54-EGFP и CD2v-HA. При исследовании культуры клеток COS-I, трансфицированных плазмидой р54-pEGFP-N1, была установлена цитоплазматическая локализация флуоресцентно меченного рекомбинантного белка p54-EGFP. В культуре клеток НЕК-293 белок CD2v обнаруживался исключительно в составе клеточной мембраны. По данным иммуноблоттинга, молекулярная масса CD2v равнялась примерно 90 кДа (при расчетной 65 кДа). Результаты иммуноблоттинга указывали на наличие двух вариантов белка CD2v с молекулярной массой 25 кДа и 90 кДа. Итак, СD2v может считаться наиболее вероятным белком-кандидатом, определяющим взаимодействие вируса АЧС с вирусоспецифическими антителами. (Ил. 3. Библ. 32)</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.agrobiology.ru/articles/6-2015mima-rus.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Agricultural Biology</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">0131-6397</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.50/n.6</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>