<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016015525">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Effect of non-traditional vegetable raw materials on the properties and biotechnological structure pastry</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Влияние нетрадиционного растительного сырья на биотехнологические свойства и структуру сдобного теста</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Kolomnikova Ya.P.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Derkanosova A.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Manukovskaya M.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Litvinova E.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">Q02</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">doughs</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">oil cakes</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Wheat germ</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">squashes</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Grain</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Oils</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_26776</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_12909</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_11131</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_37735</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3346</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5334</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The technology of buns with the addition of wheat germ oil (WGO), wheat germ oil cake (WGOC), pumpkin seed oil cake (PSOC) was developed. WGOC is a source of complete protein and biologically active substances, is rich with essential amino acids, unsaturated omega-3, omega-6 fatty acids, vitamins E, D, B1, B2, B6, PP, pantothenic and folic acids, carotenoids. The composition of PSOC include essential oils, phytosterols, resinous substances, organic acids, vitamins C and B, carotenoids, carbohydrate melen. The WGO contains all essential amino acids (tryptophan, methionine, leucine, valine, isoleucine), polyunsaturated fatty acids (omega-3, omega-6 and omega-9 acids), a large amount of vitamins, micro- and macronutrients. Buns, in which part of the wheat flour (20%) was replaced by WGOC (10%) and PSOC (10%), were chosen for the formulation in the development of the experimental basis. Margarine in the classical formulation was replaced by WGO, sugar - by natural honey. The additives significantly improve the biotech properties of the pastry: the time of the pastry maturation reduces from 120 min to 90 min, gas generation is intensified, gas-retaining ability and pastry fermentation property increase, its humidity increases from 34 to 36% that increases the yield. During microscopic research of semi-finished products it was found that pores and honey elements are more evenly distributed in the prototype product. The conclusion was drawn that it is expedient to use the studied additives.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Разработана технология сдобных булочных изделий с добавлением масла зародышей пшеницы (МЗП), жмыха зародышей пшеницы (ЖЗП), жмыха семян тыквы (ЖСТ). ЖЗП является источником полноценного белка и биологически активных веществ, отличается высоким содержанием незаменимых аминокислот, ненасыщенных омега-3, омега-6 жирных кислот, витаминов E, D, B1, B2, B6, РР, пантотеновой и фолиевой кислот, каротиноидов. В состав ЖСТ входят эфирные масла, фитостерины, смолистые вещества, органические кислоты, витамины С и В, каротиноиды, углевод мелен. В составе МЗП присутствуют все незаменимые аминокислоты (триптофан, метионин, лейцин, валин, изолейцин), полиненасыщенные жирные кислоты (омега-3, омега-6 и омега-9 кислоты), большое количество витаминов, микро- и макроэлементов. При разработке опытной рецептуры за основу брали сдобное булочное изделие, в котором часть пшеничной муки высшего сорта (20%) заменялась ЖЗП (10%) ЖСТ (10%). Маргарин в классической рецептуре заменили на МЗП, сахар-песок – на натуральный мед. Вносимые добавки значительно улучшают биотехнологические свойства сдобного теста: процесс созревания теста сокращается со 120 мин до 90 мин, интенсифицируется газообразование, возрастают газоудерживающая способность и подъемная сила теста, его влажность повышается с 34 до 36%, что увеличивает выход изделий. При микроскопическом исследовании полуфабрикатов установлено, что в опытном образце поры и частицы меда более равномерно распределены по объему изделия. Сделан вывод о целесообразности использования изученных добавок.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik-vsuet.ru/vguit/article/download/642/596</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Proceedings of the Voronezh State University of Engineering Technologies</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2226-910X</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 3</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>