<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016017699">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Shadow side of import substitution</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Теневая сторона импортозамещения</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Golubev А.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">E70</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">import substitution</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Markets</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">efficiency</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">economic development</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">innovation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">safety</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_26788</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4626</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2491</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2471</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_27560</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6732</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">In Russian agrarian economy there are examples of sharply increased producing the Russian food, particularly in poultry farming and pig breeding (growth during 2006-2913 127 and 66%). The base of those achievements - efficient mechanisms of the state support for agricultural commodity producers. But under conditions of economic sanctions the growth of producing domestic goods is limited by primary using the import technologies, which mainly compose the base of innovative development in agriculture. That creates the threat to the food security of the country, but not apparent, but remaining in the shadow. Two ways of agriculture development are compared - the introduction of domestic and foreign innovations. Economic differences between these ways of development are comparable with expanded and simple reproduction on the innovative base. The development of own technologies is a long process, but eventually it is more profitable, as expenses for acquiring technologies and their adaptation to local conditions are excluded, the domestic intellectual potential is retained and accumulated. There is given an example of the efficient work of the Uglich poultry plant, which systematically introduces innovations, born in the depths of the enterprise, thereby giving competitive advantages at the market. The most valuable in this case is constant production of innovations, initially adapted to the Russian conditions of management. The conclusion is made about the necessity of special support for Russian innovators, who create and introduce domestic technologies.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">В российской аграрной экономике есть примеры резкого увеличения производства российского продовольствия, в частности в птицеводстве и свиноводстве (рост за 2006-2013 гг. 127 и 66%). В основе этих достижений – эффективные механизмы господдержки сельхозтоваропроизводителей. Однако в условиях экономических санкций рост производства отечественных продуктов ограничивается преимущественным использованием импортных технологий, во многом составляющих основу инновационного развития сельского хозяйства. Это создает угрозу продовольственной безопасности страны, причем не видимую, а остающуюся в тени. Сравниваются два пути развития сельского хозяйства - с внедрением отечественных и зарубежных инноваций. Экономические различия между этими путями развития сравнимы с расширенным и простым воспроизводством на инновационной основе. Разработка собственных технологий – длительный процесс, но в итоге он более выгоден, т.к. исключаются затраты на приобретение технологий и их адаптацию к местным условиям, сохраняется и накапливается отечественный интеллектуальный потенциал. Приведен пример эффективной работы Угличской птицефабрики, систематически внедряющей инновации, порождаемые в недрах самого предприятия, что дает конкурентные преимущества на рынке. Самое ценное в данном случае - постоянное производство инноваций, изначально адаптированных к российским условиям хозяйствования. Сделан вывод о необходимости особой поддержки российских новаторов, создающих и внедряющих отечественные технологии.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vniiesh.ru/documents/document_20717_Golubev.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Agribusiness Sector: Economics, Management</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">0235-2443</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 12</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>