<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016019328">
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">Gladiolus productivity increase when applying the biologically active substances</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Повышение продуктивности гладиолусов при применении биологически активных веществ</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F04</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Gladiolus</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">corms</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Insecticides</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">acaricides</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Plant protection</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Residues</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">wastewater</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">fertilizers</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">crop yield</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">varieties</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3270</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1897</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3887</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_56</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5978</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6518</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8308</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2867c82c5e5a</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_10176</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8157</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The aim of the research was to improve agricultural methods of gladiolus cultivation in order to improve its productivity. The objectives of the research were to determine the effect of biologically active substances on the formation of ornamental and agronomic biological characteristics of the plants grown with the better organic mineral nutrients obtained from the non-traditional fertilizers. The influence of the sewage sludge from the Orel municipal sector, the ash of buckwheat hulls, insectofungicide “Prestige” and biosilicon organic growth stimulator "Mival-Agro" was studied when growing the following gladiolus varieties: Jester, Amsterdam, Red balance, Oasis, Invitation. The study was done in Orel region. The influence of preparations and fertilizers on the formation of the substituting bulbous tubers was determined – their weight was 1.5 times bigger in comparison with the control and equaled 27.8 g (Jester variety), 27.3 g (Amsterdam), 26.9 g (Red balance), 28.3 (Oasis), and 26.9 g (Invitation). The additional planting material formed from the bulbous tubers has been obtained. The number of the bulbous tubers in the experimental variants has been increased in 1.5-1.8 times. The varieties of gladiolus Amsterdam, Red balance and Invitation were the most responsive to the application of the preparations tested, the number of the bulbous tubers has amounted to 17.5 pieces, 17 pieces and 18 pieces respectively. The treatment of the bulbous tubers before planting with insectofungicide “Prestige” and biosilicon organic growth regulator "Mival-Agro" has allowed to increase the gladiolus productivity. The healthy planting material of high quality has been obtained. The improved organic-mineral nutrients have had an additive effect with biologically active substances.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Цель исследований заключалась в совершенствовании агротехнических приёмов выращивания гладиолуса для повышения его продуктивности. В задачи исследований входило определение влияния биологически активных веществ на формирование декоративных и хозяйственно-биологических качеств растения, выращиваемого на фоне улучшенного органоминерального питания, за счет использования нетрадиционных удобрений. Влияние осадка сточных вод коммунального хозяйства г. Орла, золы лузги гречихи, инсектофунгицида "Престиж" и биокремнийорганического стимулятора роста "Мивал-Агро" изучали при выращивании гладиолусов следующих сортов: Jester, Amsterdam, Red balance, Oasis, Invitation. Опыты проводили в Орловской обл. Установлено влияние препаратов и удобрений на формирование замещающей клубнелуковицы, прибавка массы которой была в 1,5 раза больше, в сравнении с контролем и составила 27,8 г. (сорт Jester), 27,3 г. (Amsterdam), 26,9 г. (/Red balance), 28,3 г. (Oasis), 26,9 г. (Invitation). Отмечено получение дополнительного посадочного материала, формируемого из деток. Количество деток на опытных вариантах увеличивалось в 1,5-1,8 раз. Наиболее отзывчивыми на применение испытуемых препаратов были сорта гладиолуса Amsterdam, Red balance и Invitatoin, число деток составляло 17,5 шт., 17 шт. и 18 шт. соответственно. Обработка клубнелуковиц перед посадкой инсектофунгицидом "Престиж" и биокремнийорганическим регулятором роста "Мивал-Агро" позволили увеличить продуктивность гладиолусов. Получен здоровый посадочный материал высокого качества. Улучшенное органоминеральное питание оказало аддитивный эффект с биологически активными веществами.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://ej.orelsau.ru/vestnik/vestnik-2015-05.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 5</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>