<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016017986">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Biochemical indicators of adaptation of cows of different breeds in the conditions of Yaroslavl region</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Биохимические показатели адаптации коров разных пород в условиях Ярославской области</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Ermishin A.S.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Timakov A.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L50</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Cows</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Breeds (animals)</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">blood serum</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en" />
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1939</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_9323</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Research was done in JSC “Mikhailovsky” - one of leading breeding factories located in Yaroslavl region. Cattle of Yaroslavl breed and Mikhailovsky type of domestic selection and Holstein breed of Canadian selection is bred here in same environmental conditions. 2 experimental (cows of Holstein breed and Mikhailovsky type) and 1 control (cows of Yaroslavl breed) groups of animals taking into account physiological condition were formed. The blood sampling from a jugular vein for the purpose of studying of adaptation of import Holstein cattle of the Canadian selection to conditions at biochemical level in comparison with animals of other breeds is carried out. Methods of research are general zootechnical, biochemical and biometric. As a result of researches it has been established that the majority of biochemical indicators of blood, and complex indicators of metabolic processes in an organism of cows was in norm limits. Fluctuations of the content of some mineral components of blood serum were a consequence of intensity of metabolic processes at animals in a certain physiological condition. The level of calcium and inorganic phosphorus in blood serum of newly-calved cows of Holstein breed was significantly lower, in comparison with the Yaroslavl breed and Mikhailovsky type that indicates the predisposition of Holstein cows to imbalance of phosphorus-calcium metabolism. Statistically significant correlation connections between various indicators of blood have been revealed. The tendency of increase in activity of interamination enzymes and the lowered content of calcium at Holstein newly-calved cows in the middle of lactation was revealed. It is caused by physiological mechanisms of maintenance of biochemical reactions level necessary for life and it is a breed feature of Holstein cattle. At biochemical level it is necessary to consider the adaptation of import cows of Holstein breed as satisfactory, and the adaptation of animals of domestic selection as good. 4 tables. 7 ref.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Исследования проводились в ОАО "Михайловское" - одном из ведущих племенных заводов, расположенных в Ярославской области. Здесь разводят скот ярославской породы и михайловского типа отечественной селекции и голштинской породы канадской селекции в одних средовых условиях. Были сформированы 2 опытные (коровы голштинской породы и михайловского типа) и 1 контрольная (коровы ярославской породы) группы животных с учётом физиологического состояния. Осуществлён забор крови из ярёмной вены с целью изучения адаптации импортного голштинского скота канадской селекции к хозяйственным условиям на биохимическом уровне в сравнении с животными других пород. Методы исследований - общезоотехнические, биохимические и биометрические. В результате исследований было установлено, что большинство биохимических показателей крови, а также комплексных показателей обменных процессов в организме коров находилось в пределах нормы. Колебания содержания некоторых минеральных компонентов сыворотки являлись следствием напряжённости обменных процессов у животных в определённом физиологическом состоянии. У новотельных коров голштинской породы уровень кальция и неорганического фосфора в сыворотке крови был достоверно существенно ниже, по сравнению с ярославской породой и михайловским типом, что указывает на предрасположенность голштинских коров к нарушениям фосфорно-кальциевого обмена. Были выявлены статистически достоверные корреляционные связи между различными показателями крови. Наблюдалась тенденция к увеличению активности ферментов переаминирования и пониженному содержанию кальция у голштинских новотельных коров в середине лактации, что объяснялось работой физиологических механизмов по поддержанию биохимических реакций на необходимом для жизни уровне и являлось породной особенностью голштинского скота. Адаптацию на биохимическом уровне импортных коров голштинской породы следует считать удовлетворительной, а животных отечественной селекции - хорошей. Табл. 4. Библ. 7.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.yaragrovuz.ru/images/Vestnik_APK/15-4/29-39_4-2015.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Herald of Agroindustrial complex of Upper Volga region</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1998-1635</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>