<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016018162">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">The study of variability and inheritance of length of upper internode in soft spring wheat under the conditions of the forest-steppe of the Ob Region</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Изучение изменчивости и наследования длины верхнего междоузлия мягкой яровой пшеницы в условиях лесостепи Приобья</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Kapko T.N.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Piskarev V.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Boyko N.I.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Timofeev A.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F30</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Triticum aestivum</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">spring crops</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Internodes</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">genetic inheritance</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7951</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_24918</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3920</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3869</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Not enough attention is paid to the study of the length of the upper internode, but this trait in varying degrees affects the height of plants, yield, resistance to drought and lodging. The purpose of the research is to study the variability and inheritance of the length of the upper internode of soft spring wheat in topcrosshybrids under the conditions of the forest-steppe of the Ob Region. The experiment was conducted in 2011-2013 in the South-east part of Novosibirsk region. Eight varieties and 15 their topcross hybrids F1 and F2 were used as the material for the study. The mathematical treatment of the sign intensity was carried out using basic statistical methods. The length of the upper internodes of the studied samples varied within wide limits, depending not only on the genotype, but on the conditions of growth too. In parental forms the sign value varied from 22.9 cm in the Polyushko variety (2012) to 42.8 cm in the Belle variety (2013). In F1hybrids it varied from 24.2 cm (Pamyati Vavenkova x Tulaykovskaya 10, 2012) to 45.1 cm (Belle x Kantegirskaya 89, 2013), and in F2hybrids - from 26.1 cm (Pamyati Vavenkova x Tulaykovskaya 10, 2012) to 43.0 cm (Belle x Kantegirskaya 89, 2013). It was established that the differing growing conditions over the years accounted for the largest share (57.4%) of the total phenotypical variation of the trait. The character of inheritance of the sign at hybrids varied quite widely - from depression to overdominance, and, depending on the year of studying, two extreme variants of the degree of dominance were marked in six hybrids. This shows its high exposure to the influence of environmental conditions.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Изучению длины верхнего междоузлия уделяется недостаточно внимания, однако этот признак в той или иной степени влияет на высоту растения, урожайность, устойчивость к засухе и полеганию. Цель исследования - изучить изменчивость и наследование длины верхнего междоузлия мягкой яровой пшеницы в топкроссных скрещиваниях в условиях лесостепи Приобья. Эксперимент проводили в 2011-2013 гг. в юго-восточной зоне Новосибирской области. Материалом для исследования послужили 8 сортов и 15 их топкроссных гибридов F1 и F2. Математическую обработку выраженности признака осуществляли с использованием основных статистических методов. У изученных образцов длина верхнего междоузлия изменялась в широких пределах не только в зависимости от генотипа, но и в зависимости от условий вегетации. У родительских форм отмечено варьирование от 22,9 см у сорта Полюшко (2012) до 42,8 см у сорта Бэль (2013). У гибридов F1- от 24,2 см (Памяти Вавенкова х Тулайковская 10, 2012 г.) до 45,1 см (Бэль х Кантегирская 89, 2013 г.), а в F2- от 26,1 см (Памяти Вавенкова х Тулайковская 10, 2012 г.) до 43,0 см (Бэль х Кантегирская 89, 2013 г.) Установлено, что наибольшую долю в общем фенотипическом варьировании этого признака составили различающиеся по годам условия вегетации (57,4%). Характер наследования признака у гибридов варьировал в достаточно широких пределах - от депрессии до сверхдоминирования, причем в зависимости от года изучения у 6 гибридов были отмечены оба крайних варианта проявления степени доминирования, что говорит о её высокой подверженности влиянию условий среды.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik.omgau.ru/wp-content/files/20_1.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Bulletin of Omsk State Agrarian University</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2222-0364</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>