<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016018231">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Study on proteolysis intensity of enzyme systems formed by fungi of genus of Penicillium and rennet</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Изучение интенсивности протеолиза ферментных систем грибов рода Penicillium совместно с сычужным ферментом</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Kushevskaya M.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Shabanova O.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Kriger O.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Ostroumov L.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Smirnova I.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Zakharova L.M.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">Q02</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en" />
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Moulds</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Hydrolysis</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">proteins</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Peptides</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Free amino acids</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Organoleptic properties</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4956</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_24940</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6259</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5691</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_24275</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5399</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Proteolysis is the main process among those occurring during cheese ripening. Due to proteolytic reactions, cheeses are enriched with an ammonia solution, the density of cheeses being reduced and their consistency being improved by becoming firmer. The catalytic activity of the enzyme systems of mold fungi Penicillium caseicolum (MF) has been studied. The research results revealed that acidic protease has the highest proteolytic activity, its value reach 1.20 ± 0.07 uM (substrate) / mg (protein) h. Acidic carboxypeptidase has the same catalytic activity as the alkaline aminopeptidase. The activity of these enzymes in the mycelium of MF is 1.17 ± 0.07 uM (substrate) / mg (protein) h, while metalloprotease has catalytic activity 1.14 ± 0.06 uM (substrate) / mg (protein) h. The research results revealed that the combined use of MF and rennet accelerates proteolytic processes when ripening of soft cheeses occurs. Electrophoretic analysis of cheese peptide profiles study demonstrates that MF are the carriers of the proteolytic system of high activity. Thus, after 12 hours of protein substance hydrolysis their mass fraction lowed by 9-13%, and the mass fraction of free amino acids and peptides of different molecular weight increased. It has been established that the additional introduction of rennet into the sample accelerates the proteolytic processes. According to the presented peptide profiles the rate of accumulation of organic nitrogenous compounds increases.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Среди процессов, лежащих в основе созревания сыров, основным является процесс протеолиза. Благодаря протеолитическим реакциям сыры обогащаются аммиачным раствором, снижается плотность сыров, и – становится более упругой их консистенция. Изучена каталитическая активность ферментных систем плесневых грибов Pеnicillium caseicolum (ПГ). Установлено, что наибольшей протеолитической активностью обладает кислая протеаза, значение активности которой достигает (1,20 ± 0,07) мкМ(субстрата)/мг(белка)ч. Кислая карбоксипептидаза имеет такую же каталитическую активность, как и щелочная аминопептидаза. Активность данных ферментов в мицелии ПГ составляет (1,17 ± 0,07) мкМ (субстрата)/мг(белка)ч, в то время как металлопротеаза имеет каталитическую активность (1,14 ± 0,06) мкМ (субстрата)/мг(белка)ч. Установлено, что совместное применение ПГ и сычужного фермента ускоряет протеолитические процессы при созревании мягких сыров. Анализ электрофоретического исследования пептидных профилей сыров свидетельствует о том, что ПГ являются носителями высокоактивной протеолитической системы. Так, по истечении 12 ч гидролиза белковых веществ массовая доля последних снизилась на 9–13%, а массовая доля свободных аминокислот и пептидов различной молекулярной массы увеличилась. Также установлено, что введение в образец исследования дополнительно сычужного фермента ускоряет протеолитические процессы. Согласно представленным пептидным профилям увеличивается скорость накопления органических азотистых соединений.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://fptt-journal.ru/stories/archive/39/5.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Food Processing: Techniques and Technology</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2074-9414</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>