<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016017992">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Conditions and periods of storage of the different preparation forms of microbiopreparations based on perspective strain-antagonists of a white rot pathogen</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Условия и сроки хранения разных препаративных форм микробиопрепаратов на основе перспективных штаммов-антагонистов возбудителя белой гнили</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Maslienko L.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">J15</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Brassica napus</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Spear rot</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">storage</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1066</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_34339</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7427</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">A graded screening of a collection of the laboratory for biological methods of the Research Institute of Oil Crops has allowed selecting antagonist strains Xk-1-4 of Chaetomium olivaceum (Sh1) and B-12 of Bacillus licheniformis (Sh2) which actively decomposes clerotia of a rape white rot and have a growth stimulating activity in relation to rape plants. With the purpose to develop elements of technological regulations for the production of microbiopreparations on a base of these strains conditions and terms of storage of a liquid culture (LC) and two powder formulations were analyzed. A Sh1 LC can be maintained with the titer of1.0-9.0*10E6 KFU/ml within two months both in fridge and at variable temperature with the addition of 0.1% ascorbic acid, 5.0% PVP and 10.0% sodium humate. The best formulation for Sh1 is a perlite-based powder produced by spore washout from a hard nutrient medium, further mixing with a filler which maintained the titer at variable temperature at the level of 10E7 KFU/ml within nine months. Unlike the fungus formulation, the Sh2-based LC of microbiopreparation can be kept at variable temperature for six months with the titer maintained at 10E10 KFU/ml with the addition of 1.0% PVP or 10.0% sodium humate or 5.0% glycerin. For perlite-based powder formulation the titer of the preparation was maintained at 10E10 KFU/g at variable temperature for nine months. 6 tables. 7 ref.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">В результате ступенчатого скрининга из коллекции лаборатории биометода ВНИИ масличных культур отобраны штаммы, активно разлагающие склероции белой гнили рапса и обладающие ростостимулирующей активностью в отношении культуры рапса - Xk-1-4 Chaetomium olivaceum (Ш1) и Б-12 Bacillus licheniformis (Ш2). В целях разработки элементов технологического регламента производства микробиопрепаратов на основе Ш1 и Ш2 определяли условия и сроки хранения препаративных форм жидкая культура (ЖК) и порошок в двух модификациях. Установлено, что ЖК Ш1 можно сохранить с титром на уровне 1,0-9,0*10E6 КОЕ/мл в течение 2 месяцев как в условиях холодильника, так и в условиях переменной температуры с добавкой 0,1% аскорбиновой кислоты, 5,0% поливинилпирролидона (ПВП) и 10,0% гумата натрия. Лучшей препаративной формой для Ш1 установлен порошок на перлите, полученный смывом спор с твёрдой питательной среды с последующим смешиванием с наполнителем, сохраняющий титр при переменной температуре на уровне10E7 КОЕ/мл в течение 9 месяцев. В отличие от грибного препарата, ЖК микробиопрепарата на основе Ш2 можно хранить в условиях переменной температуры в течение 6 месяцев с сохранением титра на уровне 10E10 КОЕ/мл с добавкой 1,0% ПВП или 10,0% гумата натрия, или 5,0% глицерина. В препаративной форме порошок на перлите титр бактериального препарата сохранялся на уровне 10E10 КОЕ/г в условиях переменной температуры в течение 9 месяцев. Табл. 6. Библ. 7.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://vniimk.ru/files/text/Maslichnie_kulturi/164/74-80%20%D0%9C%D0%B0%D1%81%D0%BB%D0%B8%D0%B5%D0%BD%D0%BA%D0%BE.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Oil crops. Scientific and technical bulletin of the All-Russian Research Institute of Oil Crops</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2412-608X</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>