<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016017765">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">The effect of probiotic bacterial concentrate «Immunolakt» on bakery products quality</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Влияние пробиотического бакконцентрата «Иммунолакт» на показатели качества булочных изделий</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Belokurova E.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Solokhin S.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Rodionov A.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">Q05</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">bakery products</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Probiotics</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">chemicophysical properties</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Organoleptic properties</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_785</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_32692</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1521</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5399</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The technological aspects of the "Immunolakt" probiotic bacterial concentrate (PBC) in the manufacture of bakery products with low yeast content were studied. The experimental product was developed on the basis of traditional technology taking into account the properties of the introduced additives to correct some technological parameters. While developing the recipes PBC was used at the quantity of 20%, 40%, 60%, 80% and 100% instead of a part of yeast. Comparative studies of the microstructure of experimental and control crumbs were carried out. The content of the PBC of 40% and 60% promoted the formation of a more uniform pore structure and reduction in the number of ruptures along their perimeter. Safety indicators of reference and test samples were determined. These doses of PBC are taken as optimum ones. When determining the indicators of microbiological safety it was found that the number of bacteria of reference and experimental samples of bakery products are in the normal range. The number of mesophilic aerobic and facultative anaerobic bacteria in the test samples is less than in the reference one. Qualimetric evaluation of the quality of finished products was carried out. The developed products are of high organoleptic quality indexes, they are physically and chemically stable, with enhanced nutritional value. Products with the introduction of PBC allow to expand the range of functional orientation bakery products. The use of PBC allows to adjust the course of the technological process, to form the specific properties of the dough and to improve the finished products quality.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Исследовали технологические аспекты применения пробиотического бакконцентрата "Иммунолакт" (ПБК) в производстве хлебобулочных изделий с пониженным содержанием дрожжей. Опытное изделие разработано на основе классической технологии, с корректировкой технологических параметров с учетом свойств вносимых добавок. При разработке рецептуры использовали ПБК в количестве 20, 40, 60, 80 и 100% взамен части дрожжей в рецептуре. Проведены сравнительные исследования микроструктуры мякиша опытного и контрольного образца. Содержание ПБК в количестве 40% и 60% способствовало образованию более однородной структуры пор и сокращению количества разрывов по их периметру. Эти дозировки ПБК признаны оптимальными. При определении показателей микробиологической безопасности установлено, что количество бактерий в контрольной и опытных пробах булочных изделий находится в пределах нормы. Количество мезофильных аэробных и факультативно-анаэробных микроорганизмов в опытных образцах меньше, чем в контрольном. Проведена квалиметрическая оценка качества готовых изделий. Разработанные изделия отличаются высокими органолептическими, стабильными физико-химическими показателями качества, повышенной пищевой ценностью. Изделия с внесением ПБК позволяют расширить ассортимент хлебобулочных изделий функциональной направленности. Использование ПБК позволяет регулировать ход технологического процесса, формировать определенные свойства теста и улучшать качество готовых изделий.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik-vsuet.ru/vguit/article/view/813/775</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Proceedings of the Voronezh State University of Engineering Technologies</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2226-910X</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>