<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016017191">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Proteins from fish by-products as innovative copmponents of sport nutrition</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Протеины из вторичного рыбного сырья как инновационные компоненты спортивного питания</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Hyoling A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Grimm T.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Volkov V.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Mezenova N.Yu.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">Q04</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">foods</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Sardina</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Sardinella</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">head</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Bones</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Scales</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Hydrolysis</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Peptides</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Sport</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">nutrition</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3032</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6810</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6811</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3509</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1001</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6838</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_24940</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5691</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7328</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_49892</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The interest for low-molecular active peptides of natural origin is constantly growing in sports nutrition. Fish by-products are a potential source of such peptides, which were subjected to biotransformation by specific enzymes and thermal degradation in order to obtain the fragments of molecules less than 10 kDa. These peptides are characterized by high digestibility, showing ergogenic properties, antioxidant and immunomodulatory effects. Four types of hydrolysis were studied in order to obtain active peptides of low molecular weight. These are thermal, enzymatic, enzymatic-thermal and enzymatic-thermal with a preliminary washing of raw material by water. Vertebral bones, heads and scales of sardines and sardinelles were used as raw materials. Chemical and fractional compositions of protein and sedimentary pats of hydrolyzed system were identified. The molecular weight of the peptides and their number were determined. Enzymatic and enzymatic-thermal types of hydrolysis are recommended as the most rational in order to obtain maximum yield of protein fractions with molecular weights less than 10 kDa (98.1% and 91.7% respectively). Hydrolysates of fish scales protein are the most preferred by the results of chemical analysis and organoleptic characteristics. They are used with bee products (honey, bee pollen, bee bread, propolis) for combination of multicomponent dietary supplements for sportsmen of speed-power types of sports.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Активные пептиды, представляющие собой осколки молекул низкой молекулярной массы до 10 кДа, представляют большой практический интерес в использовании их в спортивном питании. Исследовано вторичное рыбное сырье (позвоночные кости, головы и чешуя сардины и сардинеллы), являющееся потенциальным источником активных пептидов. Протеины получали из белков вторичного сырья, содержание которых в зависимости от вида составляло 41,7-60,5%. Сырье подвергалось сравнительной биотрансформации под действием 4 типов гидролиза: термический при температуре 130 град. С, ферментативный с использованием фермента Alcalase 2,5L, ферментативно-термический (комбинированный) и ферментативно-термический с предварительным промыванием сырья водой. В результате гидролиза образовывались водорастворимая и осадочная фракции, которые сублимационно высушивались. Полученные 17 образцов исследовали органолептическими и химическими методами на содержание протеинов, липидов и минеральных веществ. В каждой фракции установлен фракционный состав основных веществ, молекулярная масса и количественное содержание пептидов. Во всех водорастворимых фракциях значительная доля сухих веществ (до 100%) приходится на протеины. Ферментативный и ферментативно-термический способы гидролиза рекомендованы в качестве рационального режима для получения активных пептидов как обеспечивающие максимальный выход протеиновых фракций с молекулярной массой менее 10 кДа - до 98,1 и 91,7% соответственно. Водорастворимые фракции гидролизатов из рыбной чешуи были использованы в технологии продуктов питания спортивного назначения. Гидролизаты из чешуи совместно с апикомпозицией (мед, пыльца, перга, прополис) вошли в состав поликомпонентных биологически активных добавок, предназначенных для спортсменов скоростно-силовых видов спорта.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.klgtu.ru/science/magazine/news_kstu/2015_39/heling.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>KSTU News</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1997-3071</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 39</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>