<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016017970">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">About prospects of development of the automobile transport in agro-industrial complex</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>О перспективах развития автомобильного транспорта в агропромышленном комплексе</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Didmanidze O.N.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Karev A.M.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Mityagin G.E.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2016-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">E21</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">N20</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">vehicles</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Satellites</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Navigation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">systems</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8180</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_14093</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_15908</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_330985</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The special aspects of transport processes in agroindustrial complex (agribusiness) are identified.  The characteristic of intra-farm, internal and external transportation is presented. The records of the park fleet in Russia as for the 1st of July 2015, age pattern of trucks GAZ, ZIL, KamAz are presented. Levels of solving problems’ focused on motor vehicles’ of agribusiness effectiveness improvement are identified. The structure of vehicle fleet by body types and capacity in agribusiness in Russia is presented (according to VIM). The perspectives in the area of fleet’s development are identified: constructing of specialized vehicles with the serial shassis, elaboration of towed machinery for common or modified vehicles for operations with hydroficated bodies of tractive units. Two the most perspective directions of activity are identified: different schemes’ of mobile electrical units elaboration generating compatible circuits also</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">application of gaseous fuel type as one of the most really usable among alternative fuels what causes solving ecological and economical problems. Propositions of system’s of fuel supply creation are presented. Organizational aspect of the process of motor vehicles is reviewed. Staff training of personnel able to realize and develop marked directions is regarded as an important element. Research directions of the Department “Automobile transport” of Russian State Agrarian University – Moscow Agricultural Academy named after K.A. Timiryazev are marked as disclosing all aspects of exploitation of transportational and technologic vehicles: elaboration of energy efficient towing vehicles</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">improving the methods of usage and operations management of transportational and technologic vehicles</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">research in the field of improvement of technical service of transportational and technologic vehicles throughout their usage</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">research in the field of the quality’s of conventional fuels improvement and alternative fuels’ appliance. 3 tables. 11 ill. 19 ref.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">Определены особенности транспортных процессов в агропромышленном комплексе (АПК). Дана характеристика внутрифермских, внутрихозяйственных и внехозяйственных перевозок. Приведены данные по парку грузовых автомобилей в России по состоянию на 1 июля 2015 г.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">возрастной структуре грузовых автомобилей по маркам ГАЗ, ЗИЛ, КамАЗ. Выделены уровни решения задач, связанных с повышением эффективности автомобильного транспорта АПК. Представлена структура парка автомобилей по типам кузовов и грузоподъемности в АПК РФ (по данным ВИМ). Определены перспективы в области рационализации состава парка: создание специализированных машин на серийных шасси, разработка прицепной техники для обычных или модифицированных для работы с гидрофицированными кузовами седельных тягачей. Выделены два перспективных направления работы: разработка различных схем мобильных электроагрегатов, разновидностью которых являются и гибридные схемы</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">применение газового топлива, как одного из самых реально применимых из альтернативных топлив, за счет чего решаются проблемы экологической и экономической направленности. Даны предложения по созданию системы снабжения топливом. Рассмотрена организационная сторона работы автомобильного транспорта, в частности использование спутниковых технологий в сельском хозяйстве. Важным звеном в развитии АПК названа подготовка кадров, способных реализовывать и развивать указанные направления. Обозначены направления научной работы кафедры «Автомобильный транспорт» РГАУ–МСХА имени К. А. Тимирязева, отражающие все аспекты эксплуатации транспортно-технологических машин: разработка энергосберегающих тягово-транспортных средств</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">совершенствование методов использования и управления работой транспортно-технологических машин</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">исследования в области совершенствования технического сервиса транспортно-технологических машин на всех этапах их использования</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">исследования в области повышения качества традиционных видов топлива и применения альтернативных топлив. Табл. 3. Ил. 11. Библ. 19.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.tis-journal.com/contents/2016/vypusk-no1/#c10114</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>The International Scientific Journal</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1995-4638</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>