<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016017071">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Technological evaluation of the plum and pear suitability for drying and freezing</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Технологическая оценка пригодности алычи и груши для сушки и замораживания</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Stepanova N.Yu.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2016-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">Q02</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Plums</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">pears</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Freezing</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">chemical composition</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">organoleptic analysis</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6028</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5645</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3091</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1794</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_16006</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The suitability of some plum and pear varieties were investigated in terms of their subsequent freezing and drying: Pavlovskaya yellow (A1), Carmine (A2), Gift to Saint-Petersburg, Chizhovsky (G1), Leningrad (G2), Petrovskaya cotton (G3). In the experiment two ways of processing were used: freezing fresh plums and pears in the dry state and the drying of plums and pears in infrared dryer. Tasting of frozen fruits showed that the most delicious and aromatic were A1 and A2 plum varieties (4.7 or 4.8 points out of 5 respectively) and G1 and G2 pear varieties (4.4 or 4.5 points respectively). The highest content of sugars was in the frozen fruits of A2 plum – 11.5% and G1 pear – 11.2%. The highest content of ascorbic acid was in the frozen A1 plum – 15.6 mg/100 g and in the G3 pear – 12.6 mg/100 g. The following varieties of plums had the richest chemical composition of the frozen fruits: A1, A2, G1 and G3. Frozen plums and pears preserved their amount of dry substances and sugars almost completely, 90-95% of ascorbic acid (% from fresh berries). Organoleptic assessment of the dried plum revealed the best varieties: A1 (4.7 points) and A2 (4.6 points)</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">G1 and G2 (4.8 points). The highest sugar content was observed in dried A2 fruits – 42%, and G2 fruits. Drying decreases ascorbic acid content drastically, but nevertheless, dried plum had its adequate content of 28–40 mg/100 g and dried pear does 22–36 mg/100 g. A1, A2, G3 and G2 pears had the richest chemical content in dried fruits. Loss of sugars during drying amounted to 14–20%, losses of ascorbic acid – from 45 to 60% for plum and 40–50% for pear (depending on variety). The following varieties are recommended for production of frozen products: A1, A2, and also G1. A1, A2, and G2 are recommended for production of dried products.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">Изучали пригодности для замораживания и сушки сортов алычи Павловская желтая (А1), Карминная (А2), Подарок Санкт-Петербургу, сортов груши Чижовская (Г1), Ленинградская (Г2), Петровская ватная (Г3). Использовалось 2 варианта переработки: заморозка свежих плодов алычи и груши в сухом виде и их сушка в инфракрасной сушилке. Дегустационная оценка замороженных плодов показала, что самые вкусные и ароматные – плоды алычи сортов А1, А2 (4,7 и 4,8 балла из 5 возможных соответственно) и груши Г1 и Г2 (4,4 и 4,5 балла соответственно). Наибольшее содержание сахаров отмечено в замороженных плодах алычи сорта А2 – 11,5% и сорта груши Г1 – 11,2%</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">аскорбиновой кислоты – в плодах А1 – 15,6 мг/100 г и Г3 – 12,6 мг/100 г. Самый богатый химический состав замороженных плодов выявлен у А1, А2, Г1 и Г3. В замороженных плодах алычи и груши почти полностью сохраняется исходное количество сухих веществ, сахаров, от 90 до 95% аскорбиновой кислоты (% от свежих ягод). При органолептической оценке сушеных плодов лучшими стали А1 (4,7 балла) и А2 (4,6 балла), Г1 и Г2 (4,8 балла). Наибольшее количество сахаров отмечено в сушеных плодах А2 – 42% и плодах Г2. Несмотря на сильное разрушение аскорбиновой кислоты при сушке, в сушеных плодах алычи и груши ее остается достаточное количество — 28–40 мг/100 г и 22–36 мг/100 г соответственно. По химическим показателям сушеных плодов наиболее богатый состав имели А1 и А2, Г3 и Г2. Потери сахаров при сушке составили 14–20%, аскорбиновой кислоты – от 45 до 60% у алычи и 40–50% у груши (в зависимости от сорта). Рекомендованы для производства замороженной продукции А1 и А2, а также Г1. Для производства сушеной продукции следует использовать А1 и А2, а также Г2.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://processes.ihbt.ifmo.ru/file/article/15324.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Scientific journal NRU ITMO Series &amp;quot;Processes and Food Production Equipment&amp;quot;</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2310-1164</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>