<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016018219">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">The features of growing new potato varieties under the conditions of the Northern forest-steppe of Western Siberia</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Особенности выращивания новых сортов картофеля в условиях северной лесостепи Западной Сибири</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Cheremisin A.I.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Solanum tuberosum</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">varieties</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">crop yield</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">disease resistance</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7221</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8157</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_10176</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2328</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The aim of the work is the studying and selection of the most productive, resistant to diseases and pests potato varieties, created in different agro-climatic zones, for cultivation in the Northern forest-steppe of Western Siberia. The comparative testing of potato varieties cultivated in North-Eastern part on Omsk region on sodpodzolic loamy soil (2012-2013) and the productivity and disease resistance of varieties in conditions of Phytophthora epiphytoty (2013) were done. According to the results of ecological trials of the collection of 42 varieties, which had been received from All-Russian Research Institute of Potato Growing (2013), it was found out that during the cultivation without intensification means (fertilizers, pesticides, irrigation) the most productive, resistant to phytophthorosis and virus diseases varieties with yield exceeding 28 t/ha were selected: Matushka, Lileya, Sirenevyi tuman, Sudarynya, Liga, Gloria, Irbitskiy, Kamenskiy. The strongest drought in July and August helped to identify the varieties with field resistance to stress factors, which tops remained green until the frosts registered in late August. The varieties of Siberian breeding proved to be more resistant to drought, at the same time the varieties from the central regions of Russia, Belarus and Ukraine showed good results. The potato analysis on the washed tubers demonstrated the absence of infestation of bacterial diseases and late blight. The infestation by potato black scurf and common scab lesions was not more than 2-3% of tubers with a defeat of less than 1/10 of the surface of the tuber. The varieties possessing field resistance to stressful environmental factors under drought and moisture deficiency are Matushka, Sudarynya, Irbitskiy, Vektar Belarusian, Ilyinskyi, Nikulinskyi, Udacha, Valentina, Krasavchik, Hozyaushka.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Целью работы является изучение и подбор наиболее урожайных, устойчивых к болезням и вредителям сортов картофеля из различных агроклиматических зон для возделывания в условиях северной лесостепи Западной Сибири. Проведено сравнительное испытание коллекции сортов картофеля, возделываемых в северо-восточной части Омской обл. на дерново-подзолистой суглинистой почве (2012-2013), а также оценка сортов по продуктивности и устойчивости к болезням в условиях эпифитотии фитофтороза (2013). По результатам экологического испытания коллекции из 42 сортов, поступивших из Всероссийского НИИ картофельного хозяйства (2013), установлено, что при выращивании картофеля без применения средств интенсификации (удобрений, пестицидов, полива) выделились наиболее урожайные, устойчивые к фитофторозу и вирусам сорта с урожайностью свыше 28 т/га: Матушка, Лилея, Сиреневый туман, Сударыня, Лига, Глория, Ирбитский, Каменский. Сильнейшая засуха в июле-августе позволила выявить сорта, обладающие полевой устойчивостью к стрессовым факторам, которые сохранили ботву зеленой практически до заморозков, отмеченных в конце августа. Более устойчивыми к засухе оказались сорта сибирской селекции, в то же время неплохой результат получен и по сортам из центральных регионов России, Белоруссии и Украины. Клубневой анализ свидетельствует об отсутствии поражения бактериальными болезнями и фитофторозом на отмытых от прилипшей земли клубнях. Степень поражения ризоктониозом и паршей обыкновенной менее 1/10 поверхности клубня отмечена у 2-3% клубней. Сортами, обладающими полевой устойчивостью к стрессовым факторам среды при острой засухе и дефиците влагообеспеченности, являются Матушка, Сударыня, Ирбитский, Вектар белорусский, Ильинский, Никулинский, Удача, Валентина, Красавчик, Хозяюшка.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik.omgau.ru/wp-content/files/20_2.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Bulletin of Omsk State Agrarian University</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2222-0364</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>