<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016018314">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Nutrient status of southern chernozem and spring barley (Hordeum sativum L.) productivity in conditions of a long-term stationary experiment</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Пищевой режим чернозема южного и продуктивность ярового ячменя (Hordeum sativum L.) в условиях длительного стационарного опыта</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Chub M.P.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Pronko V.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Yaroshenko T.M.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Klimova N.F.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Zhuravlev D.Y.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F04</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Hordeum vulgare</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">experimentation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Chernozems</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">spring crops</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en" />
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">weather</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3662</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2758</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1533</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_24918</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_15292</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">In conditions of the climate aridization mineral fertilizers may be an effective means of increasing the crop productivity, particularly of barley (Hordeum sativum L.). The article presents the results of a study carried out in the long-term stationary field experiment of barley cultivation (1985–2010) in southern chernozems of Saratov area in the arid steppe zone within a 6-field rotation of grain and row crops during 12 years. Ammonium nitrate, double superphosphate and ammonium phosphate were applied at autumn ploughing. The application of N40 and N60 significantly increased the content of nitrate N as compared with the control (by 1.4–1.5 times) in highly dry, medium dry and optimum wet years. The mobile phosphate content was increased up to 2 times in the P40 variant and somewhat less in the variants of N40–80/Р40. The maximum additional yields (8.5-12.9 centner/ha) were obtained in the variants N80–90, N40P40, N60P40 on the average for 12 years (17.2 centner per hectare). In the years with optimum moisture conditions additional yields of 15.2–21.6 centner per hectare were obtained versus 26.7 centner per hectare in the control</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">in the highly dry years additional yields amounted to 3.6–8.1 centner per hectare versus 7.2 centner per hectare in the control. In these variants the productive tillering capacity, number of grains per spike, grain weight per 10 plants were higher than in a control variant. The nitrogen uptake from the soil by main and by-products increased by 1.6–2.4 times depending on a nitrogen fertilizer dose as compared with the control and by 45% in the case of phosphate fertilizers. Utilization coefficients of nitrogen fertilizers ranged from 83 to 43% and decreased as dosages of nitrogen fertilizers were increased. The maximum protein content in barley grain (15.4–15.7% or by 1.9–2.0% higher than in the control) was obtained in highly dry years.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">В условиях аридизации климата минеральные удобрения могут служить действенным средством повышения урожайности сельскохозяйственных культур, в частности, ячменя (Hordeum sativum L.). Приводятся результаты исследований за 12 опытолет выращивания ячменя (1985–2010 гг.) в длительном стационарном опыте на черноземе южном в зоне засушливой степи (Саратовская обл.) в 6-польном зернопаровом севообороте. Аммиачную селитру, двойной суперфосфат и аммофос вносили под зяблевую вспашку. В острозасушливые, среднезасушливые и влагообеспеченные годы N40 и N60 повысили содержание нитратного азота в 1,4–1,5 раза. Содержание подвижного фосфора увеличивалось до 2 раз в варианте Р40 и несколько меньше в вариантах N40–80Р40. Варианты N80–90, N40P40, N60P40 в среднем за 12 лет дали максимальные прибавки урожаев (8,5-12,9 ц/га) к средней урожайности по опыту (17,2 ц/га). Во влагообеспеченные годы, когда средний урожай достигал 26,7 ц/га, прибавка была 15,2–21,6 ц/га. В острозасушливые годы прибавка составляла 3,6–8,1 ц/га при средней урожайности на контроле 7,2 ц/га. При этом продуктивная кустистость, число зерен в колосе и масса зерна с 10 растений были выше, чем на контроле. Вынос азота из почвы с урожаем основной и побочной продукции повышался в зависимости от дозы N в 1,6–2,4 раза по сравнению с контролем, а от P40 – на 45%. Коэффициенты использования азота удобрений колебались от 83 до 43% и снижались по мере увеличения дозы. Максимальное количество белка в зерне ячменя (15,4–15,7% или на 1,9–2,0% больше, чем в контрольном варианте) накапливалось в острозасушливые годы в вариантах N60 и N80–90.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://agroproblem.soil.msu.ru/images/2015-4-20.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Agrochemistry and ecology problems</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2072-0386</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>