<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016018433">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Validation of the SNP panel for parentage assignment in local Russian sheep breeds</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Валидация панели SNP-маркеров для контроля происхождения локальных российских пород овец</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Deniskova  T.E.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Dotsev A.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Gladyr E.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Bagirov  V.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Khompodoeva U.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Ilin  A.N.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Brem G.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Zinovieva N.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">sheep</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Breeds (animals)</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">ancestry</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">genetic markers</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7030</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_394</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_24030</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Creating panels for parentage assignment based on the most informative SNPs (minor allele frequency, MAF≥ 0.3) is an important problem of the modern sheep breeding. We have performed the whole genome SNP study in four local Russian sheep breeds — Romanov (ROM, n = 22), Baikal’s fine-fleeced (ZBL, n = 7), Buryat sheep Buubey (BUB, n = 15), and Tuvan short fat tailed (TUV, n = 16) using Ovine SNP50k BeadChip. Data were processed for the total number of markers (54241 SNPs) and for 88 autosomal SNPs, recommended by ISAG. After the quality control of the entire sample, we selected 47385 SNPs with mean MAF of 0.292±0.131 for the further analysis. The mean MAF for 88 parentage SNPs was 0.380±0.091. Analysis of the SNPs’ distribution depending on theirs MAF showed that most of the SNPs (81.8%) were informative (MAF≥ 0.3). Proportion of informative SNPs differed between breeds and was 56.8% in ROM, 63.4% in ZBL, 71.6% in BUB and 72.7% in TUV. Twenty-one SNPs (23.9%) were highly informative in all four breeds, while 37 SNPs (42.0%), 17 SNPs (19.3%) and 10 SNPs (11.4%) were informative, respectively, in three, two or only one breed. Marker DU196132_525.1 was monomorphic in TUV (MAF = 0). Three SNPs with MAF &lt; 0.3 (DU232924_365.1, DU501115_497.1 and DU372582_268.1) were not informative for all four breeds. Lower pairwise values of Fst based on 88 SNPs with the same character of genetic relations compared with those using whole genome SNP profiles shown high flexibility of ISAG panel. PCA confirmed the low breed’s dependence of SNP panel by creating purely consolidated overlapping areas corresponding to different breeds. Instead of some breed-dependent character of DNA profiles of 88 autosomal SNPs, our results confirmed the possibility of applying of ISAG panel for parentage testing in four local Russian sheep breeds.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Создание панелей для контроля происхождения овец на основе наиболее высокоинформативных SNP (single nucleotide polymorphism) с частотой минорных аллелей MAF  0,3 — актуальная проблема овцеводства. Мы провели полногеномное исследование SNP у четырех аборигенных российских пород овец — романовской (ROM, n = 22), забайкальской тонкорунной (ZBL, n = 7), полугрубошерстной бурятской овцы Буубей (BUB, n = 15) и тувинской короткожирнохвостой (TUV, n = 16) с использованием Ovine SNP50k BeadChip. Обработку полученных данных проводили для общего числа маркеров (54241 SNP) и для 88 аутосомных SNP, рекомендованных ISAG. По результатам контроля качества всей выборки было отобрано 47385 SNP со средним значением MAF = 0,292±0,131. Значение MAF для 88 SNP происхождения составило 0,380±0,091. Большая часть SNP (81,8%) оказались информативными (MAF  0,3). Доля информативных SNP различалась между породами и составляла 56,8% у ROM, 63,4% — у ZBL, 71,6% — у BUB и 72,7% — y TUV. При этом 21 SNP (23,9%) были высокоинформативны во всех четырех породах, 37 SNP (42,0%), 17 SNP (19,3%) и 10 SNP (11,4%) оказались информативными соответственно в трех, двух или только в одной породе. Маркер DU196132_525.1 был мономорфен у овец TUV (MAF = 0). Три SNP с MAF &lt; 0,3 (DU232924_365.1, DU501115_497.1 и DU372582_268.1) были неинформативны для всех четырех пород. Более низкие попарные значения Fst при использовании 88 SNP по сравнению с полногеномными SNP-профилями при сохранении характера выявленных связей подтвердили высокую универсальность панели ISAG. Низкая породная зависимость SNP панели подтверждалась формированием на PCA плоте слабо консолидированных перекрывающихся массивов, соответствующих отдельным породам. Полученные нами данные, хотя и обнаруживают некоторую породную зависимость панели ISAG, в целом показывают ее пригодность для контроля достоверности происхождения четырех аборигенных российских пород овец. (Табл. 2. Ил. 2. Библ. 35)</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.agrobiology.ru/articles/6-2015deniskova-rus.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Agricultural Biology</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">0131-6397</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.50/n.6</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>