<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016018004">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Influence of thinning out and nitrogen fertilizers on photosynthesis and growth of spruce in birch forests of myrtillus type</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Влияние разреживаний и азотных удобрений на фотосинтез и рост ели в березняках черничных</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Konovalov V.N.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Zarubina L.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F04</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Picea</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Betula</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Vaccinium myrtillus</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">undergrowth</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Nitrogen</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Photosynthesis</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Growth</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5851</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_892</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8137</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_24414</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5192</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5812</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3394</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Research purpose was determining of nitrogen dose influence on photosynthesis and growth of spruce undergrowth against the background with different light mode. Spruce undergrowth (Piceaabies Karst. (Pinacea)) in myrtillus birch forests (Betuletum myrtillosum),growing in conditions of the North of Russian Federation, served as object of research. Research was conducted on 2experimental sites: in birch forest, 53 years old (1st tier forest stand structure was 7B3Os+S, 2nd one – 10E), and in myrtillus birch forest of postfire origin with the 2nd sprucetier, 59 years old (forest stand structure before felling was7B3Os+S, after –8B2Os+S). Felling of trees of 35%, 50%, 70%dominating canopy (by storage) and controlfelling were doneon the 1st site. Industrial felling of 52% of deciduous storage and control felling weredoneon the 2nd site. Urea in the rates of N180 and N270 was appliedin each vegetation on both sites. It was found that under mature birches canopy photosynthesis intensity in spruce is 2-3 times lower than in logging area. Under these circumstances undergrowth root system works weaker, photosynthates outflow and movement water regime, growth and other physiological processes are disturbed. Nitrogen applied in mature forests has got little effect on the living condition and the growth rate of spruce undergrowth. Shelterwood felling greatly activates physiological and growth nitrogen processes in spruce while heat increasing flow and light under canopy. Next introduction in understocking contributes to further improvement of living condition of spruce. In 5 years of total care (cutting+nitrogen) spruce undergrowth additional increase doubled and increase in diameter was almost 1.5. To achieve high-biological effect from total care it is enough to thin northern birch forests to 0.5, and then in 2-3 years introduce 180 kg/ha of nitrogen. Further deciduous canopy thinning and introduction of nitrogen increased dose of N270 is inexpedient.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Цель исследований – определение влияния дозы азота на фотосинтез и рост подроста ели по фону разного светового режима. Объектом исследования служил подрост ели (Piceaabies Karst. (Pinacea)) в березняках черничных (Betuletum myrtillosum), произрастающих в условиях севера Российской Федерации. Исследования проведены на 2опытных участках: в 53-летнем березняке (состав древостоя 1-го яруса 7Б3Ос+С, 2-го – 10Е) и в 59-летнем березняке черничном послепожарного происхождения со 2-м ярусом ели (состав древостоя до рубки 7Б3Ос+С, после рубки 8Б2Ос+С). На 1-м участке проводили рубки деревьев господствующего полога (по запасу) на 35%, 50%, 70% и контрольную рубку. На 2-м участке осуществляли промышленную рубку 52% лиственного запаса и контрольную рубку. На обоих участках в каждую вегетацию вносили мочевину в нормах N180 и N270. Установлено, что под пологом спелых березняков интенсивность фотосинтеза у подроста ели в 2-3 раза ниже, чем на вырубках. В этих условиях у подроста слабее работает корневая система, нарушен отток и передвижение ассимилятов, водный режим, ростовые и другие физиологические процессы. Азот, вносимый в спелые древостои, слабо влияет на жизненное состояние и скорость роста елового подроста. Постепенные рубки, увеличивая приток света и тепла под полог, значительно активизируют физиологические и ростовые процессы ели. Последующее внесение в разреженные древостои азота способствует дальнейшему улучшению жизненного состояния ели. За 5лет действия комплексных уходов (рубка + азот) дополнительный прирост верхушечных побегов у среднего подроста ели удваивается, а прирост по диаметру увеличивается почти в полтора раза. Для достижения высокого биологического эффекта от комплексных уходов северные березняки черничные достаточно разредить до полноты 0,5, а затем через 2-3 года дополнительно внести 180 кг/га азота. Дальнейшее разреживание лиственного полога и внесение повышенной дозы азота N270 нецелесообразно.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://molochnoe.ru/journal/sites/molochnoe.ru.journal/files/jrnl_publication/20-4-book_v5.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>The Dairy Farming Bulletin</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2225-4269</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>