<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016017798">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">The impact of lucerne’s new breeds on the structure of arable layer of heavy-grey forest soils depending on mineral nutrition level</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Влияние новых сортов люцерны на структуру пахотного слоя серых лесных тяжелосуглинистых почв в зависимости от уровня минерального питания</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Tagirov Marsel</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Sharipova Gulsiya</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Shaytanov Oleg</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">P33</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">varieties</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Medicago</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">soil structure</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">soil structural units</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">soil</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8157</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4687</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7196</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7195</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7156</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The experiments on the impact of alfalfa herbage on soil structure were conducted in 2007-2010 in the Republic of Tatarstan., Six alfalfa cultivars that are well adapted to local conditions were selected for this purpose - Aysylu, Tatarskaya pasture, Guzel, Muslima, Sarga, Kameliya. The soil is gray forest heavy loam, pH 5.4, with the content of humus - 3.56%, alkali-hydrolyzable nitrogen - 92.4 mg, mobile phosphorus - 157.5 mg, potassium - 85.2 mg/kg of soil. The experiment was conducted on the following backgrounds of mineral nutrition: check test (without fertilizer), N48P48K48 - annually in early spring, N72P72K72- annually in early spring. The size of plot - 45 m2, replication - four-time. The sowing was pure in order to reduce the number of influencing factors. In 2007 before experience the soil samples with the intact structure were taken from each plot of the arable layer (0-25 cm), in which the content of water-stable aggregates was determined by method of wet sieving on the unit of I.M. Baksheev. The content of aggregates of 0.25mm fraction was 47.5-53.0% in the control variant without fertilizer background, depending on the variety being studied. This index ranged from 46.3% to 51.2% on a moderate background, and from 43.3 to 50.9% on an increased background. The coefficient of soil structure under the grass stands of alfalfa was equal to or below 1.0 and only in the embodiment with Aysylu it was equal to 1.13. After comparing the data from 2007 and 2010 it was found that modern alfalfa varieties differ from each other by intensity of root system growth, responsiveness to fertilizers and habitat-forming properties. Guzel variety has the most pronounced responsiveness to the application of mineral fertilizers, it has the greatest factor of soil structuring – 2.09-2.76 on different fertilizer backgrounds. The increase of this coefficient for 3 years in other varieties was 0.22-1.57.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">В 2007-2010 гг. в Республике Татарстан были проведены опыты по изучению влияния травостоев люцерны на структуру почвы. Для этих целей были отобраны 6 сортов люцерны, хорошо адаптированных к местным условиям – Айслу, Татарская пастбищная, Гюзель, Муслима, Сарга, Камелия. Почва – серая лесная тяжелосуглинистая, рН 5,4, с содержанием гумуса 3,56%, щёлочногидролизуемого азота – 92,4 мг, подвижного фосфора – 157,5 мг и калия – 85,2 мг в 1 кг почвы. Опыт проводился на следующих фонах минерального питания: контроль (без удобрений), N48P48K48 – ежегодно рано весной, N72P72K72– ежегодно рано весной. Размер делянки – 45 м2, повторность – четырёхкратная. В целях уменьшения количества влияющих факторов посев производился беспокровно. В 2007 г. перед закладкой опыта из пахотного горизонта (0-25 см) каждой делянки были взяты образцы почвы с ненарушенной структурой, в которых методом мокрого просеивания на приборе И.М. Бакшеева было определено содержание водопрочных агрегатов. Содержание агрегатов фракции более 0,25 мм составляло на контрольном фоне без удобрений 47,5-53,0% в зависимости от изучаемого сорта,на умеренном - 46,3-51,2%, на повышенном– от 43,3 до 50,9%. Коэффициент структурности почвы под травостоями люцерны был равен или ниже 1,0 и лишь в варианте со стандартом Айслу на контрольном фоне он был равен 1,13. При сопоставлении данных за 2007 и за 2010 гг. установлено, что современные сорта люцерны существенно различаются между собой интенсивностью роста корневой системы, отзывчивостью на внесение удобрений и средообразующими свойствами. Наиболее выраженной отзывчивостью на внесение минеральных удобрений обладает сорт Гюзель, у нее наибольший коэффициент структурности почвы – 2,09-2,76 на разных фонах удобрений. У остальных сортов прибавка этого коэффициента за 3 года составила 0,22-1,57.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik-kazgau.com/images/archive/2015/4/22_tagirov.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Kazan State Agrarian University</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2073-0462</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>