<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016017785">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Influence of fertilizers on productivity of different types of feed on grey forest soil of the Republic of Tatarstan</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Влияние минеральных удобрений на урожайность различных видов кормосмесей на серых лесных почвах республики Татарстан</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Malikov Marsel</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Nizamov Rustam</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Mukhamadiev Rustem</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Minnullin Gennady</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Suleymanov Salavat</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F04</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Crops</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">compound feeds</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">crop yield</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Quality</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">fertilizers</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1972</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1796</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_10176</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6400</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2867c82c5e5a</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The field experiments testing different backgrounds of mineral nutrition were done in north-eastern part of the Republic of Tatarstan in 2011-2013. Experimental area’s soil is grey forest, medium-loamy. Natural soil fertility is low – humus content by Tyurin is only 2-3%. Salt extraction pH is 6.0-6.5. Available phosphorus content (according to Kirsanov) is 139 mg/kg and 113 mg/kg of exchangeable potassium. Two feed mixes (1 - peas, oats, barley at seeding rates of 200, 80 and 80 kg/hectare respectively, 2 – same + sunflower of 10 kg/hectare) and sunflower (20 kg/hectare) were grown. NPK was applied in 70, 155, 250 and 340 kg/hectare norms. In average for 3 years yield’s minimum level was typical for pea-oat-barley mixture of all backgrounds of fertilizers application (13.1 t/hectare in the background without fertilizer). At the same time, this sample was the largest increase of mineral fertilizers in relation to the background without mineral fertilizers (78.6%). Maximum values of green mass produced on a single-component variant of sunflower - 42.4 tons per hectare on a background of NPK 155 kg/hectare. The composition of the feed mixture with the inclusion of sunflower was intermediate (30.8 t/hectare). Mineral fertilizers heavily increased the productivity of green mass, rather than of the solids. The highest yielding agrocoenosis was formed in the mixtures with sunflower and in pure crops of sunflower. High efficiency of the active ingredient units of fertilizers is also observed in mixed crops with sunflower and with NPK of 70-135 kg/hectare. The productivity of feed mixture and payment of the active ingredient of fertilizers increases to the level of 155-250 kg/hectare. At higher norms of mineral fertilizers, the output of the active ingredient units of fertilizers is sharply reduced. Mineral composition and content of digestible protein in mixed sunflower stands with peas and forage ones are more favorable, than in pure sunflower crops.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">В 2011-2013 гг. в северо-восточной части Республики Татарстан были проведены полевые опыты по испытанию различных фонов минерального питания. Почвы опытного участка серо-лесные, среднесуглинистые. Естественное плодородие почв невысокое – содержание гумуса по Тюрину составляет всего 2-3%, рН солевой вытяжки – 6,0-6,5, содержание подвижного фосфора (по Кирсанову) - 139 мг/кг, обменного калия - 113 мг/кг почвы. Выращивали 2 вида кормосмесей (1 - горох, овес, ячмень при нормах высева 200, 80 и 80 кг/га соответственно, 2 – то же + подсолнечник 10 кг/га) и подсолнечник (20 кг/га). NPK вносили в нормах 70, 155, 250 и 340 кг/га д.в. В среднем за 3 года минимальный уровень урожайности был характерен для горохово-овсяно-ячменной смеси по всем фонам внесения удобрений (13,1 т/га на фоне без удобрений). В то же время на данном варианте была наибольшая прибавка от внесения минеральных удобрений по отношению к фону без внесения минеральных удобрений (78,6%). Максимальные показатели зеленой массы получены на варианте однокомпонентных посевов подсолнечника – 42,4 т/га на фоне NPK 155 кг/га д.в. Состав кормосмеси с включением подсолнечника занимал промежуточное положение (30,8 т/га). Минеральные удобрения в большой степени повышали урожайность зеленой массы, чем сухого вещества. Наиболее высокие урожайные агроценозы формировались в смесях с подсолнечником и в одновидовых посевах подсолнечника. Высокая отдача единицы действующего вещества вносимых удобрений также наблюдалась в смешанных посевах с подсолнечником и при внесении NPK от 70 до 135 кг/га д.в. Продуктивность кормосмесей и оплата действующего вещества удобрений возрастает до уровня питания 155-250 кг/га. При более высоких дозах минеральных веществ отдача единицы действующего вещества удобрений резко снижается. Смешанные посевы подсолнечника с горохом и зернофуражными культурами отличаются от одновидовых посевов подсолнечника более благоприятным минеральным составом и высоким содержанием переваримого протеина.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik-kazgau.com/images/archive/2015/4/16_malikov.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Kazan State Agrarian University</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2073-0462</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>