<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016018024">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Simulating interaction of the foot of legged locomotion mover with water-saturated grounds</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Моделирование взаимодействия стопы шагающего движителя с водонасыщенными грунтами</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Chernyshev V.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Arykantsev V.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">N20</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">equipment</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">soil</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Dynamic models</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2631</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7156</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_28670</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The objective of the research is to increase ground passing ability and ecological compatibility of legged locomotion mover (LLM) at water-saturated grounds. For the study a method of mathematical simulation of mechanics of foot contact with ground was used by means of the package of finite-element simulation software ANSYS (ANSYS Inc.). The process of interaction of LLM with ground can be divided on the phase of foot change and the phase of traction power. For dynamics of foot change as a calculation scheme was assumed a scheme for two-legged locomotion machine with vertical translational body movement. The simulation has shown that during leg change there are vibrations of legs in the ground. Wherein support reactions can significantly (in two times and more) exceed the static ones. However, vibrations at water-saturated tough grounds provided by leg change occupy a small part of cycle (about 5%). Therefore, an interaction of the foot with ground in support phase can be considered as quasi-static. The impact of foot shape as well as average pressure on the ground on its stress state was found out. The least impact on soil at the same equal conditions was made by ski-shaped foot. It was proved that for ski-shaped foot the impact rate on soil according to the standard (GOST 26955–86) is required an average pressure of the foot on the ground about 0.08 MPa. At water-saturated grounds with low elastic properties the pressure of the foot on the ground should be decreased to 0.03–0.04 MPa. Otherwise, inadmissibly high ground deformations occur. The results obtained can be used either in design of elementary legged locomotion machines, for example for new soil-protected technologies in irrigated agriculture, or for complex robotics systems intended for operation in extreme conditions.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Целью исследований являлось повышение грунтовой проходимости и экологичности шагающего движителя на водонасыщенных грунтах. Для исследований использован метод математического моделирования механики контакта стопы с грунтом при помощи пакета конечно-элементного моделирования ANSYS (компании ANSYS Inc.). Процесс взаимодействия шагающего движителя с грунтом подразделялся на фазу смены стоп и фазу реализации тягового усилия. При исследовании динамики смены стоп в качестве расчетной принималась двуногая схема шагающей машины с вертикальным поступательным движением корпуса. Моделирование показало, что при смене ног имеют место колебания стоп на грунте. При этом опорные реакции могут существенно (в 2 раза и более) превосходить статические. Вместе с тем на водонасыщенных вязких грунтах колебания, обусловленные сменой стоп, занимают по времени лишь малую часть цикла (порядка 5%), поэтому для них взаимодействие стопы с грунтом в опорной фазе можно считать квазистатическим. Выяснено влияние формы стопы и среднего давления на грунт на его напряженное состояние. Наименьшее воздействие на почву при прочих равных условиях оказывают лыжеобразные стопы. Доказано, что для лыжеобразных стоп нормы воздействия движителей на почву согласно требованиям ГОСТ 26955–86 соблюдаются при среднем давлении стопы на грунт порядка 0,08 МПа. На водонасыщенных грунтах, для которых характерны невысокие упругие свойства, давление стопы на грунт целесообразно снизить до 0,03–0,04 МПа. В противном случае имеют место недопустимо высокие деформации грунта. Полученные результаты могут быть востребованны как при разработке простейших шагающих машин, например для новых почвосберегающих технологий в орошаемом земледелии, так и для сложных робототехнических систем, предназначенных для работы в экстремальных условиях.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.rosniipm-sm.ru/dl_files/udb_files/udb13-rec368-field6.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Scientific Journal of Russian Research Institute of Land Improvement Problems</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2222-1816</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>