<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016017991">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Technological elements of using different formulations of microbiopreparations on the base of the promising antagonist strains XK-1-4 of Chaetomium olivaceum and B-12 of Bacillus licheniformis against white rot of winter rapeseed</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Элементы технологии применения разных препаративных форм микробиопрепаратов на основе перспективных штаммов-антагонистов XK-1-4 Chaetomium olivaceum и Б-12 Bacillus licheniformis против белой гнили озимого рапса</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Maslienko L.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Shipievskaya E.Yu.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">H20</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Brassica napus</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Spear rot</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Viability</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Sclerotia</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1066</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_34339</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8210</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_35192</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Antagonist strains Xk-1-4 of Chaetomium olivaceum (Sh1) and B-12 of Bacillus licheniformis (Sh2) were selected from a collection of the laboratory for biological methods of the Research Institute of Oil Crops as a result of a graded screening. These strains actively decompose sclerotia of rapeseed white rot Sclerotinia sclerotiorum (Lib.) De Bary and have a growth-stimulating activity of winter rape plants. The purpose of the study was to determine optimal methods, dates and norms of use of different microbiological formulations (MBF) based on the selected Sh1 and Sh2. The study involved the treatment of rape seeds before sowing, and also the treatment of infected plant residues after harvesting and before soil disking. For an artificial infection of rapeseed with a white rot pathogen the rapeseed seeds were laid on a wetted filter paper, then placed into Petri’s dishes on a white rot mycelium, the method resulted in infecting up to 80.0% of the seeds. The study showed a high efficiency of rapeseed treatment with a Sh1biopreparationto control white rot pathogen</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">the maximal biological efficiency has been determined for a powder formulation at the rate of 3.0 kg/t (72.7%) . The treatment of winter rapeseed residues with Sh1 and Sh2 based MBFs in summer and autumn before soil disking was shown to decrease the viability of white rot sclerotia. In summer, the use of powder MBF at the rate of 20.0 kg per ha (83.6-85.4%) and a liquid culture at the rate of 50.0 l per ha (81.8-85.4%) was the most effective. The efficiency of treating plant residues with these MBFs in autumn prior to soil disking at the rate of 30.0 l per ha was 79.9-82.3%. 3 tables. 4 ill. 17 ref.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">В результате ступенчатого скрининга из коллекции лаборатории биометода ВНИИ масличных культур отобраны штаммы-антагонисты Xk-1-4 Chaetomium olivaceum (Ш1) и Б-12 Bacillus licheniformis (Ш2), активно разлагающие склероции белой гнили рапса Sclerotinia sclerotiorum (Lib.) De Bary и стимулирующие рост растений озимого рапса. Целью исследования являлось установление оптимальных способов, сроков и норм применения разных препаративных форм микробиологических препаратов (МБП) на основе отобранных Ш1 и Ш2. Испытывали обработку семян рапса перед посевом, а также обработку растительных остатков, поражённых болезнью, после уборки, перед дискованием почвы. Для искусственного заражения рапса возбудителем белой гнили применяли метод раскладывания семян рапса на увлажнённую фильтровальную бумагу, помещённую в чашку Петри на газон белой гнили, при этом заражалось до 80,0% семян. Установлена высокая эффективность обработки семян рапса против возбудителя белой гнили биопрепаратом на основе Ш1. Максимальная биологическая эффективность установлена для препаративной формы порошок, с нормой расхода 3,0 кг/т (72,7%).Установлена возможность снижения жизнеспособности склероциев белой гнили при обработке растительных остатков озимого рапса МБП на основе Ш1 и Ш2 летом и осенью, перед дискованием почвы. Летом максимальная эффективность установлена при применении МБП в препаративной форме порошок, с нормой расхода 20,0 кг/га (83,6-85,4%), и жидкая культура, с нормой расхода 50,0 л/га (81,8-85,4%). При применении этих МБП осенью, перед дискованием почвы, эффективность обработки растительных остатков с нормой расхода 30,0 л/га составила 79,9-82,3%. Табл. 3. Ил. 4. Библ. 17.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://vniimk.ru/files/text/Maslichnie_kulturi/164/66-73%20%D0%9C%D0%B0%D1%81%D0%BB%D0%B8%D0%B5%D0%BD%D0%BA%D0%BE,%20%D0%A8%D0%B8%D0%BF%D0%B8%D0%B5%D0%B2%D1%81%D0%BA%D0%B0%D1%8F.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Oil crops. Scientific and technical bulletin of the All-Russian Research Institute of Oil Crops</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2412-608X</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>