<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016017967">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Choice of strategy use of raised vehicles in agriculture</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Выбор стратегий использования привлеченных транспортных средств в сельском хозяйстве</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Didmanidze O.N.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Aldoshin N.V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Karev A.M.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Pekhutov A.S.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">J10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Crops</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">vehicles</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">strategies</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">transport</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1972</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8180</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_330991</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7874</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The application of the bi-matrix theory of a game within the organization of cargo transportation by the automobile transport in the conditions of agrarian and industrial complex is being shown. The priority direction of the state Transport strategy of the Russian Federation till 2030 has been determined as - the creation of conditions for the increase of the efficiency of usage of the automobile transport serving productions of cultivation and harvesting. A problem of automobile transportation branch in agriculture is the organization of interaction of public transport and transport of the enterprises and the organizations during the periods of the expressed maxima of volumes of transportations: spring and autumn for farms of the grain direction and summer for farms of the livestock direction. The efficiency of collaboration of partners depends in many respects on the correctness of the choice of strategy of their behaviour. It is offered to use the mathematical apparatus of bi-matrix games for the choice of strategy of use of the applied vehicles. The solution of such games – the simultaneous choice by two partners of joint strategy of actions at which in this or that, but identical sense this choice would satisfy both. It is necessary to find such equilibrium situation from which the deviation of one of partners would reduce his prize. The equilibrium situation for each of partners is defined not so much by the aspiration to increase own prize, how many desire to keep the partner's prize under control. In bi-matrix game we meet antagonism of behaviour, but not antagonism of interests. Such approach is reasonable in that case when the agricultural and automobile transportation enterprises have various proprietary accessories. At the performance of transport works by different structural divisions within one organization for receiving rational strategy it is necessary to use in bi-matrix games optimality across Pareto. In this situation partners, working in common, can't increase a prize of everyone. It is rational to use such optimality in large agro-holdings. 19 ref.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Показано применение биматричной теории игры при организации грузоперевозок автомобильным транспортом в условиях АПК. Приоритетным направлением государственной Транспортной стратегии РФ до 2030 г. определено создание условий для повышения эффективности использования автомобильного транспорта, обслуживающего производственные процессы возделывания и уборки сельскохозяйственных культур. Проблемой автотранспортной отрасли в сельском хозяйстве является организация взаимодействия транспорта общего пользования и транспорта предприятий и организаций в периоды выраженных максимумов объемов перевозок: весенний и осенний для хозяйств зернового направления и летний для хозяйств животноводческого направления. Эффективность совместной работы партнеров зависит во многом от правильности выбора стратегии их поведения. Предложено для выбора стратегий использования привлеченных транспортных средств использовать математический аппарат биматричных игр. Решение таких игр – одновременный выбор двумя партнерами совместной стратегии действий, при которой в том или ином, но одинаковом смысле этот выбор удовлетворял бы обоих. Необходимо найти такую равновесную ситуацию, отклонение от которой одного из партнеров уменьшало бы его выигрыш. Равновесная ситуация для каждого из партнеров определяется не столько стремлением увеличить собственный выигрыш, сколько желанием держать под контролем выигрыш партнера. В биматричной игре мы встречаемся с антагонизмом поведения, а не антагонизмом интересов. Такой подход обоснован в том случае, когда сельскохозяйственное и автотранспортное предприятия имеют различную собственническую принадлежность. При выполнении транспортных работ разными структурными подразделениями в рамках одной организации для получения рациональной стратегии необходимо использовать в биматричных играх оптимальность по Парето. В данной ситуации партнеры, действуя совместно, не могут увеличить выигрыш каждого. Такую оптимальность рационально использовать в крупных агрохолдингах. Библ. 19.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.tite-journal.com/content/2015/vypusk-no6/#c10018</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>The International Technical-economic Journal</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1995-4646</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 6</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>