<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016017959">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Psychoemotional state of sheep after the protracted transporting</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Психоэмоциональное состояние овец после длительной транспортировки</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Fyodorova A.O.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Kukharenko N.S.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2016-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L50</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L74</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">sheep</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">transport</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Stress</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Probiotics</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7030</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7874</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7452</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_32692</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The purpose of the study is to track and analyze the psycho-emotional state of the sheep having a stress after long transportation. The sheep of the Texel and Edilbaevskaya breed, 119 animals 4-6 months old, served as the material for the research. Animals were brought from the Vladimir region in the Amur region by road. The transportation took 11 days. "Intestevit" probiotic was used once a day with forage, at the rate of 10 doses/animal for 10 days, to reduce signs of psycho-emotional stress after transport in all animals. Clinical monitoring of a livestock was carried out on the 2nd, 7th and 15th days after arrival to the economy. The animals that have undergone long transport period had a disorder of psycho-emotional state at first for several days. Aberrations were registered in 55% of animals. The signs characterize the first stage of stress (alarm) having two phases: shock and proteosome. A violation of psycho-emotional state, muscle tone slowdown, muscle tremors, fearfulness and enlarged pupils were noted in the phase of shock. Then the phase of proteosome came, when all the external characteristic features of stress began to gradually fade: muscle tone increased, the animals calmed down. By the 15th day of staying in the new living conditions the second stage of stress was noted - adaptation. During this period the animals by external features managed to recover. 41% of animals by this moment had only one stress sign from 46 estimated – lack of response to irritation. Thus, the most sudden and severe changes of psycho-emotional state of sheep were noted on the second and seventh day after transport. This reaction of animals to stress during normal conditions may end in the destruction. Application of probiotic preparation softens the effect of transport stress, helps the animal to handle it better and recover faster.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Цель исследования – проследить и проанализировать психо-эмоциональное состояние овец, подвергшихся стрессу от длительной транспортировки. Материалом для исследований служили овцы породы Тексель и Эдильбаевская 4-6-тимесячного возраста, в количестве 119 голов. Животные завозились из Владимировской области в Амурскую автотранспортом. Продолжительность транспортировки составила 11 сут. Для снижения признаков послетранспортного психоэмоционального стресса всем животным применяли пробиотик "Интестевит" 1 раз в сутки с кормом, из расчета 10 доз/гол. в течение 10 дн. Клинический мониторинг поголовья проводили на 2-е, 7-е и 15-е сут по прибытии в хозяйство. В первые дни у животных, перенёсших длительную транспортировку, возникало расстройство психо-эмоционального состояния. Отклонения от нормы выявлялись у 55% животных. Выявленные признаки характеризуют первую стадию стресса (тревоги), протекающую в две фазы: шока и противошока. В фазу шока происходило нарушение психоэмоционального состояния, падал мышечный тонус, возникала мышечная дрожь, проявлялась пугливость и расширялись зрачки. Затем наступала фаза противошока, когда все внешние характерные признаки стресса постепенно начинали проходить: мышечный тонус повышался, животные успокаивались. К 15-му дню пребывания в новых условиях существования проявилась вторая стадия стресса - адаптация. В этот период животные по внешним признакам успели восстановиться. У 41% животных к этому моменту остался только 1 признак стресса из 46 оценивавшихся – отсутствие ответных реакций на раздражение. Таким образом, наиболее резкие и тяжёлые изменения психоэмоционального состояния овец были отмечены на 2-й и 7-й дни после перевозки. Такая реакция животных на стресс в обычных условиях может закончиться гибелью. Применение пробиотического препарата смягчает действие транспортного стресса, помогает животному легче его перенести и быстрее восстановиться.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik.dalgau.ru/images/gurnal/vipusk_2016/nomer_1/Fyodorova.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Far Eastern Agrarian Herald</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">1999-6837</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 1</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>