<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016017779">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Formation of barley harvest depending on the nutrition background and the use of herbicides</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Формирование урожая ячменя в зависимости от фона питания и применения гербицидов</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Vladimirov Vladimir</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Korshunov Aleksandr</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Mitrofanov Eduard</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">F04</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Hordeum vulgare</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">varieties</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Humus</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">mineral fertilizers</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">application rates</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Herbicides</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">crop yield</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">proteins</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3662</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8157</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3693</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_36161</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_16113</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3566</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_10176</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6259</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Experiments were done in 2013-2015 in Volga-Vyatka region of Russian Federation. Soil is dark grey forest of medium-size distribution. Topsoil capacity is 28-32 cm. Humus content is 5-7%, mobile phosphorus - 170-187 mg/kg and exchangeable potassium - 77-180 mg/kg. Preceding crop is spring wheat. Fertilizers were added under predecessor in N60P60K60 doze. Straw was milled and close up at autumn tillage. Elf barley variety seeding rate is 5 million germinating seeds. 2 nutrient statuses (N54P54K54 and N70R70K70) and 4 types of herbicides were compared. Barley plants’ phenological phases’ earlier onset was observed in control, on plots without fertilizers and herbicides application, which can be explained by lower nutrients content in soil. In higher N70P70K70 fertilizers status phenological phases onset was somewhat delayed, even in comparison with status with N54P54K54 fertilizer dose. Crops general infestation in tillering stage before treatment was 283 pieces/m2 averaged for 3 years. Fertilizer application stimulates ammonifiers microflora, resulting in mineral nitrogen available forms accumulation necessary for cellulose-decomposing microorganisms vital activity normal functioning. With increase in cellulose-decomposing microorganisms number, cellulose pulp intensity in soil increases too. By the middle of growing season soaked in soil burlap decomposed in control variant by 20.3%. When herbicides were applied, fertilizing N54P54K54 increased the barley grain productivity by 0.86-1.13 t/hectare, and N70P70K70 - to 1.01-1.25 t/hectare with the yield in control being 1.58 t/hectare on average for 3 years. In both fertilizer application statuses the maximum barley harvest was formed when applying the herbicide Bomba: with N54P54K54 – 2.71 t/hectare, N70P70K70 – 2.83 t/hectare. In these variants, compared to the control one, the protein content in grain increased by 0.54-1.75% at the value of the indicator in control of 9.60%.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Опыты проводили в 2013-2015 гг. в Волго-Вятском регионе РФ. Почва участка темно-серая лесная, среднесуглинистая. Мощность пахотного слоя – 28-32 см. Содержание гумуса – 5-7%, подвижного фосфора – 170-187 мг/кг и обменного калия –177-180 мг/кг. Предшественник – яровая пшеница. Под предшественник вносили минеральные удобрения в дозе N60P60K60. Солома измельчалась и заделывалась при осенней обработке почвы. Норма высева ячменя сорта Эльф 5 млн всхожих семян. Сравнивали 2 фона питания (N54P54K54 и N70Р70К70) и 4 вида гербицидов. Более раннее наступление фенологических фаз растений ячменя наблюдалось в контроле, на делянках без применения удобрений и гербицидов, что можно объяснить с меньшим содержанием питательных веществ в почве,. На более высоком фоне удобрений N70Р70К70, наступление фенологических фаз несколько задерживалось даже по сравнению с фоном, где вносилось удобрение в дозе N54P54K54. Общая засоренность посевов в фазе кущения перед обработкой в среднем за 3 года составила 283 шт./м2. Применение удобрений стимулирует деятельность аммонифицирующей микрофлоры, в результате чего происходит накопление доступных форм минерального азота, необходимых для нормального функционирования жизнедеятельности целлюлозоразлагающих микроорганизмов. С увеличением численности целлюлозоразлагающих микроорганизмов повышается интенсивность распада целлюлозы в почве. К середине вегетации мешковина, выдержанная в почве, разложилась в контроле на 20,3%. На фоне применения гербицидов удобрения в дозе N54P54K54 повысили урожайность зерна ячменя на 0,86-1,13 т/га, а в дозе N70P70K70 – на 1,01-1,25 т/га при урожайности в контроле в среднем за 3 года 1,58 т/га. На обоих фонах внесения удобрений ячмень формировал максимальный урожай при применении гербицида Бомба: при N54P54K54– 2,71 т/га,N70P70K70– 2,83 т/га. Содержание белка в зернена этих вариантах по сравнению с контролем повысилось на 0,54-1,75% при значении показателя в контроле 9,60%.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.vestnik-kazgau.com/images/archive/2015/4/14_korshunov.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Vestnik of Kazan State Agrarian University</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2073-0462</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>