<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2016017046">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Drought impact on wood formation and antioxidant protection of Scots pine cambial zone</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">
      <dcterms:alternative>Действие засухи на формирование древесины и антиоксидантную защиту камбиальной зоны сосны обыкновенной</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Sudachkova N.E.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Romanova L.I.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Milyutina I.L.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2015-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">H01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Pinus sylvestris</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Drought</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">cambium</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">phloem</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Photosynthesis</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Pigments</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Carbohydrates</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Oxidative stress</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Russian Federation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5912</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2391</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1225</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5787</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5812</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_5875</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1300</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_37481</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33240</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The research was realized in 2010-2013 in forest-steppe part of Krasnoyarsk krai. The effect of drought on the 8-9-year-old seedlings of Scots pine (Pinus sylvestris L.) was simulated in the field by isolating trees from the precipitation. The biochemical changes typical of water stress wеre compared with the structural changes of the annual ring of wood. The needle samples of the current and previous years, cambium and adjoining layers of xylem and phloem of stems and roots were analyzed. Chlorophyll a and b and carotenoids contents were determined in the needles. The contents of hydrogen peroxide and malondialdehyde, the activity of antioxidative enzymes: superoxide dismutase (SOD), peroxidase, glutathione reductase and content of sugars and starch were determined in xylem, phloem and cambium. Drought reduces the weight of the needles, the chlorophyll content and the width of the annual wood rings. Under moderate drought oxidative stress was developed in the cambial zone, and also protection system against free radicals was activated, which were resulting in a high SOD activity and the accumulation of hydrogen peroxide due to the activity of peroxidase reduced. The division processes in cambial zone and cells extension growth were inhibited, and the width of annual wood rings decreased due to reduction in the number and size of tracheids. It was found that decrease in growth was not due to deficit of carbohydrates for the process xylogenesis. Water deficit increases the concentration of low molecular weight carbohydrates in the tissues, which due to the inhibition of division and extension cambial derivatives are only partially used for thickening cell wall of tracheid. As a result, abnormal tracheides with reduced size of cells and lumens and thickened cell walls were formed. Abundance of soluble carbohydrates was deposited as are serve pool in the root phloem in the form of starch. The stock function of root phloem was increased under water deficit conditions.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Исследование проводили в лесостепи Красноярского края в 2010-2013 гг. В полевых условиях имитировали влияние засухи на 8-9-летние саженцы сосны обыкновенной Pinus sylvestris L. путем изоляции их от атмосферных осадков. Сопоставляли биохимические изменения, характерные для водного стресса, со структурными изменениями годичного кольца древесины. Анализировали образцы хвои текущего и прошлого годов, прикамбиальные слои ксилемы и флоэмы текущего года и камбий стволов и корней. В хвое определяли содержание хлорофиллов a и b и каротиноидов, а в тканях ксилемы, флоэмы и камбия - пероксида водорода, малонового диальдегида и активность ферментов-антиоксидантов: супероксиддисмутазы (СОД), пероксидазы, глутатионредуктазы, а также содержание сахаров и крахмала. Выявлено, что засуха снижает массу хвоинок, содержание хлорофилла и ширину годичного кольца древесины. В условиях умеренной засухи в камбиальной зоне развивается окислительный стресс и активизируется система защиты от свободных радикалов, что проявляется в высокой активности СОД и накоплении пероксида водорода из-за пониженной активности пероксидазы. В результате ингибировались процессы деления в камбиальной зоне и роста клеток растяжением, что привело к уменьшению ширины годичного кольца вследствие уменьшения числа и размеров трахеид. Установлено, что снижение прироста не связано с недостатком углеводов для процесса ксилогенеза. Водный дефицит повышает концентрацию в тканях низкомолекулярных углеводов, которые лишь частично используются на утолщение клеточной стенки трахеид из-за торможения процессов деления и растяжения камбиальных производных. В результате образуются аномальные трахеиды с уменьшенными размерами клеток и люменов и утолщенными клеточными стенками. Излишки растворимых углеводов откладываются в запас во флоэме корней в виде крахмала. Депонирующая функция флоэмы корней усиливается в условиях водного дефицита.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://goo.gl/TG9u4t</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Siberian Journal of Forest Science</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2311-1410</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v./n.no. 5</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>