<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2016218087">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Assessment of classification methods and evaluation of the potential of coarse   resolution satellite images for forest-cover mapping in the Atlantic bio-geographical region of Europe</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Chania</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:publisher>
      <ags:publisherPlace>Chania (Greece)</ags:publisherPlace>
    </dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2013-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">U40</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Europe</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">imagery</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2724</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_36760</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>Bibliography: p. 57-59 ; ill.</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Forest monitoring is a crucial tool for providing updated data for decision makers, helping them allocate appropriate financial resources for effective forest conservation and management plans. One of these crucial data is Forest Area, which has been selected as one of the 60 indicators for monitoring progress towards the Millennium Development Goals, the 2010 Biodiversity Target and the Global Objectives on Forests. Forest Area and its changes are relatively easy to measure, especially nowadays with the technological progress made in remote sensing fields. This study was conducted before the launching of the PROBA-V satellite. It evaluates forest cover classification methods on the European Atlantic bio-geographical region by applying the Maximum Likelihood (ML), Artificial Neural Network (ANN) and Support Vector Machine (SVM) classification algorithms on simulated PROBA-V, VEGETATION and MODIS data, in order to determine the optimal classification methodology for the region. Landsat TM5, Google Earth and JRC forest cover maps were used to create a reference forest cover map. This map was used for training data generation and for accuracy assessment. The results show that Artificial Neural Network performed the best results, and MODIS with 2-band composition obtained better results. However, the Support Vector Machine classifier performed better with VGT.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://docs.maich.gr/thesis/T000894</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Other</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">en</dc:language>
    <agls:availability>
      <ags:availabilityLocation>T000894</ags:availabilityLocation>
      <ags:availabilityNumber>894/FO/AZ</ags:availabilityNumber>
    </agls:availability>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>