<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2016218497">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">The impact of information technologies on hotel management in terms of sustainable development [Thesis (M.Sc.)]</dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Madoyan Tatevik</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Chania</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:publisher>
      <ags:publisherPlace>Chania (Greece)</ags:publisherPlace>
    </dc:publisher>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">E20</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">tourism</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">information technology</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">management</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">sustainability</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7822</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_36660</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_16086</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33560</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <ags:descriptionNotes>Bibliography: p. 115-136 ; ill.</ags:descriptionNotes>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The purpose of this thesis topic is to identify Greek and Armenian hotel managers and their customers’ attitudes towards IT, to find out the differences between those attitudes, if there are any, and demonstrate whether or not IT influences hotel management and its sustainability. Taking into account the existing environmental issues that, unfortunately, have become an integral part of our lives, a little emphasis has also been placed on the importance of “Green IT” and green practices adopted by hotels, and their customers’ attitudes towards those practices. The necessary data was collected through 2 different questionnaires, designed for hotel managers and hotel customers</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">targeted groups were workers and customers of 4- and 5-star hotels in Greece and Armenia. They were asked to fill in the questionnaires, which were distributed to them via the internet (online questionnaire), emails, or personally. Despite the fact that the whole potential and impact of IT is not used yet, still in this research study many positive impacts on customers’ choice, hotel sustainability and hotel management, in general, have been observed. As the results of the study have shown, IT is crucial both for the hotel industry and its customers. In contrast to this, when it comes to green practices and “Green IT”, the situation changes a bit. Those practices are more developed in Greece, as the study has shown, than in Armenia. One positive thing here is the customers’ willingness and preference for experiencing green practices, hich was proved also by previous research.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://docs.maich.gr/thesis/T000908</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Other</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">en</dc:language>
    <agls:availability>
      <ags:availabilityLocation>T000908</ags:availabilityLocation>
      <ags:availabilityNumber>908/EC/MA</ags:availabilityNumber>
    </agls:availability>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>