<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="BR2016301765">
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">Estimation of leaf area index of banana orchards using the method LAI-LUX</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="pt">
      <dcterms:alternative>Estimativa do índice de área foliar de pomares de bananeira pelo método IAF-LUX</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Guimarães M.J.M.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Coelho Filho M.A.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Peixoto C. P.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Gomes F. A. J.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Oliveira V. V. M.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2013-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Leaf area index</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_35196</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">This paper aimed to compare leaf area index (LAI) from two genotypes banana orchards (Grand
Naine and Tropical) estimated by biometric measurements with the LAI-LUX method. This method is based
on measurements of radiation transmittance using a digital luximeter. There were under and overestimation
of LAI using the LAI-LUX method. The measurements taken on orchards aged over 8 months have shown the
mean relative error of -4.35% related to cultivar Tropical and +2.77% for the Grand Naine. The overall results
revealed the underestimation of results by 3.85% when the ‘Grand Naine’ banana cultivar was analyzed and
overestimation of 6.3% in the case of cultivar ‘Tropical’. These results have shown the potential to the practical
use the method LAI-LUX to estimate LAI in banana orchards but are also necessary to improve the studies in new
orchards (up to 8 months) for better understanding the main sources of error.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="pt">Este trabalho visou comparar o índice de área foliar (IAF) de pomares de bananeira (Musa spp.)
estimados por método envolvendo medidas biométricas de folhas com o método indireto de estimativa IAF-LUX.
Este método baseia-se em leituras de transmitância de luz com uso de um luxímetro digital. Houve tendência
de sub e superestimativas pelo IAF-LUX. Para pomares com idade superior a 8 meses os erros relativos médios
foram -4,35% para cultivar Grand Naine e +2,77% para bananeira Tropical. Em média, houve subestimativa de
3,85% para Grand Naine e superestimativas de 6,3% para a bananeira Tropical. Esses resultados evidenciam a
potencialidade de uso do método IAF-LUX. Estudos mais detalhados deverão ser realizados para aumento da
confiança nos resultados principalmente até os oito meses do plantio.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.ufrb.edu.br/wrim/images/wrim-2-2-2013/v02n02a01.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">en</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.2/n.2</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>