<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="ES2016104773">
    <dc:title xml:lang="es">DINÁMICA DE  POBLACIÓN DE PARÁSITOS GASTROINTESTINALES EN EL NÚCLEO DE PRODUCCIÓN DE PEQUEÑOS RUMIANTES. CENTRO DE PRODUCCIÓN E INVESTIGACIÓN AGROPECUARIA EL CIRUELO – UCC</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>GASTRO-INTESTINAL PARASITICAL POPULATION DYNAMICS IN THE SMALL RUMINANT PRODUCTION NUCLEUS. CENTER OF PRODUCTION AND AGRICULTURAL RESEARCH EL CIRUELO - UCC</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Abril  Mary</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Martínez Daniel</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Vargas Javier</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Castellanos Vilma</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Guerrero Avigdor</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Estudianes Medicina Veterinaria y Zootecnia</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Grupo de investigación en Ciencias Animales, Facultad Medicina Veterinaria y Zootecnia</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Estudianes Medicina Veterinaria y Zootecnia</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Grupo de investigación en Ciencias Animales, Facultad Medicina Veterinaria y Zootecnia</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Grupo de investigación en Ciencias Animales, Facultad Medicina Veterinaria y Zootecnia</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Animal health</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Flotation</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_431</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2986</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The objective was to know the intestinal parasitic dynamics in the creole sheep and goats from the “Centro de Investigación Agropecuaria El Ciruelo de la Universidad Cooperativa de Colombia”. Fifty male and female goats and one hundred male and female mixed short haired sheep constitute the genetic nucleus of the research center. Thirteen sheep and seven goats were randomly selected and sampled every 14 days by 6 times, during the second semester of 2013. Samples consisted of feces, weight record, body condition, rectal temperature, Famacha© test and anti-coagulated blood samples from the jugular vein. The results showed high fecal amounts of Eimeria sp and nematodes. This study achieves a serial track to the ovine and goat nucleus from the research center, showing the infestation risk faced by those animals, associated to clinical measures of decreasing productive efficiency reflected in the zoo-technical parameters for each of the studied species.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="es">El objetivo fue conocer la dinámica de parásitos intestinales en los ovinos y caprinos criollos del Centro Académico Agroindustrial El Ciruelo de la Universidad Cooperativa de Colombia. Cincuenta cabras macho y hembra, y 100 ovejas macho y hembra de pelo corto constituyen el núcleo genético del centro de investigación. Se dispuso de 7 caprinos y 13 ovinos seleccionados al azar y muestreados cada 14 días por 6 tomas en el segundo semestre de 2013. Las muestras consistieron en materia fecal, peso del animal, evaluación de condición corporal, prueba Famacha©</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">sangre con anticoagulante y temperatura rectal. Los resultados arrojaron cargas altas de Eimeria sp y nematodos gastrointestinales. Con este estudio se logró realizar un seguimiento seriado a dicho núcleo</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">donde se seleccionó una muestra representativa de individuos y se midió la carga parasitaria de cada individuo permitiendo correlacionar la carga parasitaria con la condición física y hematológica.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.uco.es/conbiand/aica/templatemo_110_lin_photo/articulos/2014/Trabajo007_AICA2014.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">es</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Actas Iberoamericanas de Conservación Animal</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2253-7325</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.4/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>