<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="ES2016105061">
    <dc:title xml:lang="es">LA GUAJOLOTA, INCUBADORA TRADICIONAL DEL TRASPATIO EN MÉXICO</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>TURKEY HEN</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="">
      <dcterms:alternative>INCUBATOR OF TRADITION IN BACKYARD IN MEXICO</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Camacho Escobar Marco</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Jerez  Martha</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Vázquez-Dávila Marco Antonio</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad del Mar</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Instituto Tecnológico del Valle de Oaxaca</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Instituto Tecnológico del Valle de Oaxaca</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">In order to know how the presence of chickens and turkeys is used to improve production results in backyard farms, this study was conducted. The information presented was obtained from surveys of 1,536 semi structured interviews to backyard poultry farmers in the Central Valleys, Mixteca, Sierra Norte, Cañada, South Sierra, Costa, Papaloapan and Isthmus regions of Oaxaca State. Turkey hens were identified that are appreciated by: ease of broody, ability to build nest, maternal ability, ability to raise another brood of chickens and provide protection to chickens. While hens are appreciated by long periods maintain posture, have early, alert and intelligent chickens, being a species with faster growth than turkeys and rapid sexual maturity. In both species are recognized: their ability to hatch the eggs and reduce disease in other species. In conclusion the turkey hens are prized for their ability to successfully incubate eggs and raise their chicks, while the hens are appreciated for their performance in the production of meat and eggs.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="es">Con la finalidad de conocer la manera en que se aprovecha la presencia de gallinas y guajolotes para mejorar los resultados productivos en las explotaciones de traspatio, se realizó el presente estudio. La información presentada se obtuvo a partir de 1,536 encuestas semi estructuradas realizadas a productores avícolas de traspatio en las regiones Valles Centrales, Mixteca, Sierra Norte, Cañada, Sierra Sur, Costa, Papaloapan e Istmo del estado de Oaxaca. Se identificaron que las guajolotas son apreciadas por: la facilidad de cloequez, habilidad para construir nido, habilidad materna, facilidad para criar pollos de otra nidada y por proveer protección a los pollos. Mientras que las gallinas son apreciadas por: mantener períodos de postura largos, tener pollos precoces, alertas e inteligentes, ser una especie con mayor velocidad de crecimiento que los guajolotes y por una rápida madurez sexual. En ambas especies se reconoce: su capacidad para empolla a los huevos y que reducen las enfermedades en la otra especie. En conclusión las guajolotas son apreciadas por su capacidad de incubar huevos y criar exitosamente a los polluelos, mientras que las gallinas son apreciadas por su desempeño en la producción de carne y huevo.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.uco.es/conbiand/aica/templatemo_110_lin_photo/articulos/2014/Trabajo117_AICA2014.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">es</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Actas Iberoamericanas de Conservación Animal</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2253-7325</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.4/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>