<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="ES2016104775">
    <dc:title xml:lang="es">CABRAS CRIOLLAS Y PEQUEÑOS PRODUCTORES: CAMINOS PARA ELEVAR LA PRODUCTIVIDAD. EXPERIENCIAS DEL PROYECTO CAPRINOS EN COCHABAMBA – BOLIVIA</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>CRIOLLO GOATS AND SMALL HOLDERS: WAYS TO ELEVATE PRODUCTIVITY. EXPERIENCES OF THE GOAT PROJECT IN COCHABAMBA - BOLIVIA</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Stemmer Angelika</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Valle Anne</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad Mayor de San Simón</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad Hohenheim</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Production conditions of the majority of goat holders in Cochabamba, Bolivia, are described. Based on research conducted by the Goat Project since 1994 until today, main results are reported of productive and reproductive capacity of Criollo goats in flocks of small holders and under semi-extensive management in the flock of the Agricultural Faculty. The advantages of Criollo goats for husbandry in marginal regions are described. Proposals are developed for elevating productivity of Criollo goats in the subsistence oriented production system.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="es">Se describen las condiciones de producción de la mayoría de criadores de caprinos en Cochabamba, Bolivia. Con base en investigaciones realizadas por el Proyecto Caprinos, se reportan los principales resultados obtenidos desde 1994 hasta la fecha sobre la aptitud productiva y reproductiva de caprinos Criollos en rebaños de productores a pequeña escala y en manejo semi extensivo en el rebaño de la Facultad de Ciencias Agrícolas y Pecuarias de la UMSS. Se describen las ventajas de las cabras Criollas para la crianza en zonas desfavorecidas. Se desarrollan propuestas para elevar la productividad de las cabras Criollas en el sistema de producción orientado a la subsistencia.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.uco.es/conbiand/aica/templatemo_110_lin_photo/articulos/2014/Trabajo015_AICA2016.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">es</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Actas Iberoamericanas de Conservación Animal</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2253-7325</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.4/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>