<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="ES2016104756">
    <dc:title xml:lang="es">PERROS Y GATOS, GUARDIA Y PROTECCIÓN EN LOS HOGARES INDÍGENAS DE UNA LOCALIDAD CHAMULA (CHIAPAS, MÉXICO)</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>DOGS AND CATS</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="">
      <dcterms:alternative>GARD AND PROTECTION IN INDIGENOUS HOMES FROM A TOWN IN CHAMULA (CHIAPAS</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="">
      <dcterms:alternative>MEXICO)</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Rodríguez Galván Guadalupe</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Reising Carlos</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Zaragoza Lourdes</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Macdonal Hernández José Manuel</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Guevara  Francisco</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad Autónoma de Chiapas</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad Autónoma de Chiapas</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad Autónoma de Chiapas</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad Autónoma de Chiapas</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad Autónoma de Chiapas</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Domestic animals</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_2356</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">In Chamula (Chiapas), the population supports its household economy in integrated small-scale farming, where animals have a important role in everyday Tzotzil life. This research was conducted in the locality of Bechijtic of the municipality of Chamula, between February and May of 2013</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="es">was developed by a community card, a survey of the Production and a semi-structured interview about the family and agricultural organization and the concept and appreciation that Tzotzils have for dogs and cats. The results identified the presence of dogs and cats (89% and 58% respectively) of houses</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">these animals are assumed by the indigenous family as working animals and not as pets, with the task of care and safeguard the house, backyard animals and the family. In conclusion it is stated that the specific conditions of each unit of production and cultural conditions determine that dogs and cats are treated as guardians and not as pets.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">En el municipio tzotzil de Chamula (Chiapas, México) la  población apoya su economía familiar en la agricultura integral a pequeña escala, donde particularmente los animales tienen un papel importante en la cotidianidad tzotzil. El objetivo de este trabajo fue destacar la función de los perros y gatos en la unidad de producción indígena tzotzil. Esta investigación se llevó a cabo en la localidad de Bechijtic del municipio de Chamula, Chiapas, entre febrero y mayo de 2013</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">se desarrolló mediante una cédula comunitaria, una encuesta sobre la Unidad de Producción (composición familiar, labores productivas, economía, cultura y manejo y función de los animales domésticos) y una entrevista semiestructurada sobre la familia y su organización agropecuaria y el concepto y aprecio que los tzotziles tienen por perros y gatos. Los resultados obtenidos identificaron la presencia de perros y gatos en 89% y 58% (respectivamente) de las viviendas</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">éstos son asumidos por la familia indígena como animales de trabajo y no de compañía, con la tarea puntual de cuidar y resguardar la casa, los animales domésticos y a la familia. Como conclusión se plantea que las condiciones específicas de cada unidad de producción y su cultura, condicionan que perros y gatos sean tratados como guardianes y no como compañía.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.uco.es/conbiand/aica/templatemo_110_lin_photo/articulos/2014/Trabajo006_AICA2014.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">es</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Actas Iberoamericanas de Conservación Animal</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2253-7325</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.4/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>