<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="ES2016104924">
    <dc:title xml:lang="es">ALGUNOS ASPECTOS SOCIALES DE LAS GRANJAS OVINAS CRIOLLAS DEL OESTE FORMOSEÑO (ARGENTINA)</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>SOME SOCIAL ASPECTS OF CREOLE SHEEP PRODUCTION OF WEST FORMOSA (ARGENTINA)</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>de la Rosa Carbajal Sebastian</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Revidatti María Antonia</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Orga Antonio</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Tejerina Emilse</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Cappello  Juan</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Pilotti Pablo</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad Nacional del Nordeste - FCV</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad Nacional del Nordeste - FCV</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Centro de Validación de Tecnologías Agropecuarias</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad Nacional del Nordeste - FCV</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad Nacional del Nordeste - FCV</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad Nacional del Nordeste - FCV</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The objective was to characterize social aspects of sheep farms in the west of Formosa, Argentina. Structured interviews (n=82) were conducted at 20 sites uniformly distributed and data were processed using a descriptive analysis. Results show that the typical farmer has a low level of education and belongs to creole ethnic. He usually lives in the farms, although he is not the landowner. It is uncommon the use of technical support and electric supply. The facilities are rudimentary and they are usually shared with goats. The production is mainly devoted to family consumption. These results indicate that sheep activity corresponds to family smallholders, where the social value is very important.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="es">El objetivo fue hacer una aproximación preliminar a aspectos sociales de las granjas ovinas criollas del oeste de la provincia de Formosa, Argentina. Se trabajó en 20 unidades de muestreos distribuidas uniformemente en el territorio, donde se realizaron encuestas estructuradas (n=82), procesando los datos mediante un análisis descriptivo.  Los resultados muestran que el productor tipo pertenece a la etnia criolla, vive en el predio, no posee la tierra que trabaja y tiene un bajo nivel de formación. Predomina la ausencia de asesoramiento técnico y energía eléctrica. Las instalaciones son rudimentarias y compartidas con ganado caprino. La producción se destina principalmente al autoabastecimiento familiar. Los resultados indican que la ganadería ovina corresponde a traspatio de subsistencia, con elevada relevancia social.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.uco.es/conbiand/aica/templatemo_110_lin_photo/articulos/2014/Trabajo078_AICA2014.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">es</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Actas Iberoamericanas de Conservación Animal</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2253-7325</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.4/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>