<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="ES2016104782">
    <dc:title xml:lang="es">EXPERIENCIAS EN LA MEJORA Y CONSERVACIÓN DE LA RAZA CUBANA DE CERDOS CC21</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>EXPERIENCES IN IMPROVING AND CONSERVATION OF CUBAN CC21 PIGS BREED</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Abeledo  Carlos M</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Santana Isabel</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Acuña Naivit</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Hernández Sonia</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Instituto de Investigaciones Porcinas</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Instituto de Investigaciones Porcinas</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Unidad Genetica Porcina el Jigue. Empresa Nacional Genetica Porcina</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Instituto de Investigaciones Porcinas</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">biological diversity</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Genetic improvement</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33950</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_11119</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">In order to expose the Cuban experience in CC21 breed conservation, 24952 records and 27026 genetic pedigrees of the farm "Jigüe", were used. It were studied, physical type, strategies to maintain a healthy genealogical structure and low levels of inbreeding, and also the productive and reproductive traits with SAS, with emphasis on genetic parameters estimation. Traits studded were: final weight (FW), weight for age (WE), average daily gain (ADG) and backfat (BF) to a final age (FA). The reproductive traits were: economic efficiency (EE), litter size at birth (LSB), at 21 days (LS21) and at weaning (LSW) with their respective weights, at birth (WB), 21 days (W21) and weaning (WW) and age at weaning (AW). A simulation analysis was performed from the classic formula of the rate of inbreeding (∆F) at ten years. Genetic progress by calculating genetic trends (GT), were monitored. Was maintained, the existence of the eight lines and pedigree families created since its founding, with never less than 2 boars per line and five sows per family. No hereditary defects occurred</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="es">the annual rate of increase in inbreeding was 0.16% and 0.64% (Cienfuegos) and 0.48% (La Union) for replication centers of CC21 breed. The estimated indexes of heritability were 0.21</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">0.22</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">0.29 y 0.48 for the FW</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">WE</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">ADG and BF, respectively, with values of genetic and environmental correlations means and positive between growth traits and negative with BF. The annual GT increase of 1.88 ± 0.01 g / year for WE and decrease -0.08 ± 0.01 mm / year for BF. Means for growth traits: FW</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">WE</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">ADG and BF were: 94.34 kg</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">451.95 g</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">487 g</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">10.83 mm respectively, with FA of 205 days at selection. The indicators for reproductive traits: EE</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">LSB</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">LS21 and LSW were: 83.35%, 9.44 piglets, 8.41 piglets and 8.40 piglets, respectively, with 1.56 kg (WB), 5.63 kg (W21), 7.35 kg (WW). The WA was 29 days with a viability of 81.96%. Strategies developed in the improvement and conservation of the Cuban breed CC21, have helped to avoid the loss of genetic material.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">Con el objetivo de mostrar la experiencia cubana en la conservación de la raza CC21, se trabajó con la información de 24952 registros y 27026 genealogías de la granja genética El Jigüe. Se abordaron el tipo físico, las estrategias dirigidas a mantener una sana estructura genealógica y niveles bajos de consanguinidad, así como la evaluación productiva y reproductiva vía SAS, con énfasis en la estimación de parámetros genéticos. Se utilizó como rasgos, peso final (PF), peso por edad (PPE), ganancia diaria (GMD) y grasa dorsal (EGD) a una edad final (EF). La parte reproductiva consideró: la eficiencia económica (EE), tamaño de camada al nacer (TCN), 21 días (TC21) y destete (TCD) con sus respectivos pesos, nacer (PN), 21 días (P21) y destete (PD) y edad al destete (ED). Se realizó un análisis de simulación a partir de la fórmula clásica de la tasa de consanguinidad (∆F) a los diez años. Se monitoreó el progreso genético por el cálculo de las tendencias genéticas (TG). Se mantuvo, la existencia de las ocho líneas y familias genealógicas creadas desde su fundación, con nunca menos de 2 verracos por línea y 5 puercas por familia. No se reportó la aparición de defectos hereditarios, la tasa anual del incremento de la consanguinidad fue de 0.16% y 0,64 (Cienfuegos) y 0,48(La Unión) para los centros réplica del CC21. Los índices de herencia estimados fueron 0.21</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">0.22</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">0.29 y 0.48 para el PF</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">PPE</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">GMD y EGD con correlaciones genéticas y ambientales de medias y positivas entre los rasgos de crecimiento y negativas con EGD. Las TG mostraron incremento anual de 1.88±0.01 g/año para PPE y decrecimiento -0.08±0.01 mm/año para EGD. Las medias para los rasgos de crecimiento fueron: 94.34 kg</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">451.95 g</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">487 g</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">10.83 mm para PF</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">PPE</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">GMD y EGD con EF de 205 días a la selección, mientras para los indicadores reproductivos de 83.35%, 9.44 Cab, 8.41 Cab, 8.40 Cab, 1.56 kg, 5.63 kg, 7.35 kg, de EE, TCN, TC21, TCD, PN, P21 y PD, la ED fue de 29 días con una viabilidad del 81.96%. Las estrategias desarrolladas en la mejora y conservación de la raza cubana de cerdos CC21, han permitido evitar la pérdida del material genético.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.uco.es/conbiand/aica/templatemo_110_lin_photo/articulos/2014/Trabajo025_AICA2014.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">es</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Actas Iberoamericanas de Conservación Animal</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2253-7325</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.4/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>