<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="ES2016105065">
    <dc:title xml:lang="es">ANÁLISIS PRELIMINARES DEL CROMOSOMA ”Y”  EN RAZAS DE OVEJAS EXPLOTADAS EN BRASIL</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>PRELIMINARY ANALYSES OF THE Y-CHROMOSOME IN SHEEP BREEDS EXPLOITED IN BRAZIL</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Lara Maria</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Gutmanis Gunta</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Cavalcante-Neto Aderbal</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Bueno  Mauro</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Landi Vincenzo</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Delgado Juan Vicente</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Instituto de Zootecnia</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Instituto de Zootecnia</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Instituto de Zootecnia</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Instituto de Zootecnia</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad de Córdoba</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad de Córdoba</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="es">The chromosome Y is a promising tool for studies of phylogeny, characterization and genetic relationship. We studied the SNP oY1, located in the SRY gene, and microsatellite SRYM18, aiming at the identification of paternal lineages of sheep herds in Sao Paulo, Brazil. There were investigated 45 sheep from Instituto de Zootecnia (IZ) (Ile de France, Morada Nova, Poll Dorset, Santa Inês and Suffolk breed), and 15 lambs from private properties (Dorper, Santa Inês and Texel breed). The SNP oY1 was investigated by PCR/RFLP technique and the SRYM18 was genotyped by the ABI3130, using the GeneMapper. From the seven haplotypes described for Ovis aries, four have been identified, as well as a new one, characterized as allele G (SNP oY1) and 141 (SRYM18). This haplotype was observed in nine lambs of IZ (1 Ile de France, 6 Poll Dorset and 2 Suffolk). The haplotypes H3 (A/139) and H5 (G/145) were observed only in the Suffolk and Texel flocks, and the H6 (A/143) in the herds Dorper and Morada Nova flocks. The H8 occurred in all herds, although it was fixed in Santa Inês. On the other hand, the frequency of this haplotype ranged between 14% (Poll Dorset and Texel) and 75% (Ile de France and Morada Nova) and in Suffolk, the frequency was 50%. The results showed that the Santa Inês flock descends from a single lineage. Other herds and increased sampling will be investigated later, once this work is part of a broader BIOVIS project of the Red CONBIAND.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">El cromosoma Y por ser exclusivamente herencia paterna, es una herramienta prometedora principalmente en estudios de filogenia, caracterización y relación genética. Se estudiaron el SNP oY1, situado en la región promotora del gen SRY y el microsatélite SRYM18, con el objetivo de la identificación de linajes paternos en rebaños de razas de ovejas explotables en São Paulo, Brasil. Se investigaron 45 corderos de los rebaños del Instituto Zootecnia (IZ) y 15 corderos de propiedades privadas. Las muestras del IZ, recogidos entre 1999 y el 2014, eran de la raza Ile de France (N = 4), Morada Nova (N = 4), Poll Dorset (N = 7), Santa Inês (N = 20) y Suffolk (N = 10) y de los particulares, Dorper (N = 3), Santa Inês (N = 5) y Texel (N = 7). El SNP oY1 (AY 604734.2) fue investigado por la técnica de PCR/RFLP. El SRYM18 (DQ272456) fue genotipado en el ABI3130, utilizando el GeneMapper. De los siete haplotipos descritos para Ovis aries, cuatro han sido identificados, así como uno nuevo, caracterizado por los alelos G (SNP oY1) y 141 (SRYM18). Este haplotipo se observó en nueve corderos del IZ (1 Ile de France, 6 Poll Dorset y 2 Suffolk). Los haplotipos H3 (A/139) y H5 (G/145) fueron observados solamente en rebaños Sulffolk y Texel y el H6 (A/143), en rebaños Dorper y Morada Nova. Por el contrario, el H8 ocurrió en todos los rebaños, aunque estaba fijado en Santa Inês. En el otro, la frecuencia de este haplotipo osciló entre el 14% (Poll Dorset y Texel) y el 75% (Ile de France y Morada Nova) y, en Suffolk, la frecuencia fue 50%. Los resultados obtenidos muestran que el rebaño Santa Inês analizado desciende de un único linaje. Teniendo en cuenta los informes de la literatura sobre la variabilidad de esta raza, se pretende aumentar la toma de muestras en otros rebaños. Además, la variabilidad observada en los rebaños restantes será investigada en nuevos estudios, teniendo en cuenta que este trabajo forma parte de un proyecto más amplio, que es una iniciativa coordinada con el consorcio BIOVIS de la Red CONBIAND.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.uco.es/conbiand/aica/templatemo_110_lin_photo/articulos/2014/Trabajo123_AICA2014.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">es</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Actas Iberoamericanas de Conservación Animal</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2253-7325</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.4/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>