<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="ES2016104975">
    <dc:title xml:lang="es">LA BIODIVERSIDAD Y LA GASTRONOMÍA ORIENTADAS AL TURISMO</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>BIODIVERSITY AND GASTRONOMY GEARED TO TOURISM</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Casanova  Elisabeth</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Mazó María Lyssette</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Zaragoza Lourdes</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad Popular de la Chontalpa</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad Popular de la Chontalpa</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad Autónoma de Chiapas</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">food security</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_10967</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The conservation of animal genetic resources is closely linked to its use. Biodiversity includes animals that live in a certain place, their genetic variability, ecosystems where they develop and landscapes. However, prevailing ecosystems are very delicate and are threatened by urbanization and over-utilization of resources. The southeast region of Mexico is predominantly tropical, so its wealth of flora, fauna and landscapes is wide and varied, in addition to the cultural richness of this region that hosted the first prehispanic culture of the country, are these factors that give regional cuisine with a unique character and great tourism potential. The objective of this study was to assess the consumption profile of dishes from local fauna, particularly of freshwater turtles on the farm "La Encantada" of the the municipality of Jalpa de Méndez, Tabasco. The study was conducted by applying techniques and tools of qualitative research. At the end of the study it was concluded that consumers are local and unaccustomed to eating these dishes in the newer generations is observed Therefore an outreach program of sustainable consumption of turtles is necessary to maintain species based on their use, conserve cultural aspects linked to this practice and increasing tourism demand in the area.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="es">La conservación de los recursos zoogenéticos está íntimamente ligada a la utilización de los mismos. La biodiversidad incluye animales que viven en un sitio,  su variabilidad genética, los ecosistemas de los cuales forman parte estas especies y los paisajes. Sin embargo, los ecosistemas que prevalecen son muy delicados y están siendo amenazados por la urbanización y la sobreutilización de los recursos. La región sureste de México es predominantemente tropical, por lo que su riqueza de flora, fauna y paisajes es amplia y variada, aunada a la riqueza cultural que sitúa a esta región como sede de la primera cultura prehispánica del país, son estos factores los que dan a la gastronomía regional un carácter único y con un gran potencial turístico. El objetivo de este estudio fue reconocer el perfil de consumo de platillos a partir de fauna local, específicamente de tortugas dulceacuícolas en la granja “La Encantada” del municipio de Jalpa de Méndez, Tabasco. El estudio se realizó mediante la aplicación de técnicas e instrumentos de investigación cualitativa. Al término del estudio se concluye que los consumidores son locales y se observa la  falta de costumbre de consumo de estos platillos en las generaciones más nuevas, por lo anterior es necesario un programa de difusión del consumo sustentable  de los quelonios, a fin de mantener a las especies con base a su utilización, conservar aspectos culturales ligados a esta práctica y aumentar demanda turística en la zona.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.uco.es/conbiand/aica/templatemo_110_lin_photo/articulos/2014/Trabajo101_AICA2014.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">es</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Actas Iberoamericanas de Conservación Animal</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2253-7325</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.4/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>