<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="ES2016104920">
    <dc:title xml:lang="es">DILUCIONES COMO MÉTODO DE CONSERVACIÓN DE SEMEN DEL GÉNERO Crotalus</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>DILUTIONS AS CONSERVATRION METHOD FOR SEMEN GENRE Crotalus</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Fuentes-Mascorro Gisela</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Alvarez Agustín</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Bautista Medel Mayra</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Girón Gutiérrez Dioseline</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Ramírez Acevedo Luz</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad Autónoma Benito Juárez de Oaxaca</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Herpetario Reptilium Zacango Estado de México</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad Autónoma Benito Juárez de Oaxaca</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad Autónoma Benito Juárez de Oaxaca</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad Autónoma Benito Juárez de Oaxaca</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">reptile</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Spermatozoa</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_6511</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_7287</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Rattlesnakes are in danger of extinction, so for preservation and fabotherapics manufacturer, captivity specimens are important. In zoos collections some species, male and female are aloof. Used as conservation semen methods dilution and freezing. Was used an no invasive method for ejaculate, males of C. atrox, C. basiliscus, C. culminatus, C. molossus nigrescens, C molosus oaxacus, C. ravus C., and C. C.simus scutulatus. They are captive in Reptilium herpetarium in controlled environment. Scale to 0 to 5 was used to evaluate gross ejaculate motility. The ejaculated was incubate to 28ºC, cloacal temperature of this animals. Gross ejaculate motility was evaluated every 30 minutes. Modified diluent Tyrode maintains gross ejaculate motvility in 2 for 6 hours, in all genera. Tyrode diluent maintains gross ejaculate motility in 1 by 90 minutes, in all genera. Acromax was unable maintains any kind of motility. In C molossus nigrescens, Magapor diluent maintain gross ejaculate motility in one for 90 minutes. In C atrox MR-A diluent maintain gross ejaculate motility in 1 for 3 hours. In C atrox Brackett diluent, maintain gross ejaculate motility in 2 for 90 minutes. Freezing was not possible because stop moving sperm with egg yolk. Rattlesnakes are able to ejaculate without everting hemipenes, after being stimulated manually. It is possible to transport the semen of these animals until to six hours in modified Tyrode.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="es">Las serpientes de cascabel están en peligro de extinción, por lo que para su preservación y la fabricación de faboterápicos los especímenes en cautiverio son importantes. En las colecciones de los zoológicos algunas especies tienen a las hembras y machos muy lejos uno de otro. El objetivo del trabajo fue emplear la dilución y la congelación como métodos de conservación del semen. Se empleó un método no invasivo para eyacular a los machos de C. atrox, C. basiliscus, C. culminatus, C molossus nigrescens, C molosus oaxacus, C ravus y C. simus. Los ejemplares se encuentran en el herpetario Reptilium en un ambiente controlado. Se empleó una escala de 0 a 5 para evaluar la movilidad masal del eyaculado. Los eyaculados fueron incubados a 28ºC, que es la temperatura cloacal de los ejemplares en este lugar. La movilidad masal fue evaluada cada 30 minutos. El diluyente Tyrode modificado mantuvo la movilidad masal de dos a seis horas, en todos los géneros. El diluyente Tyrode mantuvo la movilidad masal de los eyaculados de uno a 90 minutos, en todos los géneros. Aceromas fue incapaz de mantenr algún tipo de movilidad. En C molossus nigrescens, el diluyente Magapor mantuvo la movilidad masal en eyaculado de uno a 90 minutos. En C. atrox, el diluyente MR-A mantiene la movilidad masal de una a 3 horas. En C. atrox, el diluyente Brackett mantiene la movilidad masal del eyaculado de 2 a 90 minutos. La congelación no fue posible porque la yema de huevo detiene el movimiento de los espermatozoides. Las serpientes de cascabel son capaces de eyacular después de ser estimuladas manualmente sin evertir los hemipenes. Es posible transportar el semen de estos animales hasta por seis horas con diluyente Tyrode modificado.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.uco.es/conbiand/aica/templatemo_110_lin_photo/articulos/2014/Trabajo073_AICA2014.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">es</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Actas Iberoamericanas de Conservación Animal</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2253-7325</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.4/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>