<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="ES2016104981">
    <dc:title xml:lang="es">ESTUDIO ECONÓMICO DEL MANTENIMIENTO DE UN BANCO DE GERMOPLASMA ANIMAL</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>GERMPLASM BANK MAINTENANCE ECONOMICAL STUDY</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Gómez Mayra</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Arando Ander</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Nogales Sergio</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Camacho María Esperanza</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Pizarro Gabriela</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Miranda  Judith</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Navas Francisco</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Miró María</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad de Córdoba</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad de Córdoba</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad de Córdoba</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>IFAPA. Centro Alameda del Obispo</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad de Córdoba</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad de Córdoba</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad de Córdoba</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad de Córdoba</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Genetic resources</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Land races</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3218</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4177</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Animal genetic resources ex situ conservation is an essential and complementary tool to in situ conservation. It is one of the main procedures for population recovery. The aim of this study was to calculate and to break down the cost, determining criopreserved seminal doses annual maintenance expenses by species. During the study, the costs of two maintenance methods, on one hand kept under self-maintenance and on the other hand by means of hiring an outside maintenance service, were compared for the following species: cattle, goats, sheep, pigs and equines. The studied items to determine expenses were: nitrogen costs, labour costs, travelling costs, safety and environmental fees and the expenses generated by the hire of an external service. A Breaking down of expenses shows an 85.4% value due to nitrogen costs, 8.6% shared between safety and environmental fees, a 5.5% concerning labour costs, and a 0.4% related to travelling expenses. The self-maintenance cost for stored dose and species is 0.083 €/year for cattle, sheep or goats</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="es">0.99 €/year for pigs and 1.32 €/year for equines. In the external maintenance service case, the cost for cattle, sheep or goats is 0.1499 €/year, a 1.6799 €/year for pigs and a 2.2399 €/year for equines.  The cost per each 0.25 ml stored straw involves 0.083 €/year for self-maintenance and a 0.14€/year for the external service hire, while 0.50 ml ones represent 0.17 €/year for self-maintenance and 0.28 €/year for external maintenance hire. In conclusion, self-maintenance is the cheapest way to keep an animal germplasm bank in this case. When it comes time to allocate a certain economic item to develop a germplasm bank is imperative to consider which is the species that we work with.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">La conservación ex situ de los recursos genéticos animales es una herramienta indispensable y complementaria a la conservación in situ. En razas ganaderas autóctonas en peligro de extinción es una de las principales vías para una recuperación de la población. El objetivo de este trabajo fue calcular y desglosar el coste, determinando los gastos para el mantenimiento anual de cada dosis seminal almacenada por especie. Durante el estudio se comparó el coste de dos métodos de mantenimiento: el auto-mantenimiento y la contratación de un servicio externo de mantenimiento, para las siguientes especies: bovino, caprino, ovino, porcino  y equino. Las partidas estudiadas para determinar el gasto fueron: el coste del nitrógeno, la mano de obra, coste del desplazamiento, cuota de seguridad y medioambiente y gasto generado por la contratación del servicio. Desglosando el gasto se observa que el 85,4% es generado por el coste de nitrógeno, el 8,6 % cuota seguridad y medioambiente, 5,5 % mano de obra y 0,4% gasto de desplazamiento. El coste del auto-mantenimiento por dosis almacenada y especie es de 0,083€/año para bovino, ovino, caprino</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">0,99€/año para porcino y de 1,32 €/año en equino. En el caso del servicio externo de mantenimiento, el coste es de 0,14€/año para bovino, ovino, caprino</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">1,67€/año para porcino y de 2,23 €/año en equino. El coste por pajuela almacenada con capacidad de 0,25 ml supone un gasto de 0,083€/año para el auto-mantenimiento y de 0,14€/año para el servicio externo, mientras que las de 0,50 ml, suponen 0,17€/año para el auto-mantenimiento y 0,28€/año contratando el servicio externo de mantenimiento. En conclusión, el auto-mantenimiento es la manera más económica de mantener un banco de germoplasma animal en este caso, mientras que a la hora de destinar una partida económica para desarrollar un banco de germoplasma es imprescindible tener en cuenta la especie con la que se trabaja.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.uco.es/conbiand/aica/templatemo_110_lin_photo/articulos/2014/Trabajo102_AICA2014.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">es</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Actas Iberoamericanas de Conservación Animal</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2253-7325</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.4/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>