<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="ES2016104783">
    <dc:title xml:lang="es">GESTIÓN DE 20 AÑOS EN LA CONSERVACIÓN DEL CERDO CRIOLLO CUBANO</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>MANAGEMENT OF 20 YEARS IN CONSERVATION CUBAN CREOLE PIG</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Abeledo  Carlos M</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Santana Isabel</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Ly Julio</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Instituto de Investigaciones Porcinas</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Instituto de Investigaciones Porcinas</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Instituto de Ciencia Animal</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">biological diversity</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_33950</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">In order to evaluate 20 years of work to development Cuban Creole pig from Iberian origin, the results of the productive and reproductive performance, characterization and levels of inbreeding in this population, are shown. Information from 1993-2006 (4978 pigs) and 2009-2013 (2357 pigs) of San Pedro genetic farm, was used. Productive performance data were processed by SAS, while genetic parameters and levels of inbreeding were estimated from MTDFREML ENDOG. The average age at first conception was 297.1 days, 8 piglets born alive and 13.37 kg at birth. The means for growth traits: final weight (FW) and weight by age (WA) and fat thickness (BF), at 216 days, were: 67.19 kg, 311.06 g, 43.63 mm respectively. Heritability of FW and WA was 0.25 and 0.17 for BF. This pig has skin color and black coat, high variability in the presence of hair, in two basic types, hairless or little hair, the size is medium and fat, mucosal pigmented, medium ears, subconcave profile and dorsal back line straight or slightly arched. Wattles presence was low (13.7%), as well as helmet Mule (10.3%). Sows per boar ratio were 10 to 1 obtaining 2 births per sow per year. Genealogically, there are 10 maternal families and 4 parental lines. The actual strategy is incorporating new lines from the center preserves gene pool. The average inbreeding (Fx) and the rate of inbreeding (∆F) by whole generation were: 1.74% and 1.42%, showing a population with a high level of genetic variability. It was concluded that conservation strategies established have achieved to preserve for more than 20 years this breed in Cuba. Good genetic work was confirmed, where levels of inbreeding show a healthy increase, due to the work of mating between families and genealogical lines, plus the introduction of genes from other Creole populations.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="es">Con el objetivo de evaluar el trabajo de 20 años de gestión en el desarrollo para la conservación del cerdo criollo Cubano de origen Ibérico. Se muestran los resultados del comportamiento productivo y reproductivo, caracterización y niveles de endogamia de esta población. Se utilizó la información desde 1993-2006 (4978 cerdos) y del 2009-2013 (2357 cerdos) de la unidad genética San Pedro. Los datos comportamiento fueron procesados por SAS, mientras los parámetros genéticos y niveles de endogamia se estimaron a partir del MTDFREML y ENDOG. La edad promedio a la primera concepción fue de 297.1 días, con 8 crías nacidas vivas y 13.37 kg de peso al nacer. Las medias para los rasgos de crecimiento y espesor de grasa fueron 67.19 kg, 311.06 g, 43.63 mm y 216 días para el peso final (PF), peso por edad (PPE), grasa dorsal (GD) y edad a la selección (ES).  La heredabilidad del PF y PPE fue 0.25 y 0.17 para la GD. Se describe este cerdo con piel y color de capa negra, gran variabilidad en la presencia de pelo con dos tipos fundamentales, lampiño o entrepelado de tamaño mediano y tipo graso, mucosas pigmentadas, orejas medianas, perfil subcóncavo y línea dorso lumbar recta o ligeramente arqueada. La presencia mamelas fue baja (13,7%), así como de Casco de Mulo (10,3%). La proporción puercas por verraco fue de 10 a 1 con  la obtención de 2 partos por puerca por año. Genealógicamente se contó con más de 10 familias maternas y 4 líneas paternas siendo estrategia la  incorporación de nuevas líneas al centro proveniente de los cotos de reserva genética. La consanguinidad media (Fx) y la tasa de consanguinidad (∆F) por generación completa fueron de 1,74% y 1,42%, demostrando una población con un buen nivel de variabilidad genética y consanguinidad. Se concluyó que las estrategias establecidas de conservación han logrado preservar por más de 20 años esta raza en Cuba. Se confirmó el buen trabajo genético, donde los niveles de endogamia muestran un sano incremento, dado al trabajo de apareamiento entre líneas y familias genealógicas, además de la introducción de genes de otras poblaciones criollas.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.uco.es/conbiand/aica/templatemo_110_lin_photo/articulos/2014/Trabajo026_AICA2014.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">es</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Actas Iberoamericanas de Conservación Animal</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2253-7325</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.4/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>