<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="ES2016104908">
    <dc:title xml:lang="es">LA MUJER EN LA COMERCIALIZACIÓN DEL GUAJOLOTE (Melleagris gallopavo L.) EN LOS MERCADOS DE LOS VALLES CENTRALES DE OAXACA</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>WOMEN IN TURKEY (Melleagris gallopavo L.) MARKETING IN THE MARKETS OF VALLES CENTRALES OF OAXACA</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Angel  Arturo</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Jerez  Martha</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Camacho Escobar Marco</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Vázquez-Dávila Marco Antonio</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Villegas  Yuri</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Ortiz Gerardo</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>División de Estudios de Posgrado e Investigación, Instituto Tecnológico del Valle de Oaxaca</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>División de Estudios de Posgrado e Investigación, Instituto Tecnológico del Valle de Oaxaca</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Instituto de Industrias. Universidad del Mar</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>División de Estudios de Posgrado e Investigación, Instituto Tecnológico del Valle de Oaxaca</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>División de Estudios de Posgrado e Investigación, Instituto Tecnológico del Valle de Oaxaca</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>División de Estudios de Posgrado e Investigación, Instituto Tecnológico del Valle de Oaxaca</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">marketing</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_4620</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">In the rural areas  of Mexico, the family labor is used to develop several productive activities. Among the many tasks performed by women, the marketing of agricultural products generates complementary economic resources for the family. The aim was to investigate women participation in the turkey (Melleagris gallopavo) marketing in the local markets of the region of Valles Centrales of Oaxaca, Mexico. During 2014, seven local markets in the region were visited</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="es">these places are called "Baratillos or market day" where a specific week-day domestic animals and farm products are marketed. Seventy interviews to turkey sellers-buyers were realized by selected way. Generic and age people and their productive activity, production system and marketing details were included. Data were analyzed by testing independence of Ji-Square (p = 0.05). Over 60% of respondents were women engaged in market turkeys. Housework are major activities that women do (50%), which complement with turkey marketing produced entirely by family backyard system. Productive activity or occupation, and the role of people in turkey marketing is dependent on the genre (p ≤ 0.0079). The reasons for market the turkey are dependent on the age of the people (p = 0.05), whose productive age is the most important.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">En las zonas rurales  de México se utiliza la mano de obra familiar para desarrollar diversas actividades productivas. Dentro de las múltiples tareas realizadas por la mujer, la compra-venta de productos agropecuarios funciona como actividad complementaria de recursos económicos para la familia. El objetivo fue conocer la participación de las mujeres en la comercialización del guajolote (Melleagris gallopavo) en los mercados locales de la región de los Valles Centrales de Oaxaca. México. Durante los meses de enero-mayo del 2014, se visitaron siete mercados locales de la región llamados “Baratillos o días de plaza”, donde un día específico de la semana se comercializan animales domésticos de trabajo y productos agrícolas. Se realizaron 70 entrevistas a vendedores-compradores de estas aves, los cuales fueron seleccionados de manera dirigida. Se incluyeron datos genéricos y edad de las personas, así como su actividad productiva, sistema de producción y detalles de la comercialización. La información fue analizada mediante pruebas de independencia de Ji-Cuadrada (p = 0.05). Más de 60% de los entrevistados fueron mujeres que se dedican a comercializar pavos. Las labores del hogar son actividades principales que las mujeres realizan (50%), la cuales complementan con la comercialización del guajolote producido totalmente en un sistema de traspatio familiar. La actividad productiva u ocupación, así como el papel de las personas en la comercialización del pavo es dependiente del género de las mismas (p ≤ 0.0079). Las razones para comercializar el guajolote son dependientes de la edad de las personas (p = 0.05), cuya edad productiva es la de mayor importancia.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.uco.es/conbiand/aica/templatemo_110_lin_photo/articulos/2014/Trabajo059_AICA2014.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">es</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Actas Iberoamericanas de Conservación Animal</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2253-7325</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.4/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>