<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="ES2016104944">
    <dc:title xml:lang="es">EFECTO DEL ACABADO EN LA CALIDAD NUTRICIONAL DE LA GRASA DE LA CARNE DE CORDEROS DE RAZA OVELLA GALEGA</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>EFFECT OF THE FEEDING SYSTEMS ON THE MEAT FAT NUTRITIONAL QUALITY FROM LAMBS OF "OVELLA GALEGA" BREED</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Adán Silvia</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Moreno Teresa</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>García-Fontán Mª Camino</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Domínguez Bernardino</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Cachaldora Aida</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Arias Anisia</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>García Gloria</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Gómez María</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Fernández  Miguel</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Justo José Ramón</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Federación de Razas Autóctonas de Galicia (BOAGA)</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Fundación Centro Tecnológico de la Carne</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Fundación Centro Tecnológico de la Carne</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Instituto Ourensán de Desenvolvemento Económico (INORDE)</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Fundación Centro Tecnológico de la Carne</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Federación de Razas Autóctonas de Galicia (BOAGA)</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Fundación Centro Tecnológico de la Carne</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Fundación Centro Tecnológico de la Carne</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Fundación Centro Tecnológico de la Carne</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Federación de Razas Autóctonas de Galicia (BOAGA)</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Ovella Galega is a Galician autochthonous sheep breed, classified as danger of extinction breed. It is reared using the natural pasture resources. This kind of sheep breed is directed for meat production. In the present study, 20 male lambs from simple births were used. They were reared with their mothers on pasture and were allowed to suckle freely for 45 days when two groups of animals were made: extensive, they were reared on pasture with their mothers until being slaughtered, and semiextensive, they were fed indoors with concentrate and kept suckling their mothers at night</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="es">both groups were slaughtered at 4 months of age.The different finishing feeding systems (extensive vs semiextensive) had been studied on the intramuscular fat lipid profile, from a fat sample of Longissimusdorsi. of each animal was analyzed with an Agilent 6890N GC equipped with a FID detector and a silica capillary column (100m, 0.25mm i.d., 0.2 μm, Supelco). Intramuscular adipose tissue was extracted from homogenized muscle as described by Folch et al. (1957) and converted into FA methyl esters (FAME) by transesterification Shehata et al. (1970). Data were analyzed by ANOVA using the SPSS 15.0 program. The results showed that the different finishing feeding systems had a significant effect on the meat fatty acid profile. Animals reared in an extensive system showed higher percentage of omega-3 (1,35 vs 0,87, p</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">La Ovella Galega, raza ovina autóctona de Galicia catalogada como raza en peligro de extinción, se cría aprovechando los recursos naturales del campo y con una orientación cárnica en su producción. Para este estudio se utilizaron 20 corderos machos procedentes de partos simples y de una explotación, alimentados sólo con leche materna los primeros 45 días. Posteriormente se establecieron dos grupos hasta los 4 meses de edad: lote de extensivo suplementado con pasto, lote de semiextensivo suplementado con concentrado, ambos lotes recibieron hierba seca ad líbitum. Se estudió el efecto del tipo de acabado (extensivo vs semiextensivo) sobre el perfil lipídico de la grasa intramuscular del Longissimus dorsi, mediante GC con detección FID en un Agilent 6890N y con una columna capilar de sílice (100m, 0.25mm i.d., 0.2 μm, Supelco). Los métodos de extracción y transesterificación de la grasa de la carne fueron Folch et al. (1957) y el modificado de Shehata et al. (1970), respectivamente. Para el análisis estadístico de los datos se realizó un ANOVA con el programa SPSS 15.0. Los resultados mostraron que el tipo de acabado tuvo un efecto significativo en el perfil de ácidos grasos de la grasa intramuscular. La carne de los corderos criados a pasto, mostró mayor porcentaje de ácidos grasos omega 3 (1,35 vs 0,87, p</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.uco.es/conbiand/aica/templatemo_110_lin_photo/articulos/2014/Trabajo091_AICA2014.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">es</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Actas Iberoamericanas de Conservación Animal</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2253-7325</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.4/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>