<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="ES2016104894">
    <dc:title xml:lang="es">ESTUDIO DE LA CURVA DE CRECIMIENTO DE RICHARDS EN UN CRUCE ENTRE PORCINOS DUROC X CERDO CELTA</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>STUDY OF THE RICHARDS GROWTH CURVE IN THE DUROC PIG CROSSBRED WITH CELTA</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Iglesias Antonio</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Carril Jose</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Fernández  Miguel</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Rodríguez Iván Manuel</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Perez Cesar</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Lorenzo  José</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Franco Daniel</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Departamento de Anatomía y Producción Animal. Facultad de Veterinaria</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>ASOPORCEL</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Fundación Centro Tecnológico de la Carne</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>ASOPORCEL</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>ASOPORCEL</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Fundación Centro Tecnológico de la Carne</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Fundación Centro Tecnológico de la Carne</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The knowledge of the models of growth and development in pigs allows to evaluate the management of the nutrition. These models are useful for technical personnel and pig breeders. The aim of this work was to study the Richards growth curve in Duroc pig crossbreed with Celta breed. A total of 16 pigs of Duroc x Celta were employed. Feeding rations that were provided to the animals were those conventionally used in the area, and they were formulated according to the nutrient requirements for each of the phases of growth and finishing of animals. Pigs were weighed individually each month and estimation of the growth model parameters was performed using the program GCFIT (statistical package SIMFIT version 6.0.). The R2 statistic obtained was 0.97, indicating a good fit between experimental and theoretical data. Statistical Durbin-Watson adjusted data for this model resulted in 1,523 for a significance level of 0.05 without showing serial autocorrelation between the estimated residuals. Therefore it can be concluded that the Richards model allows described acceptably the growth of the crossing Duroc x Celta.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="es">El conocimiento del crecimiento y del desarrollo del ganado porcino, es necesario tanto desde la perspectiva del técnico como de la del ganadero, pues su control permite que el manejo nutricional de los animales pueda ser dirigido adecuadamente. El objetivo de este trabajo fue estudiar la curva de crecimiento de Richards en cruces de cerdo Duroc con Celta. Un total de 16 cerdos de raza Celta cruzados con Duroc fueron empleados. Las raciones que se les proporcionaron a los animales fueron las utilizadas tradicionalmente en la zona, siendo formuladas según los requerimientos en nutrientes para cada una de las fases de crecimiento y acabado de los animales. Los cerdos fueron pesados individualmente en báscula cada mes y la estimación de los parámetros del modelo de crecimiento fue realizada mediante el programa GCFIT del paquete estadístico SIMFIT versión 6.0. El estadístico R2 obtenido fue de 0,97, lo que indica un buen ajuste entre los datos experimentales y los teóricos. El test estadístico de Durbin-Watson para los datos ajustados a este modelo dio como resultado 1,523 para un nivel de significación de 0,05, no presentando autocorrelación serial entre los residuos estimados. Por lo tanto se puede concluir que el modelo de Richards permitió describir aceptablemente el crecimiento del cruce Duroc x Celta.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.uco.es/conbiand/aica/templatemo_110_lin_photo/articulos/2014/Trabajo045_AICA2014.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">es</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Actas Iberoamericanas de Conservación Animal</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2253-7325</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.4/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>