<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="ES2016104953">
    <dc:title xml:lang="es">LOS PATOS (ANATIDAE): RECURSO ZOOGENÉTICO DE LOS GRUPOS ÉTNICOS DEL SURESTE DE MÉXICO</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang=" ">
      <dcterms:alternative>DUCKS (ANATIDAE): A ZOOGENETIC RESOURCE OF SOUTHEAST MEXICO’S ETHNIC GROUPS</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Vázquez-Dávila Marco</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Camacho Escobar Marco</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Jerez  Martha</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Villegas  Yuri</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Instituto Tecnológico del Valle de Oaxaca</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Universidad del Mar</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Instituto Tecnológico del Valle de Oaxaca</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Instituto Tecnológico del Valle de Oaxaca</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Anas</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_8786</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">We inquire the role of ducks as animal zoogenetic resource in nine ethnic groups of Southeast Mexico through case studies. We conducted fieldwork on ducks’ traditional breeding with Chontals, Huaves, Mazatecs, Mixes, Triquis and Zapotec people from Oaxaca, Choles and Lacandon from Chiapas and with Chontals from Tabasco. In mixed flocks of indigenous backyards, where live together chickens, turkeys, ducks and other birds, we recognized at least two species of ducks (Anas platyrhynchos domesticus, and Cairina moschata domestica), and sporadic breeding of Dendrocygna autumnalis y Anas acuta. A remarkable fact is the empirical observation (effectiveness ascertained by local connoisseurs) of the transmission of the resistance of the ducks to the other species of birds against diseases called locally as mal aire (bad air) or peste (pest), hence their presence, importance and persistence in ethno-aviculture.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="es">Se indagó el papel de los patos como recurso zoogenético en nueve grupos étnicos del Sureste de México mediante estudios de caso. Se realizó trabajo de campo sobre la cría de patos entre los chontales, huaves, mazatecos, mixes, triquis y zapotecos de Oaxaca</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">choles y lacandones de Chiapas y chontales de Tabasco. En las parvadas mixtas de los traspatios indígenas, donde conviven gallinas, guajolotes, patos y otras aves, se reconocieron al menos dos especies de patos domésticos (Anas platyrhynchos domesticus y Cairina moschata domestica) así como la cría esporádica de Dendrocygna autumnalis y Anas acuta. Un hecho notable es la observación empírica (e.g., de efectividad comprobada in situ por los conocedores locales) de la trasmisión -del pato hacia las otras especies- de resistencia ante enfermedades denominadas localmente como mal aire o peste y de ahí su presencia, importancia y persistencia en la etnoavicultura.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.uco.es/conbiand/aica/templatemo_110_lin_photo/articulos/2014/Trabajo097_AICA2014.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">es</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Actas Iberoamericanas de Conservación Animal</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2253-7325</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.4/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>