<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="ES2016104784">
    <dc:title xml:lang="es">ESTRATEGIAS Y RESULTADOS DEL GRUPO CUBANO CERCRI, PARA LA CONSERVACION DEL CERDO CRIOLLO CUBANO</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>STRATEGIES AND RESULTS OF CERCRI GROUP FOR CUBAN CREOLE PIG CONSERVATION</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Santana Isabel</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Ly Julio</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Silva Olímpia</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Abeledo  Carlos M</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Instituto de Investigaciones Porcinas</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Instituto de Ciencia Animal</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Instituto Federal de Educação, Ciência e Tecnologia Baiano</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Instituto de Investigaciones Porcinas</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">protection</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_330896</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Cuban Group for the Protection of Creole Pigs (CERCRI.Cu) was formed in 2010. Group objectives of the group have been aimed at promoting Sites of genetic reservoir (CRG)</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="es">strengthen and improve the breeding and conservation efforts on them and evaluate local sustainability initiatives, towards Cuban Creole pig’s effective conservation. This paper exposed the study by the CERCRI.Cu, in January 2011- April 2014 period. Specialists, researchers, professors and producers are in the groups created in 14 provincial Pigs Societies. CERCRI.cu The group has applied two basic strategies, the effective lifting of the Creoles and the CRG and any Creole core and the development of actions and Awareness Training. These strategies were channeled through movement Workshops Creole pig</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">four of which were conducted 2011 -2014 and whose development an action group were derived. These actions highlight the need to improve both the direction and control of the formation and operation of the CRG. The number of these doubled 2010 - 2014 (48 of 24). Inventory and certification of existing in CRG is an example. It also raised the need to simplify and make more convenient actual Handbook. CERCRI.Cu management during the period was successful, leading to the increase in core Criollo, raising interest in their upbringing and protection, as well as the development of basic movement control and monitoring of the CRG, which enables better exploitation, management and improvement of the breeding population</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">El Grupo Cubano de Protección a los Cerdos Criollos (CERCRI.Cu), adscripto a la Sociedad Cubana de Porcicultura, se constituye en el año 2010, en el marco de las acciones destinadas a la conservación y uso de cerdos locales en América Latina y el Caribe. Sus objetivos de trabajo del grupo han estado dirigidos a fomentar los Cotos de Reserva Genética en el medio natural (CRG)</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">fortalecer y mejorar las gestiones de crianza y conservación en los mismos y evaluar iniciativas locales de sostenibilidad, en pro de la conservación efectiva de este genotipo. En el presente trabajo, se expone, el estudio realizado por el CERCRI Cu, entre Enero del 2011 y Abril del 2014, al que se integraron especialistas de instituciones científicas, universidades, además de los técnicos, especialistas y productores de los grupos creados en las 14 Sociedades provinciales de Porcicultura. El grupo ha aplicado dos estrategias básicas, del levantamiento de los efectivos Criollos, así como de los CRG y cualquier núcleo Criollo y el desarrollo de acciones de de Sensibilización y Capacitación. Estas estrategias se canalizaron principalmente a través del movimiento de los Talleres del cerdo Criollo, de los que se realizaron cuatro entre el 2011 y el 2014 y de cuyo desarrollo se derivaron un grupo de acciones. Estas acciones ponen de manifiesto la necesidad de mejorar tanto la orientación como el control de la formación y explotación de los CRG. El número de los mismos se duplicó entre el 2010 y el 2014 (48 de 24). La actualización de los inventarios y la certificación de los reproductores en los CRG existentes, es un ejemplo de ello. Se planteó además la necesidad de simplificar y hacer más práctico el Manual existente en forma de un Instructivo Técnico operativo. La gestión del CERCRI.Cu en el período ha sido satisfactoria, propiciando el incremento de los núcleos Criollo, elevando el interés por su crianza y protección, así como por el desarrollo del  movimiento del control y monitoreo básico de los CRG, lo que posibilita una mejor explotación, manejo y mejora de la población pura.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.uco.es/conbiand/aica/templatemo_110_lin_photo/articulos/2014/Trabajo027_AICA2014.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">es</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Actas Iberoamericanas de Conservación Animal</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2253-7325</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.4/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>