<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="ES2016104937">
    <dc:title xml:lang="es">RELEVAMIENTO DE CASTRONERÍAS EN LA PROVINCIA DE NEUQUÉN – PATAGONIA ARGENTINA</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>SURVEY OF CASTRONERÍAS IN NEUQUÉN PROVINCE – PATAGONIA ARGENTINA</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Moronta Martin</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Perez Centeno Marcelo</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Lanari Maria</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Giovannini Nicolas</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Maurino Julia</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Mogni Alejandro</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Diano Martin</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Mikuc Juan</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Instituto de Investigación y Desarrollo Tecnológico para la Pequeña Agricultura Familiar</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Instituto de Investigación y Desarrollo Tecnológico para la Pequeña Agricultura Familiar</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Instituto Nacional de Tecnología Agropecuaria (INTA)</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Instituto Nacional de Tecnología Agropecuaria (INTA)</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Instituto Nacional de Tecnología Agropecuaria (INTA)</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Instituto Nacional de Tecnología Agropecuaria (INTA)</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Instituto Nacional de Tecnología Agropecuaria (INTA)</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Instituto Nacional de Tecnología Agropecuaria (INTA)</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">L10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Genetic resources</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Indigenous knowledge</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_3218</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_35704</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">The castronerías are a distinctive and particular component that has emerged as a socially constructed response against the need for achieving mating seasonality. In the community the castronero is dedicated to the care of males out of the mating season. The castronería gather males of different owners, usually in inaccessible locations. The retribution or payment for this service is one young goat per male or its value in money. The introduction of males into the flock of goats at the return of the summer grazing season induces estrus synchronization due to so-called “Male Effect”. The objective of the present study is to survey the castronerías in Neuquén Province and carrying out their characterization in relation to their constitution and functions within traditional system. The specific aims were to geographically locate the castronerías, characterize the male goats, characterize the castronerías and related flocks management and to make visible the castronerías local knowledge. Twelve castronerías were surveyed, from which the results from the first analyzed ones are presented. The methodological process involved collecting specific data of castrones</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="es">an interview to the castronero was also carried out. At the end of the fieldwork interviews were done to the owners of the castrones, in which topics related to specific data of the flock, castrones selection criteria and systematization of local knowledge were addressed.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="">Las castronerías son un componente distintivo y particular y ha surgido como la respuesta socialmente construida frente a la necesidad de estacionar el servicio. En la comunidad el castronero es quien se dedica al cuidado de los machos fuera de la época de servicio. La castronería reúne machos de diferentes dueños, en general en lugares inaccesibles. La retribución o pago por este servicio es una cabrilla por macho o su valor en dinero. La introducción de los machos en el hato de cabras al retorno de veranada, induce la sincronización de celos debido al denominado “Efecto Macho”. El objetivo de este trabajo es el relevamiento de las castronerías en la provincia de Neuquén, y la caracterización de las mismas en relación a  su constitución y funciones dentro del sistema tradicional. Los objetivos específicos son localizar las castronerías geográficamente, caracterizar los chivatos, caracterizar el manejo de las castronerías y de los piños vinculados y hacer visibles los saberes locales relacionados con las castronerías. Se han relevado hasta el momento doce castronerías de las cuales se presentan resultados de las  primeras analizadas. El proceso metodológico implico realizar toma de datos específicos sobre los castrones, también se realizo una entrevista al castronero. Al finalizar el trabajo de campo se realizaran entrevistas a los dueños de los castrones, en la misma se abordaran temas referidos a datos específicos del piño, criterios de selección de los castrones y sistematización de los saberes locales.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.uco.es/conbiand/aica/templatemo_110_lin_photo/articulos/2014/Trabajo087_AICA2014.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">es</dc:language>
    <ags:citation>
      <ags:citationTitle>Actas Iberoamericanas de Conservación Animal</ags:citationTitle>
      <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2253-7325</ags:citationIdentifier>
      <ags:citationNumber>v.4/n.4</ags:citationNumber>
    </ags:citation>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>